<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Deccan Herald - TOP STORIES RSS FEEDS</title>
<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/</link>
<description>Feed provided by Deccanherald.</description>
<generator>http://www.deccanherald.com/</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 1 May 2016 02:00:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<image>
	<title>Deccan Herald - DHNS </title>
	<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/</link>
	<url>http://www.deccanherald.com/images/deccanhereald-logo.gif</url>
	<width>144</width>
	<height>98</height>
	<description>Feed provided by Deccanherald.</description>
</image>
<atom:link href="http://www.deccanherald.com/rss-internal/top-stories.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item>
		<title><![CDATA[IAF chopper sprinkles water to douse U'khand forest fires]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543773/iaf-chopper-sprinkles-water-douse.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543773_thump.jpg"/>An IAF Mi 17 chopper today flew several sorties in Nainital district sprinkling water lifted from a lake to douse the raging forest fires that have destroyed vast swathes of forested land across Uttarakhand.Low visibility, however, prevented a second chopper from being deployed in Pauri district for the aerial operations in the hill state which commenced today as part of efforts to control the fires that has killed seven persons and destroyed 2,269 hectares of forested land.  The fire has also spread to sparsely populated remote hill areas.Home Minister Rajnath Singh reviewed the situation in]]></description>	
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Over 130 NDRF men deployed to combat U'khand forest fire]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543776/over-130-ndrf-men-deployed.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543776_thump.jpg"/>NDRF has deployed over 130 personnel as part of multiple fire fighting teams to combat the raging forest fire in the jungles of Uttarakhand that have destroyed about 2,269 hectares of jungles in several districts and claimed at least seven lives till now.The teams of the specialised National Disaster Response Force (NDRF) have fanned out in 13 affected areas of three districts of Pauri Garhwal, Almora and Chamoli to tackle the massive blaze."Our teams are working in 13 sectors in coordination with the officials and personnel of the state fire and forest department."The teams have been instruct]]></description>	
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Rajnath reviews forest fire situation in Uttarakhand]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543769/rajnath-reviews-forest-fire-situation.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543769_thump.gif"/> Home Minister Rajnath Singh today reviewed the situation in Uttarakhand where raging forest fires have destroyed 2269 hectares of jungles in several districts and claimed at least seven lives.The Home Minister held discussions with chief secretary and other officials of the state government on the situation arising due to the forest fire and offered all assistance from the Centre.Singh directed central officials to provide all possible assistance to the state government to control the forest fires.The Home Minister yesterday spoke to Governor K K Paul, who briefed him about the situation in ]]></description>	
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Harish Rawat accepts his 'presence' in sting CD]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543772/harish-rawat-accepts-his-presence.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543772_thump.jpg"/>Deposed Uttarakhand Chief Minister Harish Rawat, who had so far been insisting the sting CD of him was "fake", today virtually accepted his presence in the video. He, however, said meeting a journalist was not a crime."Is meeting a journalist a crime? If one of the MLAs who had not been technically disqualified by that time talked to me ... how does it matter? Do we block any channels in politics?" Rawat told reporters here on the sidelines of a programme.Claiming innocence, Rawat said if the CD contained evidence of him having made an offer in cash or kind in exchange for the support of disg]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[JNUSU President Kanhaiya Kumar shown black flags in Patna]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543761/jnusu-president-kanhaiya-kumar-shown.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543761_thump.jpg"/>JNUSU president Kanhaiya Kumar was today shown black flags at a function here by two unidentified persons who were roughed up by his supporters before being detained by the police for questioning.The two persons belonging to a little-known outfit -'Youth Swaraj' - showed black flags to the JNUSU president, besides raising slogan of 'Bharat Mata Ki Jai' while he was speaking at a function 'Azadi' in S K Memorial hall here organised by AISF and AIYF.Kanhaiya's supporters thrashed the two persons in the hall. Later the police took the duo into custody. "Police have detained two persons in this re]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Narendra Modi got first class in MA from Guj University: VC]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543758/narendra-modi-got-first-class.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543758_thump.jpg"/>Amid the raging row over Prime Minister Narendra Modi's educational qualification, the Gujarat University today shared details of his MA degree saying he scored 62.3 per cent as an external student of the varsity.The details were shared by the Gujarat University after the Central Information Commission directed it to provide the same to Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal, who had recently criticised the functioning of the transparency panel."Narendra Damodardas Modi passed his MA in Political Science in 1983 with first class, securing 499 out of 800 marks, which comes to 62.3 per cent as an ]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[ISIS developing Google-style driverless cars for attacks]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543777/isis-developing-google-style-driverless.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543777_thump.jpg"/> Islamic State (ISIS) technicians are working to develop a Google-style driverless car that could navigate itself into a crowded area before detonating an explosive device, a NATO security expert has warned.ISIS' research and development department in the terror group's de facto Syrian capital, Raqqa, is believed to be producing the vehicles at the same time as US Internet giant Google attempts to perfect the same technology.If successful, the invention could prove to be a major headache for security services in Britain and throughout Europe and North America, where self-driving cars are expe]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Uber brings back surge pricing in Delhi, Kejriwal warns of strong action]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543783/uber-brings-back-surge-pricing.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543783_thump.jpg"/>On a day the ban on diesel-run cabs came into effect, taxi aggregator Uber today brought back surge pricing in Delhi, prompting Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal to warn the operators of "strong action".Uber had introduced the provision during odd-even scheme, which was objected to by commuters and Kejriwal had asserted that such demand-linked hikes would be banned permanently.A day after the second phase of odd-even ended, commuters across the city, who availed the services of the app-based cab firm today, found that surge pricing, where fares are raised when demand is higher than the available ]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Toddlers have shot at least 23 people this year in US: report]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543782/toddlers-have-shot-least-23.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543782_thump.gif"/> The US has witnessed at least 23 toddler-involved shootings since January 1, reporting a spurt in such tragic incidents despite the Obama administration's efforts to introduce new gun control measures.There have been at least 23 toddler-involved shootings in the US since January 1, compared with 18 over the same period last year, the Washington Post reported.In the vast majority of cases, the children accidentally shoot themselves. That has happened 18 times this year, and in nine of those cases the children died of their wounds.Last year, a Post analysis found that toddlers were finding gun]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Twin bombings in southern Iraq kill 33: security officials]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543779/twin-bombings-southern-iraq-kill.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543779_thump.jpg"/> Two bomb blasts in the southern Iraqi city of Samawa today killed at least 33 people and wounded more than 50, security and medical officials said."The hospitals have received 33 dead," a senior official in the Muthanna health department, which covers Samawa, told AFP. An officer in Muthanna Operations Command confirmed the toll.They said at least 50 people were also wounded in the blasts in Samawa, 230 kilometres (145 miles) south of Baghdad."Two car bombs went off in town. The first one was at around midday near a bus station in the city centre," a senior police officer in Muthanna provinc]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[Without dissent, parliamentary system is dysfunctional: Prez]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543771/without-dissent-parliamentary-system-dysfunctional.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543771_thump.jpg"/>Without dissent, parliamentary system is dysfunctional, President Pranab Mukherjee said here today, underling that "fierce debates and discussions" in the House contribute to taking decisions on important matters like economy.Addressing the business leaders of India-New Zealand Business Council here, Mukherjee invited them to India to contribute towards various programmes launched by the Indian Government."I am accompanied by a minister in the Government (Sajeev Balayan). I am also accompanied by Members of Parliament who represent the true character of Indian Parliament. They represent variou]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[India on 5th place in fake goods trade; China on top]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543764/india-5th-place-fake-goods.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543764_thump.jpg"/> India is the fifth biggest exporter of fake goods globally, while China is on the top with a huge 63 per cent share in the estimated half-a-trillion dollar worldwide imports of counterfeit and pirated goods.China is followed by Turkey, Singapore, Thailand and India among the top-five countries from where most fake goods originate, as per a new study by the OECD (Organisation Economic Cooperation and Development) and the European Union's Intellectual Property Office.China-made products accounted for 63.2 per cent of total seizures of fake imported goods globally, while the second- ranked Turk]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title><![CDATA[India's Kalvari stealth submarine starts sea trials]]></title>
		<link>http://www.deccanherald.com/content/543770/indias-kalvari-stealth-submarine-starts.html</link>
		<pubDate><![CDATA[2016-05-01]]></pubDate>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src ="http://www.deccanherald.com/page_images/thumb/2016/05/01/543770_thump.jpg"/> Kalvari, Indian Navy's first indigenous Scorpene-class stealth submarine, today sailed out of Mumbai Harbour for sea trials even as the plan to purchase heavy-weight torpedos for the vessel remains stuck due to the VVIP chopper scam.Kalvari is the first of the India's six Scorpene-class submarines being built under the much-delayed Project 75. The vessels are being built by Mazagon Dock Limited (MDL) in collaboration with French company DCNS.In October 2015, Kalvari had been set afloat. "The sea trials of Kalvari have begun today. It is a proud moment for us," a Navy official said.However, t]]></description>
		</item></channel></rss>