<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.asianage.com/more/headlines/38">
  <channel>
    <title>The Asian Age</title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/more/headlines/38</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
          <item>
    <title> Harish Rawat accepts his presence in ‘fake’ sting CD, denies any wrongdoing </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/harish-rawat-accepts-his-presence-fake-sting-cd-denies-any-wrongdoing-661</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/dc-cover-u6aq5gfrrgk8c84reeq1nehvu7-20160501163820medijpeg-660&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/dc-Cover-u6aq5gfrrgk8c84reeq1nehvu7-20160501163820.Medi_.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;dc-Cover-u6aq5gfrrgk8c84reeq1nehvu7-20160501163820.Medi_.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;dc-Cover-u6aq5gfrrgk8c84reeq1nehvu7-20160501163820.Medi_.jpeg&quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is significant as Rawat had so far been challenging the veracity of the CD, calling it &#039;fake&#039;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dehradun&lt;/strong&gt;: Deposed Uttarakhand Chief Minister Harish Rawat, who had so far been insisting the sting CD of him was &quot;fake&quot;, on Sunday virtually accepted his presence in the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He, however, said meeting a journalist was not a crime. &quot;Is meeting a journalist a crime? If one of the MLAs who had not been technically disqualified by that time talked to me ... how does it matter? Do we block any channels in politics?&quot; Rawat told reporters here on the sidelines of a programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claiming innocence, Rawat said if the CD contained evidence of him having made an offer in cash or kind in exchange for the support of disgruntled MLAs he was ready to be hanged in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If any evidence is found against me like me offering money or post to anybody, hang me at Clock tower,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clock tower is a busy chowk in the heart of the town. However, from what the deposed chief minister said it was clear that a meeting did take place between him and the journalist who made the sting CD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is significant as Rawat had so far been challenging the veracity of the CD, calling it &quot;fake&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Why should anyone spend Rs 15 crore for me. The man (journalist) was saying something meaningless to while away my time and I said something to while away his. How does it matter? We keep saying things like this on a daily basis. Does that mean they should be used against us?&quot; Rawat said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sting CD made by the editor-in-chief of a private news channel and circulated by the nine Congress rebels, who created a political crisis in the state by siding with opposition BJP in the state Assembly, purportedly shows Rawat negotiating a money deal with the journalist to buy the support of MLAs who had revolted against him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/dc-channel/business/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/pti">PTI</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491660/preview" length="8273" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491661 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> Policies were made in past keeping ballot box in mind: Modi slams Cong </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/policies-were-made-past-keeping-ballot-box-mind-modi-slams-cong-659</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/prime-minister-narendra-modi-photo-pti-658&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/dc-Cover-deorbpmhm5j363l3a4v62m3oh2-20160501151523.Medi_.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot; Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&quot; title=&quot; Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modi accused Congress-led governments for not working towards development and alleviation of poverty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ballia&lt;/strong&gt;: In a veiled attack on the erstwhile Congress-led governments, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday said most policies had been made in the past keeping the ballot box in mind and not for development or alleviation of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our government has been working for the uplift of the poverty-stricken people... through &#039;jan bhagidari&#039; (people&#039;s participation). Many policies had been made keeping in mind the ballot box and not the real interests of the vast majority of the poor people of our country,&quot; he said at a public meeting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also launched the &#039;PM Ujjwala Yojana&#039; scheme which aims at providing 5 crore free cooking (LPG) connections to below- poverty-line families over the next three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Uttar Pradesh has given so many Prime Ministers. But why did the poverty levels go on increasing? Were there some drawbacks in these policies?&quot; he asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said an MP from Ghazipur in UP when Jawaharlal Nehru was the Prime Minister had raised the issue of abject poverty in eastern UP following which a commission was formed which made several major recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What happened to those recommendations, only God knows.  Fifty years have passed since then. One of the recommendations was to connect Ghazipur and Mau by rail. We have now decided to construct a rail line to implement that recommendation,&quot; Modi said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister also spoke on the significance of May Day today and said the new &#039;Mantra&#039; should be -- &quot;Labourers, unite the world&quot; as against &quot;Workers of the World, Unite&quot;, the slogan which used to be raised earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The situation has changed. The biggest cementing factor is the sweat of the workers who can unite the world,&quot; he said, noting that those who used to raise slogans of uniting the workers have been &quot;losing ground the world over&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/dc-channel/business/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/pti">PTI</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491658/preview" length="9222" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491659 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> Revealed: Modi secured first class MA degree from Gujarat University </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/revealed-modi-secured-first-class-ma-degree-gujarat-university-645</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/delhi-chief-minister-arvind-kejriwal-wirth-prime-minister-narendra-modi-photo-pti-644&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/dc-Cover-supnkkib69fb1hb8jn3h1qjmm6-20160424124758.Medi__0.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot; Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal wirth Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&quot; title=&quot; Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal wirth Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal wirth Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Photo: PTI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal had demanded that the CIC reveal educational qualification of Narendra Modi.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;New Delhi:&lt;/strong&gt; Days after Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal demanded details of Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s degree, it has now been revealed that the four time Chief Minister completed his post-graduation from Gujarat University with a first class degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to reports, Modi had completed his post graduation in political science from Gujarat University and secured 62.3 percent in 1983.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report revealed that Modi&#039;s educational status states that while being enrolled in the university, Modi studied European Politics, Indian Political Analysis and Psychology of Politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report quotes Gujarat University Vice-Chancellor MN Patel saying, &quot;The second year marks listed in the records mention that PM scored 64 (out of 100 marks) marks in political science, 62 in European and Social Political Thoughts, 69 in Modern India/ Political Analysis and 67 marks in Concept tool/s — Political Psychological and Social.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Kejriwal had asked the Central Information Commission (CIC) to reveal the educational qualification of Modi and make it available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Vice Chancellor of the university had stated that they have not been approached by anyone seeking the details yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his letter to the Information Commissioner M Sridhar Acharyulu, Kejriwal mentioned that there were allegations that Modi did not have a degree and that people of the country should know the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Kejriwal&#039;s demand, the CIC had directed The Gujarat University and Delhi University to make information on Modi&#039;s degree public. It had also directed that varsities to reply to all the RTIs filed seeking information on the Prime Minister&#039;s education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/dc-channel/business/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/age-correspondent-0">: Age Correspondent</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/new-delhi">New Delhi</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491644/preview" length="12038" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491645 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> Chopper deal: Defence Minister to place all facts in Parliament on May 4 </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/chopper-deal-defence-minister-place-all-facts-parliament-may-4-641</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/defence-minister-manohar-parrikar-photo-pti-640&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/dc-Cover-l4vimvd25q0p7t9ae2crlng0i6-20160419081147.Medi_.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot; Defence Minister Manohar Parrikar (Photo: PTI) &quot; title=&quot; Defence Minister Manohar Parrikar (Photo: PTI) &quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Defence Minister Manohar Parrikar (Photo: PTI) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will place the detailed chronology, giving facts about the chopper deal before Parliament, said Parrikar.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Panaji:&lt;/strong&gt; Defence Minister Manohar Parrikar on Sunday said he will place all facts along with the detailed chronology about the controversial AgustaWestland chopper deal before Parliament on May 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I will place the detailed chronology, giving facts about the chopper deal before Parliament on Wednesday. I will place the detailed chronology, giving how and when necessary clauses or provisions were relaxed to suit the company,&quot; he told reporters here on the sidelines of a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Those who received kickbacks will not leave behind the proof for us to prosecute them, but we will have to prove it (that kickbacks were received),&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is for us to prove everything now. Since the issue would be placed in Parliament, I would not like to speak in detail to media,&quot; the Defence Minister further said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Why no action was taken against the company till 2014? Why was the company not blacklisted by then UPA government?&quot; Parrikar questioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I challenge the Congress to show the UPA government&#039;s order blacklisting the AgustaWestland company. Let them reply first why it was not banned. It was during our (NDA) government that we banned it,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parrikar had recently challenged the Congress to show the order by the UPA government confirming the blacklisting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AgustaWestland was not blacklisted during the UPA rule, top Modi government sources had recently claimed, asserting it was the NDA dispensation which had put on hold all acquisition proposals with the VVIP chopper scam-tainted firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parrikar was speaking to reporters on the sidelines of an event to lay foundation stone for a football ground in Panaji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal for the choppers went off track in 2013 when Italy arrested the head of Finmeccanica, which owns AgustaWestland, for paying bribes to secure the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Italian court, which convicted AgustaWestland chief Giuseppe Orsi, had reportedly described how the firm paid bribes to top Congress leaders to bag the Rs 3,600 crore deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/dc-channel/business/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/pti">PTI</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491640/preview" length="8333" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491641 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> U&#039;khand fire rages on, MI-17 choppers spray water on affected areas </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/ukhand-fire-rages-mi-17-choppers-spray-water-affected-areas-633</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/iafs-11-member-team-begins-fire-fighting-operations-douse-uttarakhand-fire-photo-anitwitter-632&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/dc-Cover-deorbpmhm5j363l3a4v62m3oh2-20160501101853.Medi_.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot; IAF&amp;#039;s 11-member team begins fire fighting operations to douse Uttarakhand fire. (Photo: ANI/Twitter)&quot; title=&quot; IAF&amp;#039;s 11-member team begins fire fighting operations to douse Uttarakhand fire. (Photo: ANI/Twitter)&quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; IAF&#039;s 11-member team begins fire fighting operations to douse Uttarakhand fire. (Photo: ANI/Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than 1,900 hectares of forest land have been affected by the fire in the Kumaoun and Garwal region.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nainital&lt;/strong&gt;: A 11-member team of the Indian Air Force began firefighting operations after the Centre deployed two MI-17 helicopters to douse the forest blaze in Uttarakhand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choppers took off from Nainital early Sunday morning to spray water on affected areas.  More than 1,900 hectares of forest land have been affected by the fire in the Kumaoun and Garwal region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read: Uttarakhand forest fire: IAF deploys Mi-17 chopper, PMO assures help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Two helicopters were sent by the Indian Air Force. One has been sent in Gorakhal Sainik School and another one in Pouri, Srinagar. The speciality of the helicopter is it can take 5,000 litre of water from any source of water, be it pond or river and can drop it anywhere,&quot; Wing Commander V.K. Singh, operation in-charge, Airforce told ANI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our mission is to carry water from Bhimtal to places where fire is burning. There is a huge area covering the flames. We will maintain a distance of 100 metre from the fire to douse the flames,&quot; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;WATCH: Latest visuals of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Uttarakhand?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Uttarakhand&lt;/a&gt; fire, 5 districts affected as fire spreads across 1900 hectares of forest area&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/cn7kviBKr6&quot;&gt;https://t.co/cn7kviBKr6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; ANI (@ANI_news) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ANI_news/status/726629955337998336&quot;&gt;May 1, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The fire raged yesterday even as three teams of National Disaster Response Force (NDRF) were deployed in Almora, Gauchar and Pauri and one team of the State Disaster Response Fund in Nainital to extinguish the flames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Air Force helicopters have been rushed into service to fight the fire in Pauri and Nanital districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;WATCH: IAF&amp;#39;s chopper MI-17 takes off from Nainital to drop water in areas affected by Uttarakhand forest fire.&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dYPKVUvMCt&quot;&gt;https://t.co/dYPKVUvMCt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; ANI (@ANI_news) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ANI_news/status/726605144578646016&quot;&gt;May 1, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Forest areas of Almora, Chamoli, Pouri, Rudra Prayag and Pithora districts have been badly affected by the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union Home Minister Rajnath Singh spoke to Governor K.K. Paul yesterday and assured him of providing all necessary assistance to control the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Governor has directed all District Magistrates of the affected districts to make full use of available resources to douse the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nainital High court has also expressed concern and directed to control the fire in the shortest possible time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of forest fire incidents in the state in early February this year, 922 incidents have occurred so far killing six people including three women and a child and blighting nearly 2,000 hectares of green cover.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/dc-channel/business/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/ani">ANI</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491632/preview" length="9384" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491633 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Copter scam: Congress counters Amit Shah with 7 key questions</title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/copter-scam-congress-counters-shah-7-key-questions-619</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;all-attached-images&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 430px&quot; class=&quot;image-attach-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/congress-leader-randeep-surjewala-photo-twitter-618&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/sites/default/files/images/suj_0_0_0_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Congress leader Randeep Surjewala. (Photo: Twitter)&quot; title=&quot;Congress leader Randeep Surjewala. (Photo: Twitter)&quot;  class=&quot;image image-content_image &quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;261&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Congress leader Randeep Surjewala. (Photo: Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sharpening its attack on BJP chief Amit Shah, the Congress on Saturday posed seven questions to Mr Shah on the AgustaWestland helicopter deal, saying the BJP and its government’s campaign on it is like “empty vessels making the loudest noise”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trashing Mr Shah’s charges against Mrs Sonia Gandhi and other party leaders on the AgustaWestland deal, it termed them as “deliberate lies” and demanded that he apologise for his “politics of deceit” and attempts to create a smokescreen to “befool the people”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AICC also asked Prime Minister Narendra Modi to tell what connection, if any, his government has with former Air Force Chief S.P. Tyagi, an accused in the copter deal case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addressing a press conference, the party’s chief spokesman Randeep Surjewala posed a number of questions to Mr Shah, who has dubbed AgustaWestland and its parent company Finmecanica a “bogus company”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked the BJP chief whether he would ask Modi government as to why it has been “protecting” the same “bogus company” for last two years as CBI and ED investigations have “reached no conclusion”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will Amit Shah and BJP answer the people as to why the same ‘fraud company’ was permitted to be part of Prime Minister’s Make in India programme and participate in Aero India Exhibition?” he said while releasing purportedly related documents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, he asked Mr Shah to also answer as to why the same “fraud company” was being given permission by the Foreign Investment Promotion Board of the Modi government as recently as on October 8, 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will Shah also answer as to why the same ‘fraud company’ was given permission to participate in defence contract as a ‘sub-contractor’ as also ‘supplier to a contracting party’ with the Government of India by a order dated 22.08.2014 of the ministry of defence?” he asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Surjewala dismissed as a “bundle of lies” Mr Shah’s claim that the bank guarantee of the defaulting company AgustaWestland was not encashed by the previous Congress government. “It is again a bundle of lies, aimed at creating a smokescreen and befool the people of India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will Amit Shah tell the country whether it is a fact that Indian government has recovered an amount of `2,068 crore from AgustaWestland as against payment of `1,620 crore, besides confiscating three helicopters?” he asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will Amit Shah and BJP government answer whether it is not correct that the then Congress government filed and won the court case leading to encashment of bank guarantees worth euro 2,28,00,00 (228 million) in the court of Milan, Italy, on May 23, 2014?” he asked. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/age-correspondent">Age Correspondent</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/new-delhi">New Delhi</category>
 <enclosure url="http://www.asianage.com/image/view/491618/preview" length="6815" type="image/jpeg" />
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491619 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>UP BJP veterans to be rested</title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/bjp-veterans-be-rested-617</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;There is bad news for the veterans in the UP BJP which is all set to get younger and more youthful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The party’s new executive committee, which will be announced sometime in May, will do away with more than 60 per cent members from the outgoing team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP high command is keen to end factionalism in the state unit by keeping the veterans out of the area. “New and young members do not have factions of their own and their loyalties are with the party. Such members will be a part of the time while the veterans can take some rest now,” said a party functionary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, there are going to be sweeping changes and a large majority of the executive committee will comprise young leaders since the BJP state president Keshav Maurya is also young — just 46 years old. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We cannot saddle him with veterans because they will refuse to obey his diktats and will tread their own path,” a said the party leader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP plans to challenge the youth base of the Samajwadi Party by promoting youth in a big way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The youth are largely disappointed with the Samajwadi government which has failed to give them employment and with a young president and a young team, we can wean away young voters to a considerable extent,” the leader explained. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new committee will have only about 40 per cent members from upper caste while the remaining 60 per cent will be from OBC and dalit caste groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is in conformity with the party’s new policy to focus on OBCs and dalits for the 2017 UP Assembly elections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interesting development, majority of those who had been a part of the outgoing committee headed by Mr Laxmikant Bajpai will not find a place in the new committee and five of the eight organisation secretaries will be changed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those who will be included in the new committee will be those who will not contest elections. Those who are keen to try their luck in the elections will not be a part of the committee,” the leader informed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The party this time wants every member of the state organisation to devote full time to poll management and if anyone is keen on contesting polls, he cannot be entrusted a job in the organisation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that leaders like Pankaj Singh, son of Mr Rajnath Singh, and Swatantra Dev Singh will not be a part of the state executive since they are both lobbying for a ticket in the Assembly polls. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/author/amita-verma">Amita Verma</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/lucknow">Lucknow</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491617 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>UDF, LDF let people down: Arun Jaitley</title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/udf-ldf-let-people-down-arun-jaitley-616</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Union finance minister Arun Jaitley rejected the allegation raised by senior Congress leader A.K. Antony that AgustaWestland was blacklisted during the UPA rule and later lifted by the NDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Jaitley, who was here to launch the Kerala unit of the National Democratic Alliance, said it was “a figment of the imagination of Mr Antony” that the copter deal was cancelled after the bribe issue cropped up. “This is a figment of somebody’s imagination. We are only struggling to find out the identity of the bribe taker,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said Kerala should have been one of the most prosperous states in the country going by its resources and assets. The economic model created by the Left was not a developmental model. He said the UDF and LDF had let the people of the state down where they relied most on “vote banks”. He said the BJP would be an alternative to the two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The domination of the Congress and the CPI(M) was not based on any developmental politics, but on an emphasis to keep certain vote banks with them,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have vote banks based on sectarian appeal, you do not have to rely much on performance,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also said Kerala and West Bengal were the only two major states to face revenue deficit though not geographically disadvantaged. Kerala should make use of its human capital here instead of exporting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NDA Vision Document promises among others land for landless, a housing programme in the name of Sree Narayana Guru, government jobs to all tribal youths who had passed tenth standard and uninterrupted water supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides BJP, the NDA now comprises BDJS, P. C.Thomas faction of Kerala Congress, A. N. Rajan Babu-led JSS, Kerala Vikas Congress, Lok Janshakti Party, NDP (S), Socialist Janata Dal, Nationalist Kerala Congress, Ganaka Sabha and Janathipathya Rashtriya Sabha led by C. K. Janu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/age-correspondent">Age Correspondent</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/thiruvananthapuram">Thiruvananthapuram</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491616 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Government to follow copter money trail </title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/government-follow-copter-money-trail-557</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharpening the attack on Congress on the AgustaWestland helicopter deal, Union minister of state for finance Jayant Sinha on Saturday said investigators have the ability to find the money trail and the government would pursue the matter for the benefit of citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These are investigations that our agencies are undertaking and they are very capable,” Mr Sinha said in response to a question on whether the government was confident about proving the money trail to Congress president Sonia Gandhi or if it was just political aggression. “Sleuths of the investigative agencies have the ability to track down and find out what the money trail is. Of course, we will pursue the matter for the benefit of the citizens of the country, wherever the investigation, wherever the evidence may take us,” he said on the sidelines of the Enforcement Directorate Day function here. The ruling BJP has been alleging that top Congress leaders are involved in the helicopter deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VVIP helicopter deal relates to a 2010 decision of the UPA government to buy 12 helicopters from AgustaWestland, a unit of Italian manufacturer Finmeccanica. The CBI had registered a case in 2013 in connection with alleged bribes paid by the firm to Indians to clinch the deal for 12 helicopters to ferry VVIPs, including the President and the Prime Minister. The CBI on Saturday quizzed former IAF deputy chief J.S. Gujral for over eight hours in the case. He will be called again for questioning, sources said, adding that three Tyagi brothers — cousins of former IAF chief S.P. Tyagi — have also been asked to appear before the investigation team next week. The former IAF chief is to appear before the CBI on Monday, they added. The CBI has so far examined over 100 people in connection with the case, including all the accused Indians, and now needs to examine five foreign nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking to mediapersons in Dehradun on Saturday, defence minister Manohar Parrikar also said the previous UPA dispensation will have to answer who received the alleged kickbacks in the AgustaWestland helicopter deal. “The moot question is who took the money in the Agusta deal. Those who were at the helm at the time when the deal was struck owe an explanation.” In Thiruvananthapuram, Union finance minister Arun Jaitley said the theory that the company was blacklisted during UPA rule and then taken off the blacklist by the NDA government was a “figment of the imagination”. Mr Jaitley disputed the statement of former defence minister A.K. Antony that the UPA government  had blacklisted AgustaWestland and Finmeccanica after the bribe issue come out. Firing a fresh salvo at Mrs Sonia Gandhi over the VVIP helicopter scam, the BJP on Saturday claimed that Mr Antony had objected to relaxations extended to AgustaWestland regarding field trials but was “overridden”, and suggested that the Congress chief was behind it. Party spokesperson G.V.L. Narsimha Rao told a press conference here that Mr Antony had questioned the rationale behind allowing the firm to conduct the field trial of helicopter on its premises abroad, and not in India, an initial condition in the RFP, asking what was the guarantee that the field trials would remain above board. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitting back at the BJP for targeting the Congress leadership, Mr A.K. Antony on Saturday dared the Narendra Modi government to take “strong” action against “bribe givers and takers”. Asserting that no names were revealed in the Italian court which convicted former employees of AgustaWestland and Finmeccanica for giving bribes in the deal, he said, “At every stage in the Italian court our lawyer represented the case. They cross-examined all witnesses. At no stage were names revealed. My question is now: CBI is with present government, ED is with present government. Why delay if there is evidence?” he told reporters in Thiruvananthapuram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Congress trashed BJP chief Amit Shah’s charges against Mrs Gandhi and party leaders on the AgustaWestland deal, terming them “deliberate lies”, and demanded that he apologise for his “politics of deceit” and attempts to create a smokescreen to “befool the people”. Addressing a press conference here, Congress chief spokesman Randeep Surjewala posed a number of questions to Mr Shah, who has dubbed AgustaWestland and its parent company Finmeccanica as a “bogus company”. He asked the BJP chief whether he would ask the Modi government why it has been “protecting” the same “bogus company” for the last two years as the CBI and ED investigations have “reached no conclusion”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/source/age-correspondent">Age Correspondent</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/new-delhi">New Delhi</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491557 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Why BJP would prefer a TMC win</title>
    <link>http://www.asianage.com/india/why-bjp-would-prefer-tmc-win-556</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The BJP, which has locked horns with the Trinamul Congress in the ongoing Assembly polls, would prefer a Mamata Banerjee-led government in West Bengal rather than a Left-Congress dispensation. The calculation is simple. A Left-Congress dispensation would trigger politics of confrontation between the state and the Centre while the saffronites expect a Mamata-led government to extend a hand of cooperation to the Modi government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politically, while Ms Mamata Banerjee will continue to remain a regional player, a powerful Left-Congress combination could emerge as a major challenge to the Modi-led BJP at the national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aware that the BJP was in no position to form a government, saffron strategists were trying hard to retain its 17-per-cent vote share. It was argued that if the BJP could retain its vote share, it would eventually “benefit” the TMC. A breach in the saffron vote share would make the contest “tight” for the Trinamul Congress, as per saffron calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP was also of the opinion that Ms Banerjee’s Trinamul Congress, reeling under a string of scams and cases, would maintain a “friendly” and “working relationship” with the Centre. That the Centre has been going soft on Ms Banerjee was evident from its lack of urgency in stepping on the gas on the Saradha and Narada scams and the Burdwan blast case. The Saradha scam had virtually reached Ms Banerjee’s doorstep. The other “advantage” of having Ms Banerjee at the helm of Bengal affairs was that by the end of her five-year-run she would be considerably “weakened” as her strength was expected to fall. After the elections, the Modi government would continue to maintain “friendly” relations with Ms Banerjee as the government needs her “support” in the Rajya Sabha, where the BJP continues to struggle for numbers. The TMC has 12 MPs in the Rajya Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Assembly polls, the “Modi-Mamata bonhomie” had not only provided the Opposition ammunition for attack but had also upset the state BJP in Bengal. It may be recalled that during the first half of the Budget Session the TMC did not support a Left-Congress-sponsored amendment to the motion of thanks on the President’s Address in the Rajya Sabha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Opposition has also been talking of “new year bonhomie” between “Modi and Mamata”. The Prime Minister had tweeted: “Received very touching New Year greetings from @MamataOfficial ji &amp;amp; that too in Gujarati! I thank Mamata Didi &amp;amp; wish her a great 2016”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Banerjee had replied: “Glad you liked the New Year greetings I sent you in Gujarati. Thanks too @narendramodi ji for the greetings you sent me in Bengali.” Interestingly, this exchange of greetings came when the BJP and TMC were at each other’s throat over the violence in Malda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resurgence of the Left and Congress at the national level could make the BJP’s return to power in 2019 somewhat difficult. BJP spin doctors are closely watching the Congress high command and, regardless of the bravados and attempts to ridicule the Gandhis, the BJP is in no mood to take them lightly. The Congress, which clocked a poor 19.3 per cent vote share during the last Lok Sabha polls, is also playing the game of coalition politics to the hilt by latching on to regional satraps. Talking about the BJP victory in the Lok Sabha polls, a saffron strategist pointed out that winning big in the general election with only 31 per cent vote share “goes to show how fragmented the voting was”. With the possibility of a grand alliance against the BJP at the national level in the 2019 general election, there could be less fragmentation and the possibility of votes splitting various ways would become virtually nil, he observed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/category/india">India</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/author/sanjay-basak">Sanjay Basak</category>
 <category domain="http://www.asianage.com/category/place/new-delhi">New Delhi</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">491556 at http://www.asianage.com</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- Page cached by Boost @ 2016-05-01 19:35:42, expires @ 2016-05-01 20:35:42 -->
