<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Financial ExpressThe Financial Express</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.financialexpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.financialexpress.com</link>
	<description>Business News, Industry, Personal Finance, Stock Market News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:57:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.2</generator>
<image>
		<title></title>
		<url>http://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/themes/vip/financialexpress/images/fe_logo.png</url>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com</link>
		<description> | Financial Express feeds follow us on financialexpress.com</description>
		</image>	<item>
		<title>Just 1per cent of population pay taxes; Over 5k paid more than Rs 1crore</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/just-1per-cent-of-population-pay-taxes-over-5k-paid-more-than-rs-1crore/246472/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/just-1per-cent-of-population-pay-taxes-over-5k-paid-more-than-rs-1crore/246472/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 19:24:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Income Tax]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246472</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Taxpayers account for just about one per cent of India's population, but tax outgo was over Rs 1 crore for as many as 5,430 individuals, as per the latest data disclosed by the government for assessment year 2012-13. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-245617" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/money-l-2.jpg" alt="Money" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/money-l-2-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/money-l-2-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/money-l-2.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> As per the overall data, total income tax collections rose nine-fold to Rs 2.86 lakh crore in 2015-16, from Rs 31,764 crore in 2000-01. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Taxpayers account for just about one per cent of India&#8217;s population, but tax outgo was over Rs 1 crore for as many as 5,430 individuals, as per the latest data disclosed by the government for assessment year 2012-13.</p>
<p>As part of a transparency drive, the government has made public direct tax data for last 15 years. Data for individuals has been published only for 2012-13 assessment year, which shows taxes for income in financial year ended March 31, 2012.</p>
<p>A total of 2.87 crore individuals filed income tax returns for that year, but 1.62 crore of them did not pay any tax &#8212; leaving the number of taxpayers at just about 1.25 crore which was close to one per cent of the country&#8217;s total population of about 123 crore at that time.</p>
<p>The tax outgo was less than Rs 1.5 lakh for a vast majority of nearly 89 per cent taxpayers (over 1.11 crore). Their average tax payable was just about Rs 21,000, while the collective amount stood at over Rs 23,000 crore.<br />
The three individuals in the top-bracket of Rs 100-500 crore paid a total tax of Rs 437 crore &#8212; resulting in an average tax outgo of Rs 145.80 crore.</p>
<p>As many as 5,430 individuals paid income tax of over Rs 1 crore. Out of this, the tax range was Rs 1-5 crore for more than 5,000 individuals, resulting in a total outgo of Rs 8,907 crore.</p>
<p>As per the overall data, total income tax collections rose nine-fold to Rs 2.86 lakh crore in 2015-16, from Rs 31,764 crore in 2000-01.</p>
<p>The data further said that the bulk of individuals who filed returns for the assessment year 2012-13 earned an annual salary between Rs 5.5 lakh and Rs 9.5 lakh.</p>
<p>Over 20.23 lakh taxpayers earned Rs 5.5-9.5 lakh, while their cumulative salary earnings stood at Rs 1.40 lakh crore in the financial year 2011-12.</p>
<p>Further 19.18 lakh individuals earned salary of Rs 2.5-3.5 lakh that year.</p>
<p>Six individuals fell in the high-end earning bracket of Rs 50-100 crore of salary income.</p>
<p>In the salary range of Rs 1-5 crore, there were as many as 17,515 individuals.</p>
<p>Nearly 2.87 crore salary earners filed their I-T returns in assessment year 2012-13.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/just-1per-cent-of-population-pay-taxes-over-5k-paid-more-than-rs-1crore/246472/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ban on diesel-run taxis comes into effect in Delhi</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/ban-on-diesel-run-taxis-comes-into-effect-in-delhi/246471/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/ban-on-diesel-run-taxis-comes-into-effect-in-delhi/246471/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 19:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246471</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The ban on plying of 27,000 diesel-run taxis came into effect today even as its real impact is likely to be felt only tomorrow, the first working day after the imposition of restriction. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-238760" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/odd-l.jpg" alt="OddEven, Arvind Kejriwal, Delhi" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/odd-l-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/odd-l-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/odd-l.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> According to Delhi transport department, about 60,000 taxis are registered in the national capital and of them 27,000 are running on diesel. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>The ban on plying of 27,000 diesel-run taxis came into effect today even as its real impact is likely to be felt only tomorrow, the first working day after the imposition of restriction.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court yesterday refused to extend the April 30 deadline fixed for the diesel-run taxis for their  conversion into CNG mode.</p>
<p>Authorities in various locations today impounded diesel-run cabs plying on the local routes in the national capital.</p>
<p>&#8220;Instructions have been issued to concerned authorities, including transport department, to impound diesel-run taxis plying in Delhi-NCR,&#8221; said a senior government official.</p>
<p>According to Delhi transport department, about 60,000 taxis are registered in the national capital and of them 27,000 are running on diesel.</p>
<p>Around 2,000 diesel-run taxis had converted into CNG mode in the last two months.</p>
<p>The SC order is not applicable on cabs having All India Permits but most of the diesel cabs ply on local routes.</p>
<p>The ban will essentially bring down the availability of cabs in the capital.</p>
<p>&#8220;As per rule, taxis having All India permit are required to cover a distance of around 200 km. Taxis having All India permits cannot ply from one point to other point inside Delhi, Noida and Ghaziabad,&#8221; the official said.</p>
<p>Cabs going off roads may inconvenience thousands of commuters as many diesel taxis ferry people from Delhi, Noida, Gurgaon and Ghaziabad.</p>
<p>&#8220;We can&#8217;t keep on extending the time. We are not extending it now and not going to make any exceptions. There is technology available, you convert,&#8221; a three-judge bench headed by Chief Justice T S Thakur had yesterday said while rejecting the plea that it would affect livelihood of poor drivers.</p>
<p>The bench, also comprising Justices A K Sikri and R Banumathi, had on March 31, extended the deadline till yesterday for conversion of all diesel taxis to CNG.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/ban-on-diesel-run-taxis-comes-into-effect-in-delhi/246471/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>India on 5th place in fake goods trade; China on top</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-on-5th-place-in-fake-goods-trade-china-on-top/246468/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-on-5th-place-in-fake-goods-trade-china-on-top/246468/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 19:09:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246468</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[India is the fifth biggest exporter of fake goods globally, while China is on the top with a huge 63 per cent share in the estimated half-a-trillion dollar worldwide imports of counterfeit and pirated goods. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-246469" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/fake-goods-l-reut.jpg" alt="China-made products accounted for 63.2 per cent of total seizures of fake imported goods globally, while the second- ranked Turkey's share was just 3.3 per cent. (Reuters)" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/fake-goods-l-reut-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/fake-goods-l-reut-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/fake-goods-l-reut.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> China-made products accounted for 63.2 per cent of total seizures of fake imported goods globally, while the second- ranked Turkey&#8217;s share was just 3.3 per cent. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>India is the fifth biggest exporter of fake goods globally, while China is on the top with a huge 63 per cent share in the estimated half-a-trillion dollar worldwide imports of counterfeit and pirated goods.</p>
<p>China is followed by Turkey, Singapore, Thailand and India among the top-five countries from where most fake goods originate, as per a new study by the OECD (Organisation Economic Cooperation and Development) and the European Union&#8217;s Intellectual Property Office.</p>
<p>China-made products accounted for 63.2 per cent of total seizures of fake imported goods globally, while the second- ranked Turkey&#8217;s share was just 3.3 per cent.</p>
<p>The same for Singapore, Thailand and India stood at 1.9 per cent, 1.6 per cent and 1.2 per cent, respectively.</p>
<p>Among the countries hit hardest by the global trade in fake foods, the US comes on the top and is followed by Italy, France, Switzerland and Japan in the top-five.</p>
<p>&#8220;Imports of counterfeit and pirated goods are worth nearly half a trillion dollars a year, or around 2.5 per cent of global imports, with US, Italian and French brands the hardest hit and many of the proceeds going to organised crime,&#8221; OECD said about the new study that takes into account the latest available figures till the year 2013.</p>
<p>The study puts the value of imported fake goods worldwide at $ 461 billion in 2013, compared with total imports in world trade of $ 17.9 trillion.</p>
<p>&#8220;Up to five per cent of goods imported into the European Union are fakes. Most originate in middle income or emerging countries, with China the top producer,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>The report, which analysed nearly half a million customs seizures around the world over 2011-13, further said that its findings contradict the image that counterfeiters only hurt big companies and luxury goods manufacturers.</p>
<p>Fake products crop up in everything from handbags and perfumes to machine parts and chemicals, while footwear is the most-copied item though trademarks are infringed even on strawberries and bananas.</p>
<p>&#8220;Counterfeiting also produces knockoffs that endanger lives auto parts that fail, pharmaceuticals that make people sick, toys that harm children, baby formula that provides no nourishment and medical instruments that deliver false readings,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>OECD said emerging economies tend to have the infrastructure for large-scale trade but often suffer from governance gaps and may lack the institutions and enforcement capacity to effectively tackle counterfeiting.</p>
<p>&#8220;While China is the top provenance of fake goods, its most innovative companies also fall victim to counterfeiters,&#8221; it said.</p>
<p>Postal parcels are the top method of shipping bogus goods, accounting for 62 per cent of seizures, reflecting the growing importance of online commerce in international trade.</p>
<p>&#8220;The traffic goes through complex routes via major trade hubs like Hong Kong and Singapore and free trade zones such as those in the United Arab Emirates. Other transit points include countries with weak governance and widespread organised crime such as Afghanistan and Syria,&#8221; it said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-on-5th-place-in-fake-goods-trade-china-on-top/246468/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying from IGI Airport gets cheaper</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/flying-from-indira-gandhi-international-airport-gets-cheaper/246465/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/flying-from-indira-gandhi-international-airport-gets-cheaper/246465/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 19:03:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IGI Airport]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246465</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Flying out of IGI Airport here has got cheaper from today with the discontinuation of the development fee being charged from each passenger for the past several years. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-246466" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/IGI-airport-l-IE.jpg" alt="The airports tariff regulator Airports Economic Regulatory Authority (AERA) had in February issued an order directing DIAL to discontinue DF from May 1, after having allowed it to levy DF through a December 2012 order. (Source: IE)" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/IGI-airport-l-IE-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/IGI-airport-l-IE-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/IGI-airport-l-IE.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> The airports tariff regulator Airports Economic Regulatory Authority (AERA) had in February issued an order directing DIAL to discontinue DF from May 1, after having allowed it to levy DF through a December 2012 order. (Source: IE)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Flying out of IGI Airport here has got cheaper from today with the discontinuation of the development fee being charged from each passenger for the past several years.</p>
<p>Delhi International Airport Limited (DIAL), the joint venture company which runs the IGI airport, was allowed to levy Rs 100 per flight as Development Fee (DF) from passengers flying on domestic routes and Rs 600 from those flying to international destinations.</p>
<p>The airports tariff regulator Airports Economic Regulatory Authority (AERA) had in February issued an order directing DIAL to discontinue DF from May 1, after having allowed it to levy DF through a December 2012 order.</p>
<p>Citing the average monthly collection of Rs 30 crore as DF, the AERA had in its order in February said the total sanctioned DF amount of Rs 3,415.35 crore was likely to be recovered by April 30, 2016. To cover the financial gap in developing the airport, the allowable DF was determined at Rs 3,415.35 crore.</p>
<p>Last month, Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) had also asked all airlines operating from Delhi to refund the development fee charged from passengers flying out of the IGI Airport on the tickets booked for journey beyond April 30.</p>
<p>DIAL is a joint venture between GMR group, Airports Authority of India and Germany&#8217;s Fraport AG.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/flying-from-indira-gandhi-international-airport-gets-cheaper/246465/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PM Narendra Modi launches solar-powered e-boats in Varanasi; distributes e-rickshaws</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pm-narendra-modi-launches-solar-powered-e-boats-in-varanasi-distributes-e-rickshaws/246462/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pm-narendra-modi-launches-solar-powered-e-boats-in-varanasi-distributes-e-rickshaws/246462/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 19:27:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[FE Online]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narendra Modi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246462</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi during his Varanasi visit on Sunday launched a scheme for environment-friendly solar-powered 'e-boats' at the Assi Ghat. The scheme to distribute e-boats is an attempt to reduce pollution and keep the Ganga river cleaner.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-246463" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/narendra-modi-l-twitter1.jpg" alt="PM Modi flagged off a fleet of 11 e-boats and also interacted with boatmen at Assi Ghat. (Twitter)" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/narendra-modi-l-twitter1-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/narendra-modi-l-twitter1-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/narendra-modi-l-twitter1.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> PM Modi flagged off a fleet of 11 e-boats and also interacted with boatmen at Assi Ghat. (Twitter)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Prime Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a> during his Varanasi visit on Sunday launched a scheme for environment-friendly solar-powered &#8216;e-boats&#8217; at the Assi Ghat. The scheme to distribute e-boats is an attempt to reduce pollution and keep the Ganga river cleaner.</p>
<p>Talking about the benefits of using e-boats, PM Modi said, &#8220;Tourists will be keen to come and take a ride on Varanasi&#8217;s e-boats, will this not boost tourism here? With e-boats,the boatmen will be able to save Rs 500 a day without spending on diesel. They can use this money for their family.&#8221; &#8220;Whatever money you save, use it for the well being of your children &#8211; their food, their education but don&#8217;t waste what you save,&#8221; Modi urged boatmen.</p>
<p>He also sought support from the people of Varanasi to keep the city and its ghats clean. &#8220;My Kashi will be clean &#8211; can we not take this vow together? We, the people, have to do this, not the government or anybody else,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Modi went on to say, &#8220;Schemes that strengthen the people are important not schemes that strengthen vote banks. We are empowering the poor so that the poor can battle poverty. Shouldn&#8217;t the poor have access to banks just like everyone else? We thought of the poor first when we introduced Jan Dhan Yojana. The poor must have access to banking services. This nation, our government and our banks&#8230;they are for the poor.&#8221;</p>
<p>PM Modi flagged off a fleet of 11 e-boats and also interacted with boatmen at Assi Ghat. PM Modi also rode in an e-boat. The boats have been modified to install solar panels.</p>
<p>&#8220;These e-boats will not only reduce pollution, but will also bring down the operational costs, thereby enabling higher incomes for those who earn their livelihoods through such boats on the river Ganga,&#8221; claims government.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, PM Modi also distributed 1,000 e-rickshaws, meeting and interacting with beneficiaries. Varanasi is the Prime Minister&#8217;s Lok Sabha constituency.</p>
<p>On a visit to Uttar Pradesh, Modi also launched the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana in Ballia. Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana is an NDA government scheme that aims to provide 5 crore free cooking (LPG) connections to below-poverty-line families over the next three years. The ambitious Rs 8,000 crore scheme will partly be funded using the money saved from 1.13 crore cooking gas users voluntarily giving up their subsidies through PM&#8217;s &#8216;Give It Up&#8217; initiative.</p>
<p>Launching the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana, PM Modi said that the cooking gas scheme will benefit 5 crore families till 2019. &#8220;We have shown how the petroleum sector is for the poor,&#8221; Modi said.</p>
<p>&#8220;This cooking gas connection will not only help reduce cost for each family, but will also help better the health of women,&#8221; Modi said at the launch of Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana. &#8220;The subsidy transfer will take place in the Jan Dhan account of the family&#8217;s woman head,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Lauding people for participating in the &#8216;Give It Up&#8217; campaign, PM Modi said, &#8220;I had appealed to people to give up <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/lpg-subsidy/">LPG subsidy</a>; it was a heartfelt plea. I hadn&#8217;t thought of a scheme or follow-up campaign, but the people of this country were great enough to give up their subsidies. I want to laud the over 1 crore families who gave up their LPG subsidies. Those subsidies that were given up have reached the households of poor people through the Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana scheme.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pm-narendra-modi-launches-solar-powered-e-boats-in-varanasi-distributes-e-rickshaws/246462/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICICI Bank top-brass foregoes performance bonus</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/icici-bank-top-brass-foregoes-performance-bonus/246461/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/icici-bank-top-brass-foregoes-performance-bonus/246461/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:31:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chanda Kochhar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICICI Bank]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246461</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Leading private sector lender ICICI Bank, which has posted a sharp plunge in its fourth quarter net profit, has decided against grant of 'performance bonus' to its senior management team for the fiscal 2015-16. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-90040" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/06/ICICI-Bank-Re-e1453298589720.jpg" alt="ICICI Bank Q4 results" /> ICICI Bank on Friday posted 87 per cent plunge in consolidated net profit to Rs 406.71 crore for the March quarter on spike in provisioning for bad loans and creation of a contingency reserve to cushion any future loan defaults. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Leading private sector lender ICICI Bank, which has posted a sharp plunge in its fourth quarter net profit, has decided against grant of &#8216;performance bonus&#8217; to its senior management team for the fiscal 2015-16.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have decided that the senior management would not receive performance bonus for FY2016. Performance bonus would however be paid to employees in the grades of Deputy General Manager and below,&#8221; ICICI Bank&#8217;s Managing Director and CEO Chanda Kochhar said in a post-results analyst call.</p>
<p>Kochhar herself was paid &#8216;performance bonus&#8217; of over Rs 1.6 crore for the fiscal 2014-15, as per the bank&#8217;s annual report for that year. Among others, Executive Director N S Kannan was paid a performance bonus of over Rs 1.1 crore.</p>
<p>The bank pays &#8220;performance linked retention pay (PLRP) to its front-line staff and junior management and performance bonus to its middle and senior management&#8221;.</p>
<p>In its worst performance in over a decade, ICICI Bank on Friday posted 87 per cent plunge in consolidated net profit to Rs 406.71 crore for the March quarter on spike in provisioning for bad loans and creation of a contingency reserve to cushion any future loan defaults.</p>
<p>While provisioning for NPAs more than doubled to Rs 3,326 crore in view of the Reserve Bank&#8217;s asset quality review (AQR) directive, the country&#8217;s largest private sector lender has set aside a large amount of Rs 3,600 crore as reserves for any potential shocks in the future.</p>
<p>Stating that the bank has completed the exercise of review of classification of cases as per <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/rbi/">RBI</a>&#8217;s AQR directive, Kochhar told the analysts, &#8220;We continue to work towards resolution and reduction of exposures through sale of assets and deleveraging, as can be seen in some of the recently announced transactions.</p>
<p>&#8220;The weak global economic environment, sharp downturn in commodity cycle and the gradual nature of the domestic economic recovery has adversely impacted borrowers in certain sectors like iron and steel, mining, power, rigs and cement.</p>
<p>&#8220;While the banks are working towards resolution of stress on certain borrowers in these sectors, it may take some time for solutions to be worked out. In view of the above, the Bank has on a prudent basis made a collective contingency and related reserve of Rs 3,600 crore during fourth quarter towards exposures to these sectors.&#8221;</p>
<p>She emphasised that this was &#8220;over and above&#8221; the provisions made for non-performing and restructured loans as per RBI guidelines.</p>
<p>Kochhar further said the bank has ended the year 2015-16 with &#8220;a very strong capital position, with Tier-1 capital adequacy of 13.09 per cent and total capital adequacy of 16.04 per cent, well above regulatory requirements&#8221;.</p>
<p>In the analyst call, Kannan said the operating expenses rose by 10.3 per cent in the fiscal 2015-16, while employee expenses rose by 5.3 per cent.</p>
<p>During the fiscal, the bank added about 6,239 employees primarily in front-line roles in the retail and rural banking business. Non-employee expenses increased by 13.9 per cent in fiscal 2016 primarily on account of the larger distribution network and higher retail lending volumes, he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/icici-bank-top-brass-foregoes-performance-bonus/246461/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>JNUSU President Kanhaiya Kumar shown black flags in Patna</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/jnusu-president-kanhaiya-kumar-shown-black-flags-in-patna/246458/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/jnusu-president-kanhaiya-kumar-shown-black-flags-in-patna/246458/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:23:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kanhaiya Kumar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246458</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[JNUSU president Kanhaiya Kumar was today shown black flags at a function here by two unidentified persons who were roughed up by his supporters before being detained by the police for questioning. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-246459" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/black-flag-Pti-l.jpg" alt="The JNUSU president, who was addressing the gathering when the incident occurred, said he was not scared of such elements who oppose him or try to distub his functions. (PTI)" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/black-flag-Pti-l-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/black-flag-Pti-l-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/black-flag-Pti-l.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> The JNUSU president, who was addressing the gathering when the incident occurred, said he was not scared of such elements who oppose him or try to distub his functions. (PTI)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>JNUSU president Kanhaiya Kumar was today shown black flags at a function here by two unidentified persons who were roughed up by his supporters before being detained by the police for questioning.</p>
<p>The two persons belonging to a little-known outfit -&#8216;Youth Swaraj&#8217; &#8211; showed black flags to the JNUSU president, besides raising slogan of &#8216;Bharat Mata Ki Jai&#8217; while he was speaking at a function &#8216;Azadi&#8217; in S K Memorial hall here organised by AISF and AIYF.</p>
<p>Kanhaiya&#8217;s supporters thrashed the two persons in the hall. Later the police took the duo into custody.</p>
<p>&#8220;Police have detained two persons in this regard,&#8221; Patna Senior Superintendent of Police Manu Maharaj told PTI.</p>
<p>The two detainees have been identified as Nitish Kumar, a resident of Sitamarhi district, and Manikant Mani, a resident of Samastipur district, the police said, adding that the two youths are said to be the members of RSS.</p>
<p>The JNUSU president, who was addressing the gathering when the incident occurred, said he was not scared of such elements who oppose him or try to distub his functions.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am not scared of anything whether you hurl a shoe or a stone&#8230;. They want to disturb my programmes as they are uncomfortable with my questions,&#8221; Kumar said.</p>
<p>Attacking Prime Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a>, Kumar alleged that he became the PM &#8220;with the support of capitalists&#8221; and cannot solve the problem of unemployment.</p>
<p>Criticizing those who say that tax-payers&#8217; money or subsidy being provided to the JNU is a waste of public money, Kumar said that there is a &#8220;conspiracy&#8221; to &#8220;defame&#8221; the premier academic institution of the country.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am a PhD scholar who is the son of an Anganwadi worker. This itself proves that taxpayers&#8217; money or subsidy given to JNU is spent and utilised properly,&#8221; Kumar said, adding that people should not worry about wastage of taxpayers&#8217; money as a large majority of people in the country want JNU like institutions.</p>
<p>Alleging that only capitalists get loans from banks, he said they &#8220;do not repay loans and instead they fly to London overnight&#8221;, a reference to the fugitive industrialist Vijay Mallya, who is in Britain after defaulting on a loan of over Rs 9000 crore.</p>
<p>Kumar was given a rousing welcome in the state yesterday. He was escorted by a posse of policemen at airport on his arrival from New Delhi and the JNUSU President moved with a convoy in the state capital.</p>
<p>Kanhaiya, who hails from Begusarai district of Bihar, is on a two-day tour of his home state and met both Chief Minister Nitish Kumar and RJD president <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/lalu-yadav/">Lalu Prasad Yadav</a> yesterday.</p>
<p>Kanhaiya shot into limelight after he was arrested in a sedition case in connection with a controversial event in JNU. He is currently out on interim bail.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/jnusu-president-kanhaiya-kumar-shown-black-flags-in-patna/246458/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sebi to hit cinema screens to spread investor awareness</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/sebi-to-hit-cinema-screens-to-spread-investor-awareness/246457/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/sebi-to-hit-cinema-screens-to-spread-investor-awareness/246457/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:06:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Indian Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246457</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To spread investor awareness and financial education, markets regulator Sebi plans to explore cinema advertising and digital platforms for its advertising campaigns, including on ponzi menace and dabba trading. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-221913" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/03/sebi-e1457683162592.jpg" alt="Sebi - Green bonds" /> Sebi also plans to undertake development of new study material such as brochures and booklet, which would be distributed in various education and awareness programs conducted pan India. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>To spread investor awareness and financial education, markets regulator Sebi plans to explore cinema advertising and digital platforms for its advertising campaigns, including on ponzi menace and dabba trading.</p>
<p>Besides, the regulator also plans to undertake financial market education and training programmes for specific target groups such as teachers and police officials.</p>
<p>As part of its mass media campaign, Sebi (Securities and Exchange Board of India) has so far carried one campaign on its Investor Grievance Redressal Mechanism and six on on unregistered collective investment schemes and ponzi menace.</p>
<p>Some new campaign relate to &#8216;dabba trading&#8217; and to ASBA (Applications Supported by Blocked Amount) facility that allows money to remain in the investor&#8217;s account till shares are actually allotted to him or her in public offers.</p>
<p>In the current financial year, Sebi would run campaigns on various media platforms, including on TV channels, radio and print, on these new topics as well as on ponzi schemes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sebi also intend to explore other media such as cinema advertising, digital media etc so as to increase the reach of SEBI in spreading education and awareness,&#8221; as per the regulator&#8217;s Plan of Action for the current financial year.</p>
<p>This fiscal, Sebi also plans to increase the number of various education and awareness programs through Resource Persons workshops and through Investor Associations, by over 30 per cent and 20 per cent, respectively.</p>
<p>To meet this objective, Sebi would empanel new Resource Persons across the country, while its Regional Offices have been asked to ensure at least one Resource Person per district. Besides, refresher training of the eligible RPs is proposed to be undertaken under all the offices.</p>
<p>Sebi also plans to undertake development of new study material such as brochures and booklet, which would be distributed in various education and awareness programs conducted pan India.</p>
<p>The regulator would also participate in various fairs and exhibitions to promote education and awareness among investors.</p>
<p>Periodic follow up meetings would be conducted with the recognized Investors Associations and Resource Persons at Sebi&#8217;s Headquarters in Mumbai and at regional level so as to synergize the efforts related to education and awareness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/sebi-to-hit-cinema-screens-to-spread-investor-awareness/246457/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>India ready to clear $ 6.5 billion of Iran&#8217;s oil dues</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-ready-to-clear-6-5-billion-of-irans-oil-dues/246456/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-ready-to-clear-6-5-billion-of-irans-oil-dues/246456/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 17:47:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Petroleum Minister Dharmendra Pradhan and External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj had visited Iran last month during which they had conveyed to Iranian leaders that India wants to significantly ramp up engagement in oil and gas sector with that country. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-245444" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/us-reut1.jpg" alt="Crude Oil, Crude Oil News, Crude Oil Latest New" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/us-reut1-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/us-reut1-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/us-reut1.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> Refiners like Essar Oil and Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals Ltd (MPRL) owe nearly $ 6.5 billion in dues to Iran. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Keen to step up engagement in hydrocarbon sector with Iran, India has conveyed to the Persian Gulf nation that it was ready to clear nearly $ 6.5 billion of the dues for oil import from that country at the earliest, provided there was clarity on payment channel.</p>
<p>The message has been conveyed to Iran even as Prime Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a> is likely to visit the oil-rich country later this month.</p>
<p>Government sources said there has been a series of discussions at various levels both in Tehran and here and both sides were confident of resolving the issue soon.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working on clearing the dues to Iran and are hopeful that the issue will be resolved soon,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>Following lifting of sanctions against it in January under a historic nuclear deal, Iran had terminated a three-year-old system with India of getting paid for half of the oil dues in rupees and has been insisting on being paid in Euros for the oil it sells to Indian refiners.</p>
<p>It has also scrapped free delivery of crude oil to Indian refiners.</p>
<p>Officials said though Western sanctions against Iran were lifted, problems persist in banking channels due to which regular transactions were not possible yet.</p>
<p>Refiners like Essar Oil and Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals Ltd (MPRL) owe nearly $ 6.5 billion in dues to Iran.</p>
<p>Since February 2013, Indian refiners like Essar Oil and MRPL paid 45 per cent of their import bill in rupees to UCO Bank account of Iranian oil company.</p>
<p>The remaining has been accumulating, pending finalisation of a payment mechanism.</p>
<p>Petroleum Minister Dharmendra Pradhan and External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj had visited Iran last month during which they had conveyed to Iranian leaders that India wants to significantly ramp up engagement in oil and gas sector with that country.</p>
<p>The issue of the pending dues had also figured in the meetings.</p>
<p>Swaraj during her visit had conveyed to Iranian leadership that India wants to invest in joint ventures in oil and gas sectors in the Persian Gulf nation where foreign investors from major economic powers are rushing in to get early footholds after lifting of sanctions.</p>
<p>Following lifting of sanctions against Iran, India has been eying deeper energy ties with that country and has already lined up $ 20 billion as investment in oil and gas as well as petrochemical and fertiliser projects there.</p>
<p>New Delhi is looking to increase engagement with the sanction-free Iran by raising oil imports and possible shipments of natural gas. It also wants rights to develop Farzad-B gas field in the Persian Gulf discovered by OVL.</p>
<p>A deal for the field was not signed during Pradhan&#8217;s visit as Iranian Parliament, Majlis, is yet to approve the new Iran Petroleum Contract (IPC) under which the Farzad-B field is to be given to the OVL-led consortium.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/india-ready-to-clear-6-5-billion-of-irans-oil-dues/246456/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>300 &#8216;smart&#8217; villages to be developed in Gujarat: Anandiben Patel</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/300-smart-villages-to-be-developed-in-gujarat-anandiben-patel/246451/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/300-smart-villages-to-be-developed-in-gujarat-anandiben-patel/246451/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 17:41:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On 57th Foundation Day, Gujarat Chief Minister Anandiben Patel today said her government has decided to make 300 villages across the state self-reliant on the lines of smart cities. ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="size-full wp-image-246454" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/anandi-patel-l-reyt.jpg" alt="Anandiben Patel was in Chhotaudepur town of the tribal-dominated district, about 100 kms from here to attend state-level Foundation Day celebrations. (Reuters)" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/anandi-patel-l-reyt-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/anandi-patel-l-reyt-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/05/anandi-patel-l-reyt.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> Anandiben Patel was in Chhotaudepur town of the tribal-dominated district, about 100 kms from here to attend state-level Foundation Day celebrations. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>On 57th Foundation Day, Gujarat Chief Minister Anandiben Patel today said her government has decided to make 300 villages across the state self-reliant on the lines of smart cities.</p>
<p>&#8220;Now that the concept of Smart Cities has reached Smart Villages, the government decided to make 300 villages self-reliant, clean and hygienic during this year,&#8221; she said in an official release here today.</p>
<p>Patel was in Chhotaudepur town of the tribal-dominated district, about 100 kms from here to attend state-level Foundation Day celebrations. Gujarat Governor O P Kohli will also attend the event later in the day.</p>
<p>Announcing a slew of measures on the occasion, Patel in her message said, &#8220;the government will set up a Tribal university in the Narmada district, over 100 smart Ashram shalas, 10 new hostels for tribal girl students at a cost of Rs 3 crore, besides &#8216;Samras&#8217; hostels at a cost of Rs 10 crore.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The government has reserved 33 per cent in jobs for women, under which 2,800 women have been employed in police department. There is a plan to provide jobs to 22,000 women this year,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>This is in addition to providing 300 sq m land and Rs 5 lakh assistance to milk societies run by women to construct milk houses, besides providing chilling centres, milking machines and chaff cutters to 2.50 lakh Sakhi Mandals (Self-Help Groups) of 35 lakh women.</p>
<p>To realise the goal of health for all, Patel said, &#8220;we have started certain key schemes like screening of 78 lakh women to test breast, cervical and mouth cancer besides treatment of 1,018 women cancer patients in super speciality hospitals free-of-cost, relief for poor and middle-class families under Amritam-Ma Yojna.&#8221;</p>
<p>Also, allocation under Ma-Vatsalya Yojna has been increased by 33 per cent to Rs 160 crore and the government is bearing the cost up to Rs 2 lakh for each such patient, she said.</p>
<p>&#8220;The government has decided to provide free medicine to diabetes and blood pressure patients. It has decided to spend Rs 102 crore on 100 vehicles in 108 ambulance service.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/300-smart-villages-to-be-developed-in-gujarat-anandiben-patel/246451/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ujjivan to open 100 new branches to meet licence norms</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/ujjivan-to-open-100-new-branches-to-meet-licence-norms/246443/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/ujjivan-to-open-100-new-branches-to-meet-licence-norms/246443/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:44:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246443</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ujjivan officials said the manpower will be increased with the proposed small bank license to around 10,000 from 7862 employees.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Micro-lender Ujjivan Financial Services, which has launched a Rs 885-crore IPO, will open 100 odd bank branches to meet the regulatory norm for a small bank licence.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need to have 25 per cent of bank branches in unbanked areas. Currently, we have none. Due to operational factors our existing branches are mostly next to PSU bank braches. We propose to set up about 100 new branches in unbanked locations,&#8221; Ujjivan MD and CEO Samit Ghosh told PTI.</p>
<p>He said identification process for such new branches had begun and the company which would become the holding company for the proposed Ujjivan Small Bank would meet the criteria once the bank is launched.</p>
<p>Ghosh had said the bank would be launched by April 2017.</p>
<p>Another requirement which Ujjivan has to fulfil is to bring down the foreign holding 49 per cent or lower.</p>
<p>&#8220;According to regulatory requirement, the foreign holding in the small bank has to be less than 49 per cent. IPO is the first step towards transformation to a small bank. Foreign shareholding has come down to 77 per cent following a pre-IPO placement. The IPO will help reduce further to 44-45 per cent,&#8221; Ghosh said.</p>
<p>Ujjivan has about 11.15 per cent marketshare of the NBFC-MFI business in the country with some 470 odd existing branches spread across 24 states.</p>
<p>&#8220;The entire business will be moved to the bank. Some 40 per cent of our existing 470 branches spread across 24 states will be brought under the bank branches in the initial phase,&#8221; Ujjivan strategy executive Rajat Singh said.</p>
<p>Ujjivan officials said the manpower will be increased with the proposed small bank license to around 10,000 from 7862 employees.</p>
<p>Ujjivans issue, which is scheduled to close on May 2, comprises fresh issuance of shares worth Rs 358.16 crore and an offer for sale of up to 24,968,332 shares by the existing shareholders at a price band of 207-210. PTI BSM PR MR 05011417</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/ujjivan-to-open-100-new-branches-to-meet-licence-norms/246443/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New uniform for Air India cabin crew in the offing</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/new-uniform-for-air-india-cabin-crew-in-the-offing/246442/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/new-uniform-for-air-india-cabin-crew-in-the-offing/246442/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:41:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Air India]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The cabin crew strength in Air India currently stands at around 4,000.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-229028 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/03/air-india-one-l-reuters.jpg" alt="Air India One" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/03/air-india-one-l-reuters-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/03/air-india-one-l-reuters-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/03/air-india-one-l-reuters.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> The state-owned carrier had last April given a makeover to the cabin crew uniform. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>A makeover for Air India&#8217;s cabin crew is in the offing soon with an internal committee, mostly comprising the in-flight staff, suggesting various sartorial options for draping themselves.</p>
<p>A 10-member committee, set up from within the ranks and headed by the General Manager for Cabin Crew, has suggested various options for patterns, material, texture and colours, among other things for the cabin crew uniform in its report, a senior Air India official told PTI here.</p>
<p>The options in the report are now being evaluated by the management before taking a final call on the issue, he said.</p>
<p>The cabin crew strength in Air India currently stands at around 4,000.</p>
<p>&#8220;The use of indigenous fabric &#8216;khadi&#8217; for draping the cabin crew is one of the several choices suggested by the committee,&#8221; the official said, not ruling out the possibility of the management looking at this option keeping in view the Prime Minister&#8217;s flagship project &#8216;<a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/make-in-india/">Make in India</a>&#8217;.</p>
<p>Significantly, the cabin crew operating Air India One, the official aircraft of the President, the Prime Minister and the Vice-President, during a recent official trip of Modi to Belgium and the US was all draped in khadi uniform.</p>
<p>&#8220;This was for the first time that such a committee was set up at the airline with all its members drawn from the cabin crew from across regional bases and also across fleets &#8212; wide-body and narrow-body. The idea was to give them a flexibility and freedom to chose the uniform they feel comfortable with,&#8221; the official said,</p>
<p>&#8220;Sampling of the clothing based on the committee&#8217;s suggestions is being carried out currently. Once this exercise is completed, the samples would be placed before the authorities concerned for a final view,&#8221; the official said.</p>
<p>The state-owned carrier had last April given a makeover to the cabin crew uniform.</p>
<p>At that time, while retaining the traditional saree as part of the uniform, it had introduced kurtis, churidars and trousers, besides Western style clothing to give a more contemporary look to its flight attendants.</p>
<p>Air India had the uniforms designed by the National Institute of Fashion Technology.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/new-uniform-for-air-india-cabin-crew-in-the-offing/246442/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mutual funds approach Sebi with 35 new proposals in 2016</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/mutual-funds-approach-sebi-with-35-new-proposals-in-2016/246441/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/mutual-funds-approach-sebi-with-35-new-proposals-in-2016/246441/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:26:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Indian Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246441</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Retirement, fixed maturity plan (FMP), equity and debt are some of the themes for which mutual fund houses have filed the applications.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-206978 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/mutual-funds660.jpg" alt="mutual funds outflow" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/mutual-funds660-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/mutual-funds660-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/mutual-funds660.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> Interestingly, many mutual fund companies submitted papers with Sebi for launching plans with Hindi names so that investors in rural areas understand the objectives of the schemes in a better manner.</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>To tap the growing demand from retail investors, mutual fund houses have filed draft papers with markets regulator Sebi to launch as many as 35 New Fund Offers (NFO) in the first four months of the year.</p>
<p>Retirement, fixed maturity plan (FMP), equity and debt are some of the themes for which mutual fund houses have filed the applications.</p>
<p>In addition, mutual fund houses are eyeing overseas stock exchanges for investment purpose.</p>
<p>Sundaram Mutual Fund filed papers for a scheme (Sundaram World Brand Fund) that will invest in equity and equity related instruments listed on overseas stock exchanges across the world, while Reliance MF approached Sebi for launching a Korea-focussed fund in Indian markets.</p>
<p>Interestingly, many mutual fund companies submitted papers with Sebi for launching plans with Hindi names so that investors in rural areas understand the objectives of the schemes in a better manner. The move is seen as moving away from the old tradition of English names for investment schemes.</p>
<p>&#8216;Bal Vikas Yojana&#8217;, a scheme aimed at saving for children&#8217;s future, Kar Bachat Yojana, a tax saving fund, &#8216;Bachat Yojana&#8217; and &#8216;Nivesh Lakshya&#8217; both fixed income schemes, are some of the launch schemes filed with Sebi by Mahindra MF and Reliance MF.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our idea is to explain the investment opportunities to customers in our priority markets in their own language starting with the product names,&#8221; Mahindra AMC MD and Chief Executive Ashutosh Bishnoi said.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, draft documents for 35 NFOs have been submitted with the Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi). Of these, 16 draft offers have been filed in last month alone.</p>
<p>According to market participants, MF houses are rushing towards Sebi to launch new schemes on account of growing demand from retail investors for such products as well as robust response received from investors in the recent fund launches.</p>
<p>There has been a growing demand from retail investors for mutual fund products as the investors base touched a record high of 4.76 crore at the end of March.</p>
<p>A total of 191 draft papers were filed last year with the capital markets watchdog.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/mutual-funds-approach-sebi-with-35-new-proposals-in-2016/246441/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PAC asks Raghuram Rajan to explain &#8216;real causes&#8217; of bad-loan menace</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pac-asks-raghuram-rajan-to-explain-real-causes-of-bad-loan-menace/246449/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pac-asks-raghuram-rajan-to-explain-real-causes-of-bad-loan-menace/246449/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:12:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raghuram Rajan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At the end of December, as many as 701 accounts with bad loans exceeding Rs 100 crore owed public sector banks (PSBs) Rs 1.63 lakh crore, while SBI accounted for the biggest chunk.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-205818 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/Raghuram-Rajan-EP1.jpg" alt="Raghuram Rajan" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/Raghuram-Rajan-EP1-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/Raghuram-Rajan-EP1-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/02/Raghuram-Rajan-EP1.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> Other reasons cited by Rajan were laxity in credit risk appraisal and loan monitoring in banks and lack of appraising skills for projects that need specialised skills resulting in acceptance of inflated cost and aggressive projections. (Express photo)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Asked to explain the &#8220;real causes&#8221; of ballooning bad loans at public sector banks, <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/rbi/">RBI</a> Governor <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/raghuram-rajan/">Raghuram Rajan</a> has put the blame on &#8220;overall economic downturn&#8221;, among other reasons, in his submission to the key Parliamentary Panel.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/congress/">Congress</a> leader K V Thomas-led Public Accounts Committee (PAC), whose term ended yesterday, has examined Rajan&#8217;s response but can ask the RBI Governor to appear before it in future once it is reconstituted, sources said.</p>
<p>Various public sector banks may also be asked to appear before the panel again to explain their position.</p>
<p>The Parliamentary Panel had suo motu decided to examine the non-performing assets of the public sector banks, which touched Rs 3.61 lakh crore at the end of December 2015.</p>
<p>At the end of December, as many as 701 accounts with bad loans exceeding Rs 100 crore owed public sector banks (PSBs) Rs 1.63 lakh crore, while SBI accounted for the biggest chunk.</p>
<p>PSBs had first refused to appear before PAC, but agreed later and made their submission.</p>
<p>During the examination of bad loan recovery process of the banks, the PAC found that in a number of cases the same bankers were trying to retrieve the bad loans who had earlier sanctioned the loans.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since the same officers, who sanctioned the loans are trying to retrieve it, it remains to be seen how successful they will be.. It seems they did not have a mechanism,&#8221; a PAC member said on the condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>In its questionnaire for the RBI Governor, the panel observed that Private Sector Banks and Foreign Banks do not have as much NPAs as the Public Sector Banks. This was despite the constraints under which the entire banking sector operates being the same, except for the Priority Sector Lending (PSL) requirements.</p>
<p>Noting that Private Sector Banks and Foreign Banks have 2.2 per cent NPAs whereas the Public Sector Banks have 5.98 per cent NPAs, the PAC felt &#8220;it is hard to believe that the difference is only due to the PSL&#8221;.</p>
<p>The PAC Chairman also sought to know the &#8220;real causes for the present spurt in NPAs and stressed assets&#8221; and whether these are really different from those listed by the Narsimham Committee that went into the NPA issue in 1998.</p>
<p>In his reply, Rajan said, &#8220;While some of the reasons for recent spurt in NPAs could be subset of those indicated by Narasimham Committee, the level of stressed assets are seen in the context of overall economic downturn&#8221;.</p>
<p>Rajan listed six primary reasons for spurt in stressed assets that have been observed in recent times.</p>
<p>These included domestic and global economic slowdown, delays in statutory and other approvals especially for projects under implementation and aggressive lending practices during upturn as evidenced from high corporate leverage.</p>
<p>Other reasons cited by Rajan were laxity in credit risk appraisal and loan monitoring in banks and lack of appraising skills for projects that need specialised skills resulting in acceptance of inflated cost and aggressive projections. Besides, he also listed wilful default, loan frauds and corruption in some cases among the key reasons.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/pac-asks-raghuram-rajan-to-explain-real-causes-of-bad-loan-menace/246449/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steady economic growth fails to revive job market: Report</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/steady-economic-growth-fails-to-revive-job-market-report/246446/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/steady-economic-growth-fails-to-revive-job-market-report/246446/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:59:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jobs and Education]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246446</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The industries that witnessed decline in employment growth were telecom, engineering, electronics, packaging and cables, it added.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-185312 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/12/Economy-EP.jpg" alt="Indian economy, economic growth rate" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/12/Economy-EP-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/12/Economy-EP-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/12/Economy-EP.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> The report analysed employment data across various sectors as well as industries and is based on a sample of 1,072 companies across various sectors. (Express photo)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Notwithstanding the Indian economy&#8217;s steady growth, sectors such as telecom, engineering and electronics have witnessed a decline in employment rate over the last four years, says a report.</p>
<p>&#8220;The economic growth witnessed at the macro-level has not translated into more jobs creation,&#8221; according to Care Ratings report on &#8216;Employment in the Corporate Sector&#8217;.</p>
<p>The industries that witnessed decline in employment growth were telecom, engineering, electronics, packaging and cables, it added.</p>
<p>Care Ratings said the economic growth performance has been impressive but the employment curve has not kept pace with the same.</p>
<p>The report analysed employment data across various sectors as well as industries and is based on a sample of 1,072 companies across various sectors.</p>
<p>Care Ratings opined that jobs need to be created not just to sustain the issue of employment but also add to consumer demand, which has been lagging in the last three years and has to be reversed.</p>
<p>Negative growth under the manufacturing segment was witnessed in electronics (4.5 per cent), engineering (6.6 per cent) and telecommunication (7.9 per cent).</p>
<p>Other sectors that saw a negative growth in FY2014-15 were non financial services (17.4 per cent), construction (17.1 per cent) and mining (3.8 per cent), the report added.</p>
<p>&#8220;Manufacturing in particular has not done too well, while services performed better. The preference for services even for the pool of employable people can distort the demand-supply equation when manufacturing is back on track,&#8221; it said.</p>
<p>The report revealed that manufacturing had the highest share in employment accounting for more than 40 per cent of jobs creation, followed by banking (23 per cent) and information technology (18.4 per cent), the report said.</p>
<p>This means that the future of job creation would largely be dependent on the growth in the manufacturing sector and the low growth in the last 3 years is a cause for concern, it said.</p>
<p>Financial and other non financial services together account for 5.</p>
<p>2 per cent share in total employment.</p>
<p>The highest growth rate in jobs were in forgings, consumer foods, IT, breweries and pharmaceuticals. Meanwhile, in 2014-15, IT, banking and financial services were the only sectors to witness positive growth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/steady-economic-growth-fails-to-revive-job-market-report/246446/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Narendra Modi got first class in MA from Guj University: VC</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/narendra-modi-got-first-class-in-ma-from-guj-university-vc/246445/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/narendra-modi-got-first-class-in-ma-from-guj-university-vc/246445/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:54:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narendra Modi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The details were shared by the Gujarat University after the Central Information Commission directed it to provide the same to Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal, who had recently criticised the functioning of the transparency panel.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-242979 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/Narendra-Modi-Re-1.jpg" alt="Narendra-Modi-Re" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/Narendra-Modi-Re-1-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/Narendra-Modi-Re-1-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/Narendra-Modi-Re-1.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> After Kejriwal&#8217;s letter, the CIC had on Friday ordered Delhi University, from where he pursued his Bachelor of Arts (BA) course, and Gujarat University, from where he completed his MA, to reveal details of his education qualifications. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Amid the raging row over Prime Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a>&#8217;s educational qualification, the Gujarat University today shared details of his MA degree saying he scored 62.3 per cent as an external student of the varsity.</p>
<p>The details were shared by the Gujarat University after the Central Information Commission directed it to provide the same to Delhi Chief Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/arvind-kejriwal/">Arvind Kejriwal</a>, who had recently criticised the functioning of the transparency panel.</p>
<p>&#8220;Narendra Damodardas Modi passed his MA in Political Science in 1983 with first class, securing 499 out of 800 marks, which comes to 62.3 per cent as an external student,&#8221; Gujarat University&#8217;s Vice Chancellor M N Patel told PTI today.</p>
<p>Kejriwal, in a letter to CIC in response to an RTI application seeking details of his electoral photo identity card (EPIC), demanded that while he was ready to share information sought by RTI applicants, the CIC must also order disclosure of educational qualifications of the PM.</p>
<p>After Kejriwal&#8217;s letter, the CIC had on Friday ordered Delhi University, from where he pursued his Bachelor of Arts (BA) course, and Gujarat University, from where he completed his MA, to reveal details of his education qualifications.</p>
<p>Vice Chancellor Patel said he has not received any order of CIC till now, but he came to know about it from media, and will give the details to concerned applicants if he receives the order.</p>
<p>&#8220;The details (of Modi&#8217;s degree) were sought through several Right to Information (RTI) applications filed before the university, but we were not in a position to share the details under the RTI Act on technical grounds,&#8221; Patel said.</p>
<p>&#8220;The details of marks can only be provided to the candidate himself, and we do not provide details of university records beyond 20 years,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>When asked about the details of Modi&#8217;s BA degree, Patel said they do not have it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Modi did his MA as an external candidate. He secured 237 out of 400 marks in MA first year, and 262 out of 400 marks in MA second year,&#8221; Patel said giving the details.</p>
<p>&#8220;The breakup of marks in second year MA shows that Modi obtained 64 marks in political science, 62 marks in European and social political thoughts, 69 marks in modern India/political analysis, and 67 marks in political psychology,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The CIC, acting on the letter from Kejriwal, had asked the Delhi University and Gujarat University to &#8220;make best possible search for the information regarding degrees in the name of Mr Narendra Damodardas Modi in the year 1978 (Graduation in DU) and 1983 (Post Graduation in GU) and provide it to the appellant Mr Kejriwal as soon as possible&#8221;.</p>
<p>The genesis of the case is in two previous CIC orders and a scathing letter from Kejriwal to Information Commissioner Sridhar Acharyulu where he demanded that while he was ready to share information sought by RTI applicants, the CIC must also order disclosure of educational qualifications of the Prime Minister.</p>
<p>In a case related to one Neeraj Pandey, who sought information about electoral photo identity card of the Delhi Chief Minister, Acharyulu had sought explanation from Kejriwal why he as an MLA be not declared as Public authority under the RTI Act and why his party too was not brought under the Act.</p>
<p>Kejriwal in his response did not object to disclosure of information about him but raised a demand for information about Prime Minister&#8217;s educational qualifications referring to Hans Raj Jain case, Acharyulu had noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;He stated that while CIC wanted Mr Kejriwal&#8217;s information to be given, CIC was obstructing the information about degrees of Mr Modi, the Prime Minister. He expressed surprise over this and also doubted objectivity of the Commission,&#8221; Acharyulu said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/india-news/narendra-modi-got-first-class-in-ma-from-guj-university-vc/246445/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Non-subsidised LPG, kerosene, ATF prices hiked</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/non-subsidised-lpg-kerosene-atf-prices-hiked/246444/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/non-subsidised-lpg-kerosene-atf-prices-hiked/246444/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:49:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Non-subsidised cooking gas (LPG) now costs Rs 527.50 in Delhi as against Rs 509.50 previously. The hike comes on back of three straight monthly reductions.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-241550 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/lpg.jpg" alt="Modi government, PM Modi, Narendra Modi, LPG, LPG connections, Pradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/lpg-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/lpg-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/lpg.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> Kerosene sold to non-ration card segment outside the subsidised public distribution system (PDS) will cost Rs 49,109.05 per kilolitre (kl) or Rs 49.1 a litre in Delhi as against Rs 46,172.13 per kl previously. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>After petrol and diesel, rates of non-subsidised cooking gas, non-PDS kerosene and aviation turbine fuel (ATF) were today raised in line with global trends.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/petrol/">Petrol price</a> was late last night hiked by Rs 1.06 a litre to Rs 62.19 per litre in Delhi and diesel by Rs 2.94 to Rs 50.95 a litre.</p>
<p>The increase was followed up today with nearly Rs 3 per litre hike in price of non-PDS kerosene, according to state- owned oil companies.</p>
<p>Kerosene sold to non-ration card segment outside the subsidised public distribution system (PDS) will cost Rs 49,109.05 per kilolitre (kl) or Rs 49.1 a litre in Delhi as against Rs 46,172.13 per kl previously.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, the oil firms raised prices of non- subsidised LPG, which consumers buy after exhausting their quota of 12, by Rs 18 per 14.2-kg cylinder.</p>
<p>Non-subsidised cooking gas (LPG) now costs Rs 527.50 in Delhi as against Rs 509.50 previously. The hike comes on back of three straight monthly reductions. Prices were last cut by Rs 4 on April 1. Rates were reduced by Rs 61.50 on March 1 and Rs 82.5 per 14.2-kg bottle on February 1.</p>
<p>Subsidised LPG costs Rs 419.15 per 14.2-kg cylinder in Delhi.</p>
<p>Aviation Turbine Fuel (ATF), or jet fuel, price was today hiked by 1.5 per cent.</p>
<p>ATF price in Delhi was raised by Rs 627 per kilolitre, or 1.48 pr cent, to Rs 42,784.01 per kl. The hike comes on the back of of a steep 8.7 per cent or Rs 3,371.55 per kl hike on April 1.</p>
<p>Prior to that, rates were hiked by steep 12 per cent, or Rs 4,174.49, on March 1.</p>
<p>Rates vary at different airports because of differential local sales tax or value-added tax (VAT).</p>
<p>Jet fuel constitutes over 40 per cent of an airline&#8217;s operating cost and the price increase will add to the financial burden of cash-strapped carriers.</p>
<p>No immediate comment was available from airlines on the impact of the price increase on passenger fares.</p>
<p>The three fuel retailers &#8212; Indian Oil Corporation, Hindustan Petroleum and Bharat Petroleum &#8212; revise jet fuel and non-subsidised LPG prices on the first day of every month, based on the average international price in the preceding month.</p>
<p>The ATF price cut on March 10 was on account of change in taxation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/non-subsidised-lpg-kerosene-atf-prices-hiked/246444/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FPIs stay glued to Indian market, put in USD 2.2 bn in April</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/fpis-stay-glued-to-indian-market-put-in-usd-2-2-bn-in-april/246440/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/fpis-stay-glued-to-indian-market-put-in-usd-2-2-bn-in-april/246440/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 09:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:19:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Indian Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[FPIs turned net buyers of equities in March after pulling out a massive Rs 41,661 crore from the market in the previous four months (November to February).]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><img class="wp-image-242147 size-full" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/dollar-reu-L.jpg" alt="dollar-reu-L" srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/dollar-reu-L-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/dollar-reu-L-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2016/04/dollar-reu-L.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /> This year so far, FPIs have invested Rs 12,911 crore in equities while withdrawing Rs 939 crore in the debt market, resulting in a net inflow of Rs 11,971 crore. (Reuters)</figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Foreign investors continued to invest in Indian capital markets for the second month in April, as they pumped in USD 2.2 billion in equities and debt, driven by hopes of good monsoon and positive economic data.</p>
<p>In the previous month, FPIs had invested a staggering Rs 19,967 crore in capital markets &#8212; both equities and debt.</p>
<p>FPIs turned net buyers of equities in March after pulling out a massive Rs 41,661 crore from the market in the previous four months (November to February).</p>
<p>This year so far, FPIs have invested Rs 12,911 crore in equities while withdrawing Rs 939 crore in the debt market, resulting in a net inflow of Rs 11,971 crore.</p>
<p>Market experts attributed the huge inflow in April month to the rate cut by <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/rbi/">RBI</a> in its first monetary policy meet of 2016-17 on April 5.</p>
<p>RBI had reduced the short-term lending rate by 0.25 per cent to an over 5-year low of 6.5 per cent.</p>
<p>Besides, investor sentiment has improved further following positive macroeconomic data, including a cooling inflation and a forecast of an above-normal monsoon this year, igniting hopes of a higher growth and more policy easing by RBI, experts added.</p>
<p>According to data available with depositories, foreign portfolio investors (FPIs) invested Rs 8,416 crore in equities last month, while it stood at Rs 6,418 crore for the debt market, leading to a total inflow of Rs 14,834 crore (USD 2.23 billion).</p>
<p>&#8220;Following the recent rate cut by RBI, bond prices have rallied (prices move inversely to rate), which has led to inflows from FPIs in anticipation of further price appreciation in future,&#8221; SAS Online Chief Operating Officer (COO) Siddhant Jain said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Also, the recent hike by capital markets regulator Sebi in the FPI investment limit for government debt will lead to more FPI inflows.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/fpis-stay-glued-to-indian-market-put-in-usd-2-2-bn-in-april/246440/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Govt wants PSUs to emulate private sector, buy back shares</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/govt-wants-psus-to-emulate-private-sector-buy-back-shares/246437/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/govt-wants-psus-to-emulate-private-sector-buy-back-shares/246437/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 09:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:01:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSU]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246437</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Government wants cash-rich PSUs like Coal India, Oil India and NTPC to take a cue from the private sector and use surplus cash to buy back shares and improve balance sheets.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/article/markets/indian-markets/global-market-rout-a-huge-risk-for-ipos/125656/attachment/psu-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-125659"><img class="wp-image-125659" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/08/PSU.jpg" alt="With public sector companies sitting on an estimated cash pile of Rs 2.6 lakh crore, leveraging surplus cash would be the best option for them rather than going for disinvestment." srcset="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/08/PSU-300x200.jpg 300w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/08/PSU-620x413.jpg 620w, http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/08/PSU.jpg 780w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /></a><figcaption><h2></a> With public sector companies sitting on an estimated cash pile of Rs 2.6 lakh crore, leveraging surplus cash would be the best option for them rather than going for disinvestment.</h2></figcaption></figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Government wants cash-rich PSUs like Coal India, Oil India and NTPC to take a cue from the private sector and use surplus cash to buy back shares and improve balance sheets.</p>
<p>&#8220;Major private sector companies have a treasury wing to make use of their cash balance more effectively. PSUs have so far not been able to manage their cash balance efficiently. DIPAM will endeavour to help PSUs to utilise their cash balance for resource augmentation,&#8221; an official said.</p>
<p>As many as eight private sector companies, including Bharti Infratel, <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/bharti-airtel/">Bharti Airtel</a>, Wipro, Dr Reddy&#8217;s and OnMobile Global, in 2016 have announced buy-back plans totalling about Rs 7,700 crore.</p>
<p>&#8220;Private companies have been using buy-back as a strategy of investment management. They assess ways to increase resources and at the same time how best to maximise returns to equity shareholders,&#8221; the official added.</p>
<p>With public sector companies sitting on an estimated cash pile of Rs 2.6 lakh crore, leveraging surplus cash would be the best option for them rather than going for disinvestment.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you are having huge cash balance, is it advisable to divest promoter holding or leverage the cash first? If the return on cash balance is not more than bank rate then there is no reason for holding huge cash. The PSUs should take professional views on balance sheets,&#8221; the official said.</p>
<p>Buy-back helps a company to reduce equity by using idle cash and hence provide better returns to the shareholders.</p>
<p>At the end of March 2015, NMDC had a cash and bank balance of Rs 18,443 crore, Coal India had Rs 53,093 crore, NTPC (Rs 13,000 crore), Nalco (Rs 4,628 crore) and MOIL (Rs 2,830 crore). Latest cash balance with OIL is Rs 9,000 crore.</p>
<p>While renaming the Department of Disinvestment as Department of Investment and Public Asset Management (DIPAM) in Budget, Finance Minister <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/tag/arun-jaitley/">Arun Jaitley</a> said it &#8220;will adopt a comprehensive approach for efficient management of the government investment in CPSEs by addressing issues such as capital restructuring, dividend, bonus shares&#8221;.</p>
<p>Post this, DIPAM has helped the exchequer garner Rs 4,500 crore through buy-back of shares by Hindustan Aeronautics Ltd and Bharat Dynamics Ltd in March. While HAL had cash balance of Rs 17,671 crore, BDL&#8217;s stood at Rs 3,669 crore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/economy/govt-wants-psus-to-emulate-private-sector-buy-back-shares/246437/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vedanta unit seeks rollover of $ 1.25 bn loan from Cairn India</title>
		<link>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/vedanta-unit-seeks-rollover-of-1-25-bn-loan-from-cairn-india/246436/</link>
		<comments>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/vedanta-unit-seeks-rollover-of-1-25-bn-loan-from-cairn-india/246436/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 09:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 14:58:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PTI]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cairn India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vedanta]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.financialexpress.com/?p=246436</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Vedanta Group firm THL Zinc Ltd has sought a rollover of a controversial USD 1.25-billion loan taken from the conglomerate's cash-rich oil explorer Cairn India in July 2014.]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<section class="imgsection alignnone"><figure><a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/article/companies/cairn-india-to-merge-into-vedanta-ltd-board-approves-merger/84569/attachment/cairn-india-vedanta-re-l/" rel="attachment wp-att-84577"><img class="size-full wp-image-84577" src="http://images.financialexpress.com/2015/06/cairn-india-vedanta-re-L-e1452695103717.jpg" alt="cairn india" /></a><figcaption><h2></a> The loan had become controversial in 2014 as Cairn India had not disclosed extending of loan to its new parent Group. It came to light only in the analyst call in July 2014 but not before USD 800 million out of the total loan of USD 1.25 billion had already been disbursed. (Reuters)</h2></figcaption></figure><div class="clear"></div>
			</section>
<p>Vedanta Group firm THL Zinc Ltd has sought a rollover of a controversial USD 1.25-billion loan taken from the conglomerate&#8217;s cash-rich oil explorer Cairn India in July 2014.</p>
<p>The loan, which was extended for two years at floating rate of 3 per cent plus LIBOR, was to be repaid by July 2016.</p>
<p>&#8220;CIHL (Cairn India Holdings Ltd), which is a 100 per cent subsidiary of Cairn India, has received a request from THL Zinc for the rollover of the loan and a sub-committee comprising two independent directors have been constituted to review the said rollover request,&#8221; Cairn India CFO Sudhir Mathur said in an investor call, transcript of which was made public on Friday evening.</p>
<p>The loan had become controversial in 2014 as Cairn India had not disclosed extending of loan to its new parent Group. It came to light only in the analyst call in July 2014 but not before USD 800 million out of the total loan of USD 1.25 billion had already been disbursed.</p>
<p>Mathur said the committee of independent directors &#8220;would be going into the details of this rollover request and we will get back to you one way or another what decision of the directors is.&#8221;</p>
<p>In September 2015, London-listed Vedanta Resources Plc, the parent firm of Vedanta, said the USD 1.25-billion loan was used to repay USD 800 million of principal and USD 450 million in interest on another inter-company loan.</p>
<p>In June last year, it proposed merging Cairn India with Vedanta Ltd. If the proposed merger goes through, it could mean that the USD 1.25 billion loan is written off.</p>
<p>When an analyst asked if cash reserves can be lent to the promoters without going to minority shareholders, he said, &#8220;I think there was no law which prevented this loan from being given.&#8221;</p>
<p>Under the new Companies Act, companies need to take shareholder nod for related party transactions.</p>
<p>Mathur said the independent directors committee would seek advice on all these elements.</p>
<p>&#8220;They would be going into details of this extension, this rollover terms to be changed if any. We will get back to you one way or the other,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Mathur, however, did not say Vedanta is seeking rollover for how many years.</p>
<p>Asked if the parent group has sought additional loan, he said, &#8220;There is no request and we do not foresee any request for incremental loan.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cairn had a cash balance of Rs 19,500 crore at the end of March 31, 2016.</p>
<p>In 2014, it had used its cash to buy back shares that helped Vedanta gain greater control of the firm. It bought 36.7 million shares for Rs 1,225 crore and extinguished them, resulting in promoter shareholding rising from 58.76 per cent to 59.90 per cent.</p>
<p>Vedanta group shareholding would have gone up to 64.53 per cent, had Cairn been able to buy all the 170.9 million share it had intended to buy back for up to Rs 5,725 crore. It could not as Cairn share traded higher than Rs 335 offered.</p>
<p>Mathur said, &#8220;All the interest (on the USD 1.25 billion loan) that was to received from THL Zinc has been received.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.financialexpress.com/article/industry/companies/vedanta-unit-seeks-rollover-of-1-25-bn-loan-from-cairn-india/246436/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>