<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss"><channel><title><![CDATA[national]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/news/national]]></link><description><![CDATA[Mid Day]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-us]]></language><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 13:55:06 GMT]]></pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright: (C) 2014 mid-day.com India Limited. All Rights Reserved.]]></copyright><image><title><![CDATA[Mid Day]]></title><url><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/Resources/midday/images/logo.png]]></url><link><![CDATA[http://mid-day.com/]]></link><width><![CDATA[144]]></width><height><![CDATA[28]]></height><description><![CDATA[Visit http://mid-day.com/]]></description></image><item><title><![CDATA[Assam Chief Minister Tarun Gogoi admitted to hospital]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/assam-chief-minister-tarun-gogoi-admitted-to-hospital/17187163]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 13:31:13 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17187163]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/01gogoi-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Assam Chief Minister Tarun Gogoi admitted to hospital]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Assam Chief Minister Tarun Gogoi has been hospitalised after he complained of stomach-related problems</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Guwahati</strong>: Assam Chief Minister Tarun Gogoi has been hospitalised after he complained of stomach-related problems.</p>
<p><img title="Tarun Gogoi" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/01gogoi.jpg" alt="Tarun Gogoi" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>Assam Chief Minister Tarun Gogoi</strong></em></span></p>
<p>According to doctors attending to him at the Gauhati Medical College and Hospital where he was admitted last evening, Gogoi had complained of stomach pain.&nbsp;He is recovering fast, they said. He was having constipation-related issues and his condition was stable now, doctors said.</p>
<p>Although he was fit to go home today, Gogoi will stay tonight at the hospital and undergo some further tests.</p>
<p>Governor P B Acharya visited the hospital during the day to enquire about his health and wished him speedy recovery.</p>
<p>Doctors said the chief minister is likely to be released tomorrow.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Former Maharashtra MLA Harishchandra Patil passes away]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/former-maharashtra-mla-harishchandra-patil-passes-away/17187154]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 12:15:08 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17187154]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Former Maharashtra MLA Harishchandra Patil passes away]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Former Maharashtra MLA Harishchandra Patil passed away today, family members said. 62-year-old Patil, died of cardiac arrest at his residence this morning and is survived by his wife and two sons, they said</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Thane (Maharashtra)</strong>: Former Maharashtra MLA Harishchandra Patil passed away today, family members said. 62-year-old Patil, died of cardiac arrest at his residence this morning and is survived by his wife and two sons, they said.</p>
<p>He was MLA from 1995-2000 in the Maharashtra Assembly. Patil was the Leader of Opposition in Kalyan Dombivili Municipal Corporation (KDMC) and was also mayor of the twin cities.</p>
<p>His funeral, which was held this afternoon, was attended by Kalyan-Dombivili mayor Rajendra Devlekar, KDMC Commissioner E Ravinderan, MP Srikant Shinde and others. A condolence meeting will be held on May 4.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Attempt to marry off minors in mass function foiled in Palghar]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/attempt-to-marry-off-minors-in-mass-function-foiled-in-palghar/17187153]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 12:09:52 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17187153]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Attempt to marry off minors in mass function foiled in Palghar]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>An attempt to get minors married at a mass marriage function was successfully foiled by activists of Shramajivi Sanghatana&nbsp;</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Palghar</strong>: An attempt to get minors married at a mass marriage function was successfully foiled by activists of Shramajivi Sanghatana from Wada here.</p>
<p>The district president of Sanghatana, Ulhas Bhanushali told PTI that it was on Friday a mass marriage was organized by the Dhanghar community members at Kudus of Wada taluka. There were a total of seven couples to get married at the function and they had come from Nashik, Ahmednagar etc, he said.</p>
<p>The activists were informed that of the seven couple two were minors and were not eligible for marriage. The marriage function was fixed at about 6 pm but even before it could take off, the Sanghatana activists accompanied by local police reached the spot.</p>
<p>During verification, it was revealed that Sharad Kolpe (19) was to get married to Ashvini Hake (15) and Datta Madne (20) was to get married to one Sundara Kolpe (14), Bhanushali said.</p>
<p>API Sambaji Bhoir of Wada police station told newsmen that parents of the minors were warned from reiterating the act.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[No fees? No results: Mumbai school withholds marksheets of more than 1,000 students ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/no-fees-no-results-mumbai-school-withholds-marksheets-of-more-than-1000-students/17185188]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 07:46:32 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185188]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1St-Xavier-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[No fees? No results: Mumbai school withholds marksheets of more than 1,000 students ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, parents of over a thousand students from St Xavier's High School in Goregaon gathered in the premises demanding their wards' examination results</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, parents of over a thousand students from St Xavier's High School in Goregaon East gathered in the premises demanding their wards' examination results. The school has allegedly withheld results of these students following a management-versus-parents brawl over a proposed fee hike. A court case over this dispute is pending in the Bombay High Court.</p>
<p><img title="Parents demand the declaration of exam results at St Xavier's School on Saturday " src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1St-Xavier-1.jpg" alt="Parents demand the declaration of exam results at St Xavier's School on Saturday " /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Parents demand the declaration of exam results at St Xavier's School on Saturday </em></strong></span></p>
<p>The results were supposed to be declared during a three-day open house, which concluded yesterday. Some of these parents were given the results verbally, and asked to sign on a register. None received the marksheets.</p>
<p>Two years ago, the school hiked the fees to Rs 1,350 per month across all standards without a nod from the Parent Teacher Association (PTA). Following this, parents moved the Sessions Court which declared the fee hike inappropriate.</p>
<p>Then, the school moved the High Court, where the case is pending. A parent, whose daughter studies in Class III, said, "Since last year, we have been paying R835 &mdash; an amount decided legally after the intervention of government authorities &mdash; as monthly fees. However, this year again, the fees has been hiked to Rs 1,735."</p>
<p>On Friday, Education Minister Prakash Charate issued a notice stating that the school cannot demand increased fees. He said, "Schools have been instructed regarding this and yet we continue to receive complaints."</p>
<p>When mid-day contacted the school, the staff refused to transfer the call to the principal, stating they would revert with a comment. However, there was no response from school authorities later.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Delhi: Diesel, petrol cabs go off Delhi roads, owners warn of suicides]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/delhi-diesel-petrol-cabs-go-off-delhi-roads-owners-warn-of-suicides/17186197]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 07:16:10 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186197]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/jan/odd-even-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Delhi: Diesel, petrol cabs go off Delhi roads, owners warn of suicides]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The Supreme Court's ban on plying of diesel and petrol driven taxis in Delhi took effect on Sunday, with three taxi owners warning this might lead to suicides in frustration</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:&nbsp;</strong>The Supreme Court's ban on plying of diesel and petrol driven taxis in Delhi took effect on Sunday, with three taxi owners warning this might lead to suicides in frustration.</p>
<p>Cab operators termed the apex court's decision tyrannical, saying if the decision was not changed then it will lead many of them to commit suicide. Over 27,000 taxis run on diesel alone in Delhi.</p>
<p>The cab operators told IANS that they had decided to launch a protest after mutual consultations. They claimed that almost half the taxis were run on diesel in the national capital.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/jan/odd-even-m.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="484" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Representational pic</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"I have cancelled 17 bookings since morning as most of my taxis are run on diesel. I have only five taxis run by CNG. We do not understand why the court and Government come up with such decisions?" S. Kumar, owner of Kumar Taxi Services in central Delhi, told IANS.</p>
<p>He said the apex court decision of Saturday will lead many taxi operators to commit suicide as they won't be able to pay their car instalments now.</p>
<p>"How do we pay our monthly instalments to banks for the loans taken to buy taxis? Does not the government realize that diesel cars can't be converted into CNG?"</p>
<p>The Supreme Court on Saturday refused to give more time to taxi operators to switch to the cleaner compressed natural gas (CNG). The deadline for the change, which had been extended twice, was Saturday.</p>
<p>Another transporter, who did not wished to be named, told IANS: "The order would have at least made sense if it was applicable to diesel taxis after their ongoing permit got over. That would have at least given some time to the operators to arrange for alternate taxis. But now we are all ruined."</p>
<p>According to the Delhi transport department, about 60,000 taxis are registered in the city. Of them, 27,000 run on diesel.</p>
<p>Some taxi operators believe the court ruling will mainly affect cab aggregators Ola and Uber.</p>
<p>"The decision is not applicable to taxis with All India Tourist Permit. This is going to be a setback for Ola and Uber who have a large number of taxis run on diesel," Raman of Kamal Taxi Service told IANS.</p>
<p>"The authorities should not be surprised if taxi owners and drivers commit suicide in sheer frustration," Raman added.</p>
<p>Pritpal Singh, a taxi owner in south Delhi, that even taxis with all-India permits often plied within the capital when there was no business for journeys outside. "So even they will be hit. We don't know what to do."</p>
<p>On Sunday, with taxis plying on petrol and diesel staying off the roads, commuters switched over to the limited number of CNG-driven yellow-top taxis and auto-rickshaws. The problem is expected to peak on Monday.</p>
<p>"I called two taxi companies but declined to take my booking citing lack of CNG cabs. Finally I took an auto-rickshaw to reach Noida Sector 15," Sangeeta Johari, a stock broker, told IANS.</p>
<p>Piyush, working with a NGO, told IANS that he waited for two hours to get his taxi booked.</p>
<p>"I was initially told there are no cabs. Later, they said a taxi will be available but in two hours. I had no option and to wait," he said.</p>
<p>This is the second blow to Uber and Ola in Delhi. The Delhi government has declared that it will not let them charge "surge pricing".</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Uttarakhand forest fire: IAF undertakes water sprinkling operations]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/uttarakhand-forest-fire-iaf-undertakes-water-sprinkling-operations/17186196]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 07:02:29 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186196]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/25-Fire-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Uttarakhand forest fire: IAF undertakes water sprinkling operations]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A Mi 17 chopper of the IAF began water sprinkling operations in Nainital today to control raging forest fires which have destroyed 2269 hectares of forested area across Uttarakhand, even as another chopper engaged for the same mission failed to take off due to low visibility</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dehradun:</strong>&nbsp;A Mi 17 chopper of the IAF began water sprinkling operations in Nainital today to control raging forest fires which have destroyed 2269 hectares of forested area across Uttarakhand, even as another chopper engaged for the same mission failed to take off due to low visibility.</p>
<p>The chopper, which has the capacity of carrying 3000 litres of water, is collecting water from Bhimtal lake and making sorties of Almakhan, Kilbari and Nalena areas of the district to douse the fires, Principal Conservator of Forest and nodal officer BP Gupta told PTI.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/25-Fire-1.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="503" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Representational pic</em></strong></span></p>
<p>However, another IAF chopper engaged for the same purpose in Pauri has not been able to take off due to low visibility, Pauri District Magistrate Chandrasekhar Bhatt said. The chopper has collected water from Shrinagar dam but will make a sortie over areas where fires are active only when visibility improves, he said.</p>
<p>However, with the two choppers pressed into service and all security agencies besides locals involved in fire extinguishing operations the situation is likely to be brought under control in a couple of days, the PCF said.</p>
<p>Seven persons have been killed due to forest fires, which have spread to sparsely populated remote hill areas. Pauri, Nainital, Rudraprayag and Tehri are among the worst hit districts, Gupta said but hoped with all agencies activated the situation was bound to improve.</p>
<p><object id="ventuno_player" width="405" height="325" data="http://player.ventunotech.com/vtn_player_2.swf?vID=NzcyMTg5fHwxMjY0fHw0MTd8fDEsMiwx" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://player.ventunotech.com/vtn_player_2.swf?vID=NzcyMTg5fHwxMjY0fHw0MTd8fDEsMiwx" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allownetworking" value="all" /><param name="flashvars" value="muted=false&amp;autoPlay=false" /> </object></p>
<p>Three companies of the NDRF, one of SDRF besides PRD and homeguard personnel are currently engaged in the operations, he said.</p>
<p>With the MeT department predicting a significant fall inday temperatures after May 2, forest fires may get under control after a couple of days, he said but added that the administration will have to remain alert for the next 35 days to prevent fresh forest fire incidents.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kashmiri man reunites with family at Pune mental hospital after 14 years]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/kashmiri-man-reunites-with-family-at-pune-mental-hospital-after-14-years/17185184]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 06:05:17 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185184]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/01pune-reunited-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Kashmiri man reunites with family at Pune mental hospital after 14 years]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>31-year-old Kashimiri man Adil Rashid Khan, missing from home since 2002, has a tearful reunion with parents at the Yerwada mental hospital on Friday</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Thirty one-year-old Adil Rashid Khan could hardly contain his tears when he was reunited with his family after 14 years at the Regional Mental Hospital in Yerwada on Friday.</p>
<p><img title="Adil Rashid Khan (centre) along with parents Rashid, mother Hamida and sister Nusrat at the Regional Mental Hospital in Yerwada" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Adil-Rashid-Khan-1.jpg" alt="Adil Rashid Khan (centre) along with parents Rashid, mother Hamida and sister Nusrat at the Regional Mental Hospital in Yerwada" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Adil Rashid Khan (centre) along with parents Rashid, mother Hamida and sister Nusrat at the Regional Mental Hospital in Yerwada</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Adil, who suffers from schizophrenia, had run away from his home in Srinagar in 2002, while appearing for his Class X examinations. Eight years later, in May 2010, he was found in a poor mental state at the Solapur Railway Station. He was then taken to the Pune mental hospital where he was being treated, until his counsellor Mohan Bansode decided to trace his family.</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon, when Khan's father Rashid Khan (62), mother Hamida (59) and younger sister Nusrat (28) arrived with two police officers from Kashmir, emotions ran high. On seeing his father, Khan broke down. Khan, who was 16 years old when he went missing, was unable to recognise his mother or sister. However, later in the evening, he appeared to be very happy and refused to let go of his parents' hand. The family left for Mumbai on Saturday afternoon, from where they will be leaving for Srinagar.</p>
<p>Adil now hopes to sell fruits in his hometown. "I love different colours. So when I go back and sell fruits. I will give the money I make from this business to my father," he added.&nbsp;Adil's father Rashid, a painter by profession, recalled the anxious time the family went through after his son's disappearance.</p>
<p><img title="Adil, when he was found at the Solapur railway station in 2010" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Adil-Rashid-Khan-2.jpg" alt="Adil, when he was found at the Solapur railway station in 2010" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Adil, when he was found at the Solapur railway station in 2010</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Rashid said, "He was the most loved and pampered at home. When he first went missing, I approached the police who abused and manhandled me, and claimed that my son had joined a terror outfit. After all this stigma, I had completely lost hope of him returning home."</p>
<p>His mother Hamida said she couldn't thank God enough for reuniting her with her son. "Despite people claiming that my son had joined a terror outfit, I knew that he would never do such a thing. My upbringing is really good. I am thankful to Allah for having answered my prayers and giving my son back. He still cannot recognise me, but his memory will come back when I feed him his favourite pulav," said the emotional.</p>
<p>Bansode, who helped bring the family together, said he first met Adil at the hospital. "You need a lot of patience with schizophrenic patients, but I was determined to interact with Adil and get him to speak. While talking to him, I learnt that he was from Batamaloo in Srinagar. With the help of Google, I started searching for colonies and areas in the town, and asked him if he was aware of any of the places I had mentioned. He finally reacted positively when I spoke of the New Colony Society," Bansode said.</p>
<p>The counsellor, with the help of the Maharashtra police, got in touch with the Srinagar control room that finally located Adil's family. In a telephonic conversation with mid-day, Adil's eldest sister Rifat who works for a finance company in Kashmir, said, "God is there. He sent some messengers to help us and bring our brother back to us."</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai Diary: Sunday Dossier]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-diary-sunday-dossier/17186166]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:34:18 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186166]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Aditya-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai Diary: Sunday Dossier]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p><span>The city &mdash; sliced, diced and served with a dash of sauce</span></p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Rawal Junior stands up for the Queen</strong></span><br /><img title="Aditya" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Aditya-1.jpg" alt="Aditya" /><br /><br />Aditya, Paresh Rawal and Swaroop Sampat's younger son, is a busy lad in New York. The 24-year-old is working on the production of his first play, a historical drama titled The Queen, which he wrote last year. "Additionally, a few short films that I wrote or directed are in various stages of production. Also, I am going to graduate in a couple of weeks, so that's keeping me pretty busy," says the student of the Dramatic Writing Graduate Program at Tisch School of the Arts, NYU.</p>
<p>The play is set in 16th century India, at the peak of the Mughal era. The Queen is the story of Durga, who is consigned to the west wing of the palace after her husband, a Rajput king, marries a younger woman. "She battles the loss of power and relevance as she resolves to burn the palace down and avenge her husband's betrayal," says Aditya. The show opens at Theater for the New City, an iconic landmark in the East Village on June 2. Pop by if you're around.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Moving museums</strong></span><br />Today, photographer Dayanita Singh's Museum Bhavan will move out of its temporary home at the Kiran Nadar Museum of Art, New Delhi and rest awhile at Singh's residence.</p>
<p><img title="Dayanita Singh" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Dayanita-Singh-1.jpg" alt="Dayanita Singh" /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Dayanita Singh</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Singh calls her photo-installation a travelling family and says it needs a break from its hectic schedule, especially since in May 2017, the exhibit is slated at the Tokyo Metropolitan Museum of Photography. In the meanwhile, interested folk can check with Singh for an appointment at her home to see the photo-museum.</p>
<p>With mixed feelings, Singh tells us that she hasn't been content with the lack of critical thought surrounding museums. "It is a sad situation with art in the country and everyone realises it," she says.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>And the music never stops...</strong></span><br />The music festival mania doesn't seem to end, and Don't Let Daddy Know is the latest entrant on the scene. If the name isn't enough to entice you, there's Steve Angello, former member of Swedish House Mafia, who will be there to make you scream on May 27 at Mumbai's NSCI.</p>
<p><img title="Steve Angello" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Steve-Angello-1.jpg" alt="Steve Angello" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Steve Angello</em></strong></span></p>
<p>You can also listen to homegrown talent Anish Sood. Why India? "Because we have been watching it, and it's known to be a dance music heaven," says DLDK co-founder Alex Hes.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Real deal of cricket flicker books</strong></span><br />IN 1983, a few months after Kapil Dev's Indian team shocked the world by winning the World Cup, young cricket fans in Mumbai were preoccupied collecting inners of Thums Up bottle tops which had images of Indian and West Indies cricketers.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Thump.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>The more you collected, the more you got in exchange &mdash; miniature Thums Up bottles, mini bats. Probably, the most sought-after among collectibles were the flicker books featuring the batting actions of Kapil Dev (also bowling) apart from Sunil Gavaskar, Sandeep Patil, Viv Richards and Clive Lloyd.</p>
<p>For those who are wondering what the Thums Up flicker books were all about, flicking the pages with your left thumb at one go would show you the batsman completing the full stroke. Flicking the pages slowly would help you watch the stroke in slow motion.</p>
<p>Flicking the pages with your right thumb would show you the cricketer having a swig of the beverage. The 1983 flickers are very hard to find with the most enterprising of antique dealers.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1gary.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Daily Dossier discovered recently that flicker books were also published (by The Bombay Chronicle Press) when the West Indians were here for a Test series in the 1958-59 season. They featured Garfield Sobers (book pictured) and Wesley Hall.</p>
<p>JW McKenzie, the specialist cricket booksellers in United Kingdom, have made them available for &pound;200 and &pound;250 pounds (R19,400 and R24,250). Why is Hall costlier than the legendary Sobers? We don't have an answer to that. What we do know is that cricket flickers books are as rare as they come.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Fighting homophobia on Instagram</strong></span><br />When 23-year-old Shubham Mehrotra started the @50shadesofgay (FSoG) campaign on Instagram in February this year, she claims to have found it difficult to convince the LGBT community about her cause. The photo series aims at telling stories of struggle and acceptance faced by LGBT members in India.</p>
<p><img title="Shubham Mehrotra" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Shubham-Mehrotra-1.jpg" alt="Shubham Mehrotra" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Shubham Mehrotra</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"The government and masses are so indifferent to their rights that they are often forced to become their own spokespersons. And here I was, someone, who wasn't part of their community, trying to reach out to them," says Mehrotra, who worked as a journalist in China and Malaysia, before returning to Mumbai six months ago. They were obviously happy, but slightly wary, she recalls.</p>
<p>Three months on, her campaign is growing from strength to strength. Despite a certain section uncomfortable with making their stories public, Mehrotra and her team of volunteers have managed to gather over 60 narratives &mdash; 15 of them have already been published on the Instagram handle.</p>
<p>This week, FSoG launched a similar page on Facebook. "Some of the stories of abuse and harassment are heart-breaking. Through the campaign, we hope to do our bit to ensure equal human rights for all Indians," says Mehrotra. Here's more hope for humanity.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Provide details of degrees earned by PM Modi to Kejriwal: CIC to Delhi University]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/provide-details-of-degrees-earned-by-pm-modi-to-kejriwal-cic-to-delhi-university/17186163]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:30:55 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186163]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2015/dec/22kejriwal-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Provide details of degrees earned by PM Modi to Kejriwal: CIC to Delhi University]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The Central Information Commission on Saturday directed the Delhi University and the Gujarat University to search and provide information on degrees earned by Prime Minister Narendra Modi to Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> The Central Information Commission on Saturday directed the Delhi University and the Gujarat University to search and provide information on degrees earned by Prime Minister Narendra Modi to Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal, who had criticised the functioning of the transparency panel on Friday.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/27kejriwal.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="447" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Arvind Kejriwal. Pic/PTI</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Information Commissioner Sridhar Acharyulu also directed the Prime Minister's Office to provide "specific number and year" of the degrees earned by the Prime Minister to his alma mater, Delhi University and Gujarat University, to make it easy for them to locate these records.</p>
<p>"Not prescribing the education (degree based) qualification for contesting electoral offices is one of the great features of the Indian democracy. What is needed is education, and not a degree. However, when a citizen holding the position of Chief Ministership wants to know the degree-related information of the Prime Minister, it will be proper to disclose," Acharyulu said in the order.</p>
<p>It was an unusual step by the Information Commissioner to treat Kejriwal's letter as an RTI application. "The Commission directs the CPIOs of Delhi University and Gujarat University to make best possible search for the information regarding degrees in the name of 'Mr Narendra Damodar Modi' in the year 1978 (Graduation in DU) and 1983 (Post Graduation in GU) and provide it to the appellant Mr Kejriwal as soon as possible," he said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nitish questions NDA govt's sincerity over Augusta deal probe]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/nitish-questions-nda-govts-sincerity-over-augusta-deal-probe/17186162]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:25:36 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186162]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Nitish-Kumar-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Nitish questions NDA govt's sincerity over Augusta deal probe]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar on Saturday questioned the seriousness of NDA government in probing the AgustaWestland helicopter deal and said an "impartial" investigation should be held so that the guilty are punished</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Patna:</strong> Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar on Saturday questioned the seriousness of NDA government in probing the AgustaWestland helicopter deal and said an "impartial" investigation should be held so that the guilty are punished.</p>
<p><img title="Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar with DGP PK Thakur in Patna on Saturday. Pic/PTI" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Nitish-Kumar-1.jpg" alt="Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar with DGP PK Thakur in Patna on Saturday. Pic/PTI" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar with DGP PK Thakur in Patna on Saturday. Pic/PTI</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"Why does it taking so long for the inquiry into the deal of AgustaWestland chopper? Why has not the Centre completed the probe yet?" Kumar told reporters while replying to a query on the chopper deal.</p>
<p>"The present government is not serious regarding probe into the chopper deal... they are only looking for excuses to make speeches on the issue," the JD(U) President said, virtually echoing the stand of the Congress which is facing heat in Parliament over the matter.</p>
<p>Earlier, senior BJP leader Sushil Kumar Modi had questioned Kumar's "silence" over the chopper deal in which Congress chief Sonia Gandhi is under attack from the ruling party. The UPA government had said that the deal was cancelled when allegation of irregularities came into the picture.</p><br/>Shah trying to create smokescreen: Cong<br/><p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> The Congress on Saturday trashed BJP chief Amit Shah's charges against Sonia Gandhi and party leaders on AgustaWestland deal, terming them as "deliberate lies", and demanded that he apologise for his "politics of deceit" and attempts to create a smokescreen to "befool the people".</p>
<p>The AICC also asked Prime Minister Narendra Modi to tell what connection, if any, his government has with former Air Force Chief SP Tyagi, an accused in the chopper deal case.</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Driving licenses to say if driver is organ donor ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/driving-licenses-to-say-if-driver-is-organ-donor/17186160]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:23:35 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186160]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Driving licenses to say if driver is organ donor ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>In a humanitarian move, the Centre is all set to introduce a mechanism so that when a driving license is issued, it will have an option earmarked if the driver desires to donate his organs in case of a fatality</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> In a humanitarian move, the Centre is all set to introduce a mechanism so that when a driving license is issued, it will have an option earmarked if the driver desires to donate his organs in case of a fatality.</p>
<p>The Road Transport and Highways Ministry are in the process of giving final touches to having the provisions of pledge in the driving licence issued to any individual. The smart card-based driving licences will have a chip with all the information stored.</p>
<p>The driver will have to mention whether he permits the concerned authorities to extricate the organ from the deceased, which can either be preserved or transplanted immediately.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[West Bengal Assembly polls: 78% turn up to vote, 15 injured in poll violence]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/west-bengal-assembly-polls-78-turn-up-to-vote-15-injured-in-poll-violence/17186159]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:18:38 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186159]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Young-girls-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[West Bengal Assembly polls: 78% turn up to vote, 15 injured in poll violence]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A heavy turnout of over 78 per cent was registered on Saturday in the fifth and penultimate phase of assembly polls in West Bengal, which saw sporadic incidents of violence that left seven people injured</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kolkata:</strong> A heavy turnout of over 78 per cent was registered on Saturday in the fifth and penultimate phase of assembly polls in West Bengal, which saw sporadic incidents of violence that left seven people injured.</p>
<p><img title="Young girls take a selfie after casting their votes at a polling station during the fifth phase of West Bengal Assembly elections in Kolkata on Saturday. Pic/PTI " src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Young-girls-1.jpg" alt="Young girls take a selfie after casting their votes at a polling station during the fifth phase of West Bengal Assembly elections in Kolkata on Saturday. Pic/PTI " /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Young girls take a selfie after casting their votes at a polling station during the fifth phase of West Bengal Assembly elections in Kolkata on Saturday. Pic/PTI </em></strong></span></p>
<p>Voter turnout of 78.98 per cent was recorded from Hooghly district, 79.69 per cent in South 24 Parganas while Kolkata South the lowest turnout of 63.10 per cent.</p>
<p>In South 24 Parganas, six persons were injured in poll violence while one injury was reported from Hooghly. Four RSP workers were injured in a clash with TMC supporters at a booth at Bhangonkhali village in Basanti constituency after TMC activists allegedly prevented them from casting votes, a police officer said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in Rashbehari assembly constituency of south Kolkata, Riya Sarkar became the first transgender presiding officer of a booth in South City International School. A number of heavyweights including Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee are in the fray in this phase. Altogether 349 candidates, including 43 women, are trying their luck in Saturday's election across three districts.</p>
<p>Senior Trinamool Congress ministers also accused central paramilitary forces of misbehaving with voters "in the name of maintaining law and order" and expressed confidence in winning the ongoing Assembly polls in Bengal. "The Central Paramilitary Forces are frisking people without any reason, browbeating voters. We condemn this. But irrespective of such intimidation, we will win the polls," senior TMC leader and state Panchayat Minister Subrata Mukherjee said.</p><br/>Thrash the CPI-M agent, says TMC's Sonali Guha<br/><p>Temperamental Trinamool Congress candidate and deputy speaker of the West Bengal Assembly Sonali Guha on Saturday landed in a controversy after she was seen giving instructions over phone to "thrash the CPI-M agent". Taking cognisance of the remarks, the Election Commission (EC) ordered a first information report (FIR) against Guha, who is defending her Satgachhia assembly constituency.</p>
<p><strong>TMC leader called Kolkata 'mini Pak': BJP</strong><br />The BJP has alleged that a state minister and Trinamool Congress leader Firhad Hakim has described a part of Kolkata port area as "mini Pakistan" in an interview to Pakistan daily Dawn and demanded an explanation, even as Hakim denied having made such comment. "How can a minister say such things? We demand an explanation from both Firhad Hakim and Mamata Banerjee," BJP national secretary Siddharth Nath Singh said.</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Major block between Saphale-Vaitarna today]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/major-block-between-saphalevaitarna-today/17186155]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 03:06:03 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17186155]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Major block between Saphale-Vaitarna today]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A major block for launching of main girder and de-launching of existing girder work on North span of Bridge No 92 will be taken today for over hours from 7:00 am to 5:15 pm on UP Line between Saphale and Vaitarna stations</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>A major block for launching of main girder and de-launching of existing girder work on North span of Bridge No 92 will be taken today for over hours from 7:00 am to 5:15 pm on UP Line between Saphale and Vaitarna stations.&nbsp;Due to this block some passenger trains will be cancelled / partially cancelled / regulated during this block period, details of which are as under:</p>
<p><strong>Trains cancelled:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Suburban Trains</strong><br />Train No. 93001 Virar - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93002 Dahanu Road - Borivali local<br />Train No. 93003 Virar - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93004 Dahanu Road &ndash;Churchgate local<br />Train No. 93005 Churchgate - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93006 Dahanu Road - Borivali local<br />Train No. 93007 Borivali - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93008 Dahanu Road - Virar local<br />Train No. 93009 Borivali - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93010 Dahanu Road &ndash;Churchgate local<br />Train No. 93011 Churchgate - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93012 Dahanu Road- Virar local<br />Train No. 93013 Virar - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93014 Dahanu Road &ndash; Dadar local<br />Train No. 93015 Virar - Dahanu Road local<br />Train No. 93016 Dahanu Road &ndash;Churchgate local</p>
<p><strong>Memu/Demu Trains</strong><br />Train No. 69145 Dadar - Dahanu Road MEMU<br />Train No. 69147 Virar - Dahanu Road MEMU<br />Train No. 69148 Dahanu Road- Virar MEMU<br />Train No. 69149 Virar - Dahanu Road MEMU<br />Train No. 69150 Dahanu Road- Virar MEMU<br />Train No. 69155 Virar - Dahanu Road MEMU<br />Train No. 69156 Dahanu Road- Virar MEMU<br />Train No. 69158 Dahanu Road- Virar MEMU<br />Train No. 69159 Virar - Dahanu Road MEMU<br />Train No. 69160 Dahanu Road &ndash; Dadar MEMU<br />Train No. 71088 Boisar- Vasai Road DEMU</p>
<p><strong>Passenger/ Express Trains</strong><br />Train No. 59023 Mumbai Central- Valsad Fast Passenger<br />Train No. 59024 Valsad- Mumbai Central Fast Passenger<br />Train No. 59039 Virar- Valsad Passenger<br />Train No. 59044 Dahanu Road - Virar Passenger<br />Train No. 59046 Valsad- Bandra (T) Passenger<br />Train No. 12935 Bandra (T)- Surat Intercity Express<br />Train No. 12936 Surat- Bandra (T) Intercity Express<br />Train No. 12921 Mumbai Central - Surat Flying Ranee Express<br />Train No. 12922 Surat - Mumbai Central Flying Ranee Express</p>
<p><strong>Trains regulated</strong></p>
<p><strong>Down Direction trains:-</strong><br />Train No. 12925 Bandra (T)- Amritsar Paschim Express will be regulated for about 3 hrs &amp; 25 minutes<br />Train No. 12216 Bandra (T)- Delhi Sarai Rohilla Garibrath Express will be regulated for about 2 hr. and 45 minutes.<br />Train No. 14708 Bandra (T)- Bikaner Ranakpur Express will be regulated for about 25 minutes<br />Train No. 22913 Mumbai Central- New Delhi AC Express will be regulated for 05 minutes<br />Train No 22476 Coimbatore &ndash; Bikaner AC Express will be regulated for about 1 hr and 10 minutes.<br />Train No. 93017 Churchgate- Dahanu Road EMU will be regulated for about 15 minutes.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sea horses, sea snakes to woo summer visitors at Taraporewala Aquarium]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/sea-horses-sea-snakes-to-woo-summer-visitors-at-taraporewala-aquarium/17185192]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 02:50:05 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185192]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/01sea-horse-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Sea horses, sea snakes to woo summer visitors at Taraporewala Aquarium]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Charni Road's Taraporewala Aquarium has been seeing schools and families in large numbers since the summer vacation began. And nothing's better than treating eager visitors with seven estuary sea horses (of species Hippocampus Kuda) and five sea snakes as new attractions</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Charni Road's Taraporewala Aquarium has been seeing schools and families in large numbers since the summer vacation began. And nothing's better than treating eager visitors with seven estuary sea horses (of species Hippocampus Kuda) and five sea snakes as new attractions. However, the aquarium's promise, made last year, of online booking has still not taken off.</p>
<p><img title="Curious visitors take in the sight of a sea snake, part of the new additions at the Taraporewala Aquarium" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Taraporewala-Aquarium-1.jpg" alt="Curious visitors take in the sight of a sea snake, part of the new additions at the Taraporewala Aquarium" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Curious visitors take in the sight of a sea snake, part of the new additions at the Taraporewala Aquarium</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"It's been two years since the aquarium was inaugurated and people get bored of seeing the same things. That's why we decided to procure something new," said Fisheries Commissioner Madhukar Gaikwad, in-charge of this aquarium. All the creatures are adults, and special water tanks have been created to accommodate these long sea snakes.</p>
<p>The new marine additions were brought in phases from Ratnagiri last week and kept in quarantine. Now, save for four sea horses still in quarantine, others have been kept on display.</p>
<p><img title="An estuary sea horse at the aquarium. Pics/ Sayyed Sameer Abedi" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1sea-horse-1.jpg" alt="An estuary sea horse at the aquarium. Pics/ Sayyed Sameer Abedi" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>An estuary sea horse at the aquarium. Pics/ Sayyed Sameer Abedi</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"Since these animals come from their natural habitat, they are not used to crowds, lights or noise. Sudden exposure might lead to mortality. That is why we keep them in quarantine to acclimatise them," said curator Ajinkya Patil.</p>
<p><strong>No e-bookings</strong><br />The authorities had declared last year that people would be able to book aquarium tickets online but have failed to deliver yet. The reason for the delay, they said, is that the MTDC is&nbsp;planning a tourism package for Mumbai.</p>
<p>"This aquarium will feature in the list of various tourist attractions. So, people will be able to book the entire tour online. The MTDC is going to develop the website and the booking facility," an official stated.</p><br/>History<br/><p>The Taraporewala Aquarium is one of the largest in the country. Built in 1951, the aquarium was shut for two years for renovation in 2013. It was renovated for a cost of Rs 22 crore and re-inaugurated in 2015 by the state chief minister. It has over 400 species of salt water and fresh water fish.</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Charity in the time of tragedy]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/charity-in-the-time-of-tragedy/17185190]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 01:50:18 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185190]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Khadya-Peye-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Charity in the time of tragedy]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Despite cost to restore stalls gutted in fire at Juhu beach, owners raise Rs 10 lakh for drought relief</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Rising above the tragedy of a fire that gutted several food stalls at Juhu Chowpatty and caused insurmountable damage to property, 80 stall owners on Friday came forward to give financial assistance to drought-hit villages in Maharashtra. After pooling their resources, the stall owners handed over a cheque of Rs 10 lakh to state chief minister Devendra Fadnavis.</p>
<p><img title="Members of the Khadya Peye Vikrete Coop Society Ltd, the apex body of the Juhu Chowpatty food court" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Khadya-Peye-1.jpg" alt="Members of the Khadya Peye Vikrete Coop Society Ltd, the apex body of the Juhu Chowpatty food court" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Members of the Khadya Peye Vikrete Coop Society Ltd, the apex body of the Juhu Chowpatty food court</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Their donation comes in the wake of the drought that has gripped the state. According to reports, the total number of farmer suicides in the drought-affected Marathwada region this year is estimated to be around 338.</p>
<p>C Arunachalam, chairman of Khadya Peye Vikrete Coop Society Ltd &mdash; the apex body of the food court &mdash; said that the initial plan was to raise Rs20 lakh. "We were in the process of collecting funds, when there was a fire on April 22, which resulted from a short circuit. Seventeen stalls were gutted, while three were partially burnt," Arunachalam said. The food court, which is on the northern end of the main Juhu beach, has 80 stalls.</p>
<p><img title="Workers reconstruct food stalls gutted in the April 22 fire " src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Workers-1.jpg" alt="Workers reconstruct food stalls gutted in the April 22 fire " /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Workers reconstruct food stalls gutted in the April 22 fire </em></strong></span></p>
<p>After rough estimates, it was found that the cost of building each stall would be around R6 lakh. "We had no choice, but to divert the funds set aside for drought-relief, for rebuilding the stalls," he added.</p>
<p>Ramchandra Kadam, secretary of the food court operations, said the decision to donate the money came from stall owners and workers, who hail from different parts of India and earn their living by selling food on the beach. Meanwhile, the stall owners have also decided to ration the amount of water they use on a daily basis. Committee member Ganesh Thevar said, "We have now instructed each of them to use just one bucket of water to mop the floor."</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Microbiology students create trim almond truffle  ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-microbiology-students-create-trim-almond-truffle/17185187]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 01:39:17 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185187]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Samidha-Pawaskar-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Microbiology students create trim almond truffle  ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Five-star expresses interest nutritional avatar of rich eats that Somaiya College students have created at the end of four years of research</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine biting into your favourite almond truffle and knowing you are offering your body much needed nutrition. Students of Microbiology (MSc I and II) at KJ Somaiya College of Science and Commerce in Vidyavihar have spent the last four years researching how they can make popular rich eats, healthy, in an ongoing project titled Functional Food Project.</p>
<p><img title="Samidha Pawaskar, HOD, Biochemistry (left) and her students have researched the Functional Food Project for four years" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Samidha-Pawaskar-1.jpg" alt="Samidha Pawaskar, HOD, Biochemistry (left) and her students have researched the Functional Food Project for four years" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Samidha Pawaskar, HOD, Biochemistry (left) and her students have researched the Functional Food Project for four years</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The idea carries enough business potential for Vakola-based five-star Grand Hyatt to have expressed interest in stocking gluten-free yogurt and thandai on their regular menu. Their challenge was made tougher by the fact that they could use only natural products. Every batch since 2012 took the project one step ahead through laboratory tests and resulting observations.</p>
<p>This year, the project has finally yielded results and the product line includes almond truffle, multigrain dosa, paan booster thandai, sugar-free fruit jellies and chocolates, all to be made available for an sale at an upcoming store on campus and their college canteen.</p>
<p>"Since we became an autonomous institution in 2013, we have focused on application-based education. The project challenged the students, batch after batch, to come up with functional ready-to-cook packet food and ready-to-eat dishes," says Samidha Pawaskar, HOD, Biochemistry.</p>
<p><img title="Vegetable roll" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1roll-1.jpg" alt="Vegetable roll" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Vegetable roll</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The students started by studying the resistance starch value of grains and stability of ingredients. Pawaskar says while theories are mastered in the classroom, it's the lab that allows for a testing ground.</p>
<p>The group has identified three categories of food eaters &mdash; working professionals, kids and seniors "We have not compromised on taste," Pawaskar assures, adding that the group is happy to take small orders too (foodprojects@somaiya.edu).</p>
<p>Sara Mukkadam, 21, was on the team that worked on the Masala Paan Booster. "For this thandai, we extracted juice from paan leaves, and added sabja (basil seeds), ice cream for energy, along with dry fruits high in Omega 3 fatty acids," she shares.</p>
<p>The menu also has something for lactose- and gluten-intolerant consumers. "We are making non-dairy yoghurt too made with live culture. One variety is made using pomegranate and strawberry, both good for the heart and great anti-oxidants," says Pawaskar.</p>
<p>The ready-to-cook dosa mix is made of multi-grains like soya bean, wheat, barley and moong. "We sprouted them and used their nutritional water. It's a great source of carbohydrate for diabetics," says student Sanjeevani More.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Six die as 90-year-old building in Kamathipura collapses]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-six-die-as-90yearold-building-in-kamathipura-collapses/17185186]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 01:26:59 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185186]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Kamathipura-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Six die as 90-year-old building in Kamathipura collapses]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Workers were renovating the three-storey structure when the mishap occurred; MHADA and BMC to launch independent inquiries into whether the design of the building led to the cave-in</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Najirul Shaikh owes his life to an extended lunch break. The 22-year-old construction labourer was with two friends &mdash; Minarul Shaikh (21) and Sambo Shaikh (26) &mdash; chewing paan at a three-storey building in Kamathipura they were renovating, when the structure collapsed on Saturday afternoon, killing six persons.<br /><br /><span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>&nbsp;Three days go</strong></span><img title="Full-fledged repairs were on at the building on 14th Street, Kamathipura, just three days ago. Pic/MehtabA Quereshi" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Kamathipura-1.jpg" alt="Full-fledged repairs were on at the building on 14th Street, Kamathipura, just three days ago. Pic/MehtabA Quereshi" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Full-fledged repairs were on at the building on 14th Street, Kamathipura, just three days ago. Pic/MehtabA Quereshi</em></strong></span></p>
<p>"There were eight of us in the building. We had lunch around 1 pm and half an hour later, three of us came down to have paan. We had to get back to work at 2 pm," recalled Najirul.</p>
<p>Najirul and Minarul sat at a paan shop on the ground floor, while Sambo went a little farther away. Within minutes, their chatter was broken by a rumble and a loud crash. "The building completely collapsed," said Najirul. Six persons &mdash; the five workers inside the building and paan shop owner Angad Chaube &mdash; were trapped in the rubble. All of the workers were migrants from Murshidabad, West Bengal.</p>
<p>Rescue personnel pulled out some workers and rushed them to the hospital. Five of the injured were admitted to JJ Hospital, four of whom Jabaaz Mulla (30), Sarfulla Mulla (28), Angad Chaube (45), Wasim Bisman Mullakhan (14), who had stopped by to meet two of his uncles inside the building - were later declared dead. Three others were rushed to Nair Hospital. Two of them, an unidentified man and woman, were declared brought dead. The third, Mohammad Zakeri (50), is undergoing treatment.</p>
<p><strong>Faulty design?</strong><br />The 90-year-old structure next to the Pattharwali building in Kamathipura's lane number 14, which was being repaired, had been on thin ice from the beginning. Locals alleged that it had a faulty design.<br /><br /><span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>&nbsp;Saturday</strong></span> <img title="Rescue operations at the mishap site went on for hours. Pics/Ajinkya Sawant" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Kamathipura-2.jpg" alt="Rescue operations at the mishap site went on for hours. Pics/Ajinkya Sawant" /></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Rescue operations at the mishap site went on for hours. Pics/Ajinkya Sawant</em></span></strong></p>
<p>According to Mehtab, a resident of 14th Street, the steel angles and beams required for the construction were brought in just Friday morning. "Besides, the building was supposed to be restricted to two-storeys. I don't know how an additional floor came up," he alleged. The structure was a cessed building. A number of shops functioned out of the ground floor. Erstwhile tenants also ran some manufacturing units there.</p>
<p>MHADA authorities refuted the locals' allegation. Engineers from its repair and reconstruction board said the original building plan was for a ground-plus-three-storey structure. "We will carry out an inquiry into the matter to determine the cause of the mishap. I have already directed the deputy chief engineer to do so and submit a report within three days," said Sumant Bhange, chief officer of the board.</p>
<p>Bhange said the board carries out structural audits between March and June every year. "The building was not declared dilapidated last year. Otherwise, we would have demolished it. Neither was there a demand from tenants for redevelopment. But there were demands for repairs. Even local politicians supported it. That it why we planned these repairs," Bhange said.</p>
<p>The architect prepares the final renovation plans and his role in the mishap, too, will be probed. The repairs had begun on April 7, and the waterproofing and plastering work on April 28.&nbsp;The BMC's building construction department will also conduct an independent inquiry into the mishap.</p>
<p>MHADA has declared a compensation of Rs 5 lakh for the kin of the deceased and Rs 50,000 for the injured. Nagpada police have registered an accidental death case. "Once there is clarity on whether was any negligence on part of the authorities concerned, we will register a case under the relevant sections," said Dhananjay Kulkarni, deputy commissioner of police and PRO, Mumbai police.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Right to pray: mid-day tours Muslim places of worship in Mumbai with a direct connect to women]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/right-to-pray-midday-tours-muslim-places-of-worship-in-mumbai-with-a-direct-connect-to-women/17185183]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 01:04:45 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185183]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/Ma-Haji-Ani-Dargah-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Right to pray: mid-day tours Muslim places of worship in Mumbai with a direct connect to women]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>While Haji Ali simmers over equal praying rights, women quietly nurture their alliance with other dargahs, some tailored to rid their woes</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>A surprise greets you when you walk up a steep, not-very-wide flight of stairs to the Ma Haji Ani Dargah. Across a carpeted terrace is the entry to the dargah, through which both men and women can enter.</p>
<p><img title="At the Ma Haji Ani Dargah, built in 1908 by Haji Ismail Hasham, women and men share equal rights. Pics/Sayyed Sameer Abedi" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Haji-Ismail-Hasham-1.jpg" alt="At the Ma Haji Ani Dargah, built in 1908 by Haji Ismail Hasham, women and men share equal rights. Pics/Sayyed Sameer Abedi" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>At the Ma Haji Ani Dargah, built in 1908 by Haji Ismail Hasham, women and men share equal rights. Pics/Sayyed Sameer Abedi</em></strong></span></p>
<p>This is the mausoleum of a woman very dear to Khwaja Haji Ali, whose famed and now controversial tomb sits across the sea from this one on Worli Seaface. The caretaker Zahir Shail says some legends say it belongs to his mother, others believe it is his sister. He isn't sure which and asks us to "check the Internet".</p>
<p>What Shail does share is that, unlike the more famous dargah, this one is an equal space shared by men and women. Inside, there are no barricades that prevent either gender from touching the mazhar.</p>
<p>"It's a woman's mazhar so there's no question of not allowing women," says Shail. Built in 1908 as a token of devotion by Haji Ismail Hasham, whose family-owned Sir Yusuf Mohammed Trust now runs it, sees approximately 250 devotees every day, which rises to 500 during Thursdays, Fridays and Sundays.</p>
<p><img title="All are allowed to touch the mazhar, says its caretaker Zahir Shai" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Ma-Haji-Ani-Dargah.jpg" alt="All are allowed to touch the mazhar, says its caretaker Zahir Shai" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>All are allowed to touch the mazhar, says its caretaker Zahir Shai</em></strong></span></p>
<p>At Haji Ali, the average daily rush is an estimated 10,000 to 15,000 thousand, which doubles during Thursdays, Fridays and Sundays. The numbers, are in fact, one of the reasons that Haji Ali trustees have used to support the restriction of women in the sanctum sanctorum, now a subject of raging debate.</p>
<p>On Thursday, rights activist Trupti Desai of the Bhumata Brigade tried to enter the dargah after successfully campaigning for entry of women to the Shani Shingnapur temple in Maharashtra last month. But the chaos between pro and anti groups foiled her attempt to enter.</p>
<p>In 2011, Haji Ali's trustees restricted women's entry into the sanctum sanctorum &mdash; a move which was challenged in the Bombay High Court. Historical rights to graves The trustees had earlier told the court that entry of women in close proximity to the grave of a male Muslim saint is considered a grievous sin in Islam.</p>
<p><img title="Reay Road's Mira Datar Dargah is said to be the baithak of Hazrat Sayid Ali Mira Datar, whose dargah at Unnava in Gujarat is far more famous. Devotees often come and spend the day here, getting food from the benevolent" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Mira-Datar-Dargah-1.jpg" alt="Reay Road's Mira Datar Dargah is said to be the baithak of Hazrat Sayid Ali Mira Datar, whose dargah at Unnava in Gujarat is far more famous. Devotees often come and spend the day here, getting food from the benevolent" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Reay Road's Mira Datar Dargah is said to be the baithak of Hazrat Sayid Ali Mira Datar, whose dargah at Unnava in Gujarat is far more famous. Devotees often come and spend the day here, getting food from the benevolent</em></strong></span></p>
<p>It's a claim that Dr Zeenat Shaukat Ali, former professor of Islamic Studies at St Xavier's College and currently Director of the Wisdom Foundation (a global secular, democratic peace initiative), says, is misguided. The Quran mentions the Prophet's daughter Fatema as visiting her granduncle's grave once a week, says Shaukat Ali. The Prophet's grave too, adds Ali, was built in his home which he shared with his wife Ayesha. "So, during her life, Ayesha was living next to the grave."</p>
<p>In fact, in other parts of the world, certain mosques too are open to women, says Delhi-based writer Sadia Dehlvi, who is author of the 2012 title, The Sufi Courtyard: Dargahs of Delhi. "It is not mandatory for women to go to the mosque and thank God for that &mdash; will they run their homes or run to the mosque?" Most mosques outside India, she adds, have separate chambers for women to pray and a separate entrance too. In the subcontinent, it hasn't been a tradition, but there is no bar against women.</p>
<p><img title="A woman in trance at the Hussain Tekri Imamwada. Its caretaker Rizvi says there's nothing to be afraid of as those &quot;who bear goodwill will come to no harm&quot;" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Hussain-Tekri-1.jpg" alt="A woman in trance at the Hussain Tekri Imamwada. Its caretaker Rizvi says there's nothing to be afraid of as those &quot;who bear goodwill will come to no harm&quot;" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>A woman in trance at the Hussain Tekri Imamwada. Its caretaker Rizvi says there's nothing to be afraid of as those "who bear goodwill will come to no harm"</em></strong></span></p>
<p><strong>A sisterhood of strangers</strong><br />Elsewhere in Mumbai, when one asks about dargahs frequented by women besides Ma Haji Ani &mdash; where a stand stacked with bangles represents prayers for marriage and children &mdash; among the first names to be shared is the Mira Datar Dargah.</p>
<p>In a crowded lane at Reay Road, lined with dhoop and dhaga sellers, the over 300-year-old dargah is a legend unto itself with stories of faith healing. It's more of a baithak and doesn't have a grave, and in many senses is a 'branch' of the more famed Hazrat Sayid Ali Mira Datar Dargah at Unnava in Gujarat.</p>
<p><img title="Sayyed Saleem Rizvi, the current caretaker of the Hussain Tekri Imamwada, near Vakola masjid, says the imamwada has been in the family home forever. It was made accessible to the public 30 years ago. He admits he sees more women than men" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Sayyed-Saleem-Rizvi-1.jpg" alt="Sayyed Saleem Rizvi, the current caretaker of the Hussain Tekri Imamwada, near Vakola masjid, says the imamwada has been in the family home forever. It was made accessible to the public 30 years ago. He admits he sees more women than men" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Sayyed Saleem Rizvi, the current caretaker of the Hussain Tekri Imamwada, near Vakola masjid, says the imamwada has been in the family home forever. It was made accessible to the public 30 years ago. He admits he sees more women than men</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Dehlvi's words come true here. She says that within Islamic society, dargahs hold a unique position as they have developed as a participatory space for men, women and children across all faiths and classes. Mosques, meant strictly for prayer, are not places one can sit around in.</p>
<p>As you enter the dargah, there is a division of spaces for men and women to sit. We sit down to speak to the women and within minutes, a sisterhood builds.</p>
<p>Shaheen Qureshi, a regular for 35 years, guides us to Anusuya Siddhu Malusare, who estimates her age to be 80. She started coming to the dargah, famed for the daily loban and nagada which help the affected get rid of evil spirits, to cure her of the pain in her limbs.</p>
<p><img title="In 2011, Haji Ali's trustees restricted women&rsquo;s entry into the sanctum sanctorum - a move which was challenged in the Bombay High Court" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Haji-Ali-1.jpg" alt="In 2011, Haji Ali's trustees restricted women&rsquo;s entry into the sanctum sanctorum - a move which was challenged in the Bombay High Court" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>In 2011, Haji Ali's trustees restricted women&rsquo;s entry into the sanctum sanctorum - a move which was challenged in the Bombay High Court</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Visits to doctors, she insists, don't help. "The tests don't show anything," pitches in Radha, a young Dombivli resident sitting near us. She suffered from regular bouts of unconsciousness which, she says, remained undiagnosed for most of her life. Believing that it was the work of an evil spirit, Radha started coming to the dargah and felt better after regular hajiris (when in the presence of the baba, the evil spirit is made to appear). Mira Datar Baba whose dargah it is, chime in the three women, "daant ke neeche se shaitan ko chabaate hain".</p>
<p>Here, as in Haji Ali, women are not allowed into the sanctum sanctorum. The rest of the dargah is open to all. But, ask anyone and they will say it is women who are affected more.</p>
<p><strong>Family that takes care</strong><br />Sayyed Saleem Rizvi, the current caretaker of the Hussain Tekri Imamwada, near Vakola masjid, proffers a reason: "Often, the spirits affect the house, which women have a direct connect with. Also, women are likely to come in the presence of the Lord more easily than men, who may have to go to work."</p>
<p>As we sit on a Thursday morning in front of the imamwada at Rizvi's home, a woman standing next to us is in a state of trance. "Nahin sataaoonga&hellip; itni taaqat naahin hai," she utters on repeat, obviously taking on the male gender. Rizvi is unfazed. "There's nothing to be scared of. This is God's place. No harm will come to those who bear goodwill," he says.</p>
<p>His family has been living in the house since before Independence. "We have had the imamwada &mdash; essentially a private praying space &mdash; forever. However, it was not always open to public. Our family would visit the Hussain tekri at Ratlam in Madhya Pradesh on an annual visit. Once, during loban there, it came to our mind that we should open it to everyone," he says. That was around 30 years ago. Miracles started occurring almost immediately.</p>
<p>Ramesh Patel, a Vakola resident, who also pitches in with the caretaking of the imamwada, says when he came here the first time, three cloves ejected out of his foot; the sign of an evil presence. The woman in trance beats her head on the floor and sometimes, stops to slaps herself. She doesn't mind us interrupting her routine when we ask her name. "Reena," she smiles.&nbsp;Many women, tired from the hajiri, sit or sprawl in the open area outside the home. "They leave by night. The family needs some time off, after all," says Patel.</p>
<p><strong>Common restrictions</strong><br />Here, like elsewhere, it's advised that women stay away during their menstruation cycle. But the restriction, says Ali, is not only for women. "Islam lays great stress on hygiene. So, anytime there's any emission from the body, you are required to clean yourself and then go for prayers." Both Dehlvi and Ali stress that there are certain spaces where women are allowed and men aren't. One example is the Khwaja Qutub Dargah in Delhi.</p>
<p>Here, in the inside chamber, women are not allowed. However, inside the complex lies a smaller dargah of Khwaja Qutbuddin Bakhtiar Kaki's wife and wet nurse, called the Dai Sahiba Dargah, where men are not allowed. Gender politics is not restricted to only women, it seems. Equality might be an aim for both Desai and Haji Ali Trustees.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kangana Ranaut gives statement, but at home; refuses to part with laptop  ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/kangana-ranaut-gives-statement-but-at-home-refuses-to-part-with-laptop/17185180]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 00:56:04 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185180]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Kangana-Ranaut-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Kangana Ranaut gives statement, but at home; refuses to part with laptop  ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Officers from the BKC's cyber police station record actress'&nbsp;statement; say surrendering of gadgets would have helped them in tracing person alleged to be impersonating actor Hrithik Roshan</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Officers from Bandra Kurla Complex's cyber police station, who arrived at the Khar West house of actor Kangana Ranaut to take her statement in an investigation into a case of someone impersonating actor Hrithik Roshan, were disappointed when Ranaut refused to hand them her laptop and iPad.</p>
<p><img title="Kangana Ranaut" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Kangana-Ranaut-1.jpg" alt="Kangana Ranaut" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Kangana Ranaut</em></strong></span></p>
<p>This, the officers were hoping, would help them help them crack the case.&nbsp;In February, Roshan's legal team had sent a notice to Ranaut demanding an 'unconditional apology' for a 'defaming' remark in an interview where she allegedly referred to him as her 'silly ex'.</p>
<p>That triggered off a war between the two with a counter-notice being filed by Ranaut and further allegations and counter-allegations being leaked every other day. In the interim, Roshan also filed an FIR at the cyber police station against an unidentified person for impersonating him and chatting with Ranaut as him. Ranaut, who was named in this FIR, said she would give her statement to the cops on April 30. The actor's sister Rangoli also gave her statement.</p>
<p>According to sources, Ranaut said that all allegations made by Roshan are false and that his team (she hasn't specified who) have hacked into her account and tampered with the mails. The sources weren't clear about whether her email ID had been hacked into to delete or send the emails. The alleged impersonation came to light at filmmaker Karan Johar's party, when the two actors bumped into each other.</p>
<p><strong>Chasing Kangana<br /></strong>On Saturday, there was heavy media presence outside the Khar West building where Ranaut lives. Earlier, it was believed that she would go to the cyber police station to give her statement. Around 1 pm, Ranaut left, only for the media to realise that it was for the gym. She returned in an hour.</p>
<p><img title="A cyber cell officer visited Kangana Ranaut's Khar residence (below)" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1cyber-cell-1.jpg" alt="A cyber cell officer visited Kangana Ranaut's Khar residence (below)" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>A cyber cell officer visited Kangana Ranaut's Khar residence (below)</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The cops arrived at 4.45 pm. Ranaut's advocate was present at the meeting with senior inspector Kalpana Gadekar. At the meeting, which lasted for over three hours, sources said Ranaut denied allegations of stalking Roshan and talking to the alleged imposter.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1cyber-cell-2.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Aside from her laptop and iPad, the cops asked for Ranaut's iPhone, from which she allegedly sent the emails to Hrithik. The actor said the phone had fallen in water after which she threw it away.</p>
<p>A police source said, "We asked Ranaut and her legal team for the digital equipment to better trace the sender of the emails, but she did not give us anything." Kangana's advocate Rizwan Siddiqui said in a statement, "The police were happy to get more information from my clients and learn about things that were not mentioned by the complainant in his FIR."</p>
<p>A police source said accessing Kangana's email account and then checking the details of the emails sent by the imposter is what investigators are looking for. "From the header of the imposter's emails, investigators can find out the IP address of the imposter. And through that, the imposter can be identified within a few days," another police officer said. But the case could hit a dead end if the imposter had used proxy servers, said another source.</p>
<p>However, an officer said Ranaut did not have her laptop when the police team visited her home to record her statement. Siddiqui did not respond to queries on allowing the police access to Kangana's email account. Roshan's publicity representative said the actor was not going to issue a statement.</p>
<p><em><strong>&mdash; With inputs from Shubha Shetty-Saha</strong></em></p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thane: 62-year-old falls in bus, suffers four spine fractures ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/thane-62yearold-falls-in-bus-suffers-four-spine-fractures/17185178]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 00:50:26 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185178]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Dattatray-Chavan-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Thane: 62-year-old falls in bus, suffers four spine fractures ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The driver missed seeing a speed breaker, and as a result, the senior citizen fell off from his seat and injured himself. The family has alleged that the driver was drunk</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>A 62-year-old man suffered four fractures on his spine while riding a Kalyan-Dombivli Municipal Transport Authority bus on Tuesday. The driver missed seeing a speed breaker, and as a result, the senior citizen fell off from his seat and injured himself. The family has alleged that the driver was drunk.</p>
<p><img title="Dattatray Chavan, was on his way back from meeting friends in Kalyan" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Dattatray-Chavan-1.jpg" alt="Dattatray Chavan, was on his way back from meeting friends in Kalyan" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Dattatray Chavan, was on his way back from meeting friends in Kalyan</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Dattatray Chavan, a resident of Mangeshi Samruddhi Apartments in Khadkpada area of Kalyan West, was returning home after meeting his friends in Kalyan East. Around 11.30 pm, Chavan took a bus from Kalyan station. "Soon, the driver started speeding and the passengers shouted at him and told him to slow down," said Chavan, a retired Central Railway employee, who has now been advised bed rest for four months.</p>
<p>The driver continued to rush and missed a speed breaker. "I fell from my seat. After getting off, we took a picture of the bus driver but forgot to note down the number of the bus as it sped off," said Chavan.</p>
<p>When he reached home, it became difficult for him to walk or get up on his own. His son, Harshal, rushed him to Aayush Hospital. An MRI scan confirmed that Chavan had suffered multiple fractures on the lumbar and thoracic areas of spinal cord. The doctors had to use screws and rods to stabilise the spine after the fractures. "We spent R4 lakh on the surgery," said Chavan.</p>
<p>The family claims it has registered an FIR at Mahatma Phule Police Station in Kalyan, along with the photographs of the driver, but say the police are yet to take action. The police have registered a case under Indian Penal Code Sections 279 (rash driving) 337 (Causing hurt by act endangering life or personal safety of others) and 338 (Causing grievous hurt by act endangering life or personal safety of others).</p>
<p>Senior Police inspector at Mahatma Phule Police station, Anil Pawar, said, "I am not aware of the case. I will need to check the details."</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Eastern Freeway ramps may never see light of day]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-eastern-freeway-ramps-may-never-see-light-of-day/17185177]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[01 May 2016 00:40:11 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185177]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Wadala-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Eastern Freeway ramps may never see light of day]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Two years after spending Rs 5 crore to create new points of access to the freeway, MMRDA realises that the ramps are a hazard, and may not get traffic cops&rsquo; nod</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Each time Shoaib Hussain gets onto the Anik depot-Orange Gate stretch of the Eastern Freeway, he keeps a wary eye on the two ramps running beside it. The 250-metre-long stretches are yet to be opened &mdash; they have been ready for two years, having missed the December 2013 deadline &mdash; but the Andheri resident knows that they are a disaster waiting to happen.</p>
<p><img title="The south-bound ramp connects with the Eastern Freeway near Wadala at a sharp curve prodding the traffic police to permanently station an emergency tow van at the spot. Pics/Pradeep Dhivar" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Wadala-1.jpg" alt="The south-bound ramp connects with the Eastern Freeway near Wadala at a sharp curve prodding the traffic police to permanently station an emergency tow van at the spot. Pics/Pradeep Dhivar" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>The south-bound ramp connects with the Eastern Freeway near Wadala at a sharp curve prodding the traffic police to permanently station an emergency tow van at the spot. Pics/Pradeep Dhivar</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The 250-metre-long ramps, were supposed to help motorists travelling between South Mumbai and areas like Sion, Kurla, Ghatkopar and Wadala get onto the freeway easily, but they are a textbook example of poor planning. The ramps have been rendered useless because they are built on marshy land and meet the freeway near Wadala at a sharp curve.</p>
<p><strong>No green light</strong><br />An expenditure of Rs 5 crore later, it might now be too late for the Mumbai Metropolitan Region Development Authority (MMRDA) to go back to the drawing board. The traffic police have reportedly refused to clear the ramps' opening due to fears of accidents at the spot where the south-bound ramp takes a sharp curve onto the Freeway.</p>
<p>Sources said most vehicles on the freeway don't stick to the speed limit of 60 kmph. The traffic police wants signals to first be installed at the spot &mdash; a suggestion that hasn't gone down well with MMRDA authorities since the Eastern Freeway was pegged to be a signal-less stretch.</p>
<p><img title="The ramp connects with the Eastern Expressway at Wadala on a sharp bend" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Wadala-2.jpg" alt="The ramp connects with the Eastern Expressway at Wadala on a sharp bend" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>The ramp connects with the Eastern Expressway at Wadala on a sharp bend</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Prakash Mamdapuyre, chief of MMRDA's engineer department, said the opening of the ramps hinges on the traffic police's clearance. "The BMC has been asked to install the signals. Work has already begun. The ramps will be opened at the earliest."</p>
<p>MMRDA sources said, for the time being, a passing signal &mdash; asking motorists to slow down &mdash; has been installed on the freeway.</p>
<p>Without the ramps, motorists have to take a creek bridge at the Anik junction, travel almost 1.5 km in the opposite direction towards Panjarpol and then take a U-turn under the RCF flyover to go to South Mumbai.</p>
<p><img title="An emergency towing vehicle stationed at the curvature - an accident-prone spot" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/may/1Wadala-3.jpg" alt="An emergency towing vehicle stationed at the curvature - an accident-prone spot" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>An emergency towing vehicle stationed at the curvature - an accident-prone spot</em></strong></span></p>
<p>But a reality check by mid-day on Saturday revealed that traffic signals alone aren't holding up the opening. The ramps, it turns out, have been built on marshy land &mdash; at at least two spots, the ground has been sinking.</p>
<p>A worker at the site said the land continues to sink despite being levelled repeatedly. "It's all marshy land. It is bound to sink." The pillars of the ramps are just 50-100 metre away from a mangrove plantation. With the ramps continuing to sink in, the plaster on pillars and girders at a number of places have begun to peel off.</p>
<p>An MMRDA official admitted that the land on which the pier of the ramps stand need to be first strengthened. "The piers were constructed on marshy land. All proper procedures were followed and the foundation of the piers was laid as per standards. There is no threat to the structure."</p>
<p>mid-day also found that the south-bound ramp offers little leeway to vehicles getting onto the Freeway &mdash; a sure recipe for disaster. The authorities are aware that the sharp curve is an accident-prone zone &mdash; they have stationed an emergency towing van near the south-bound carriageway. The MMRDA official said CCTV cameras have been installed to monitor speeding vehicles. "We can ask traffic police to deploy personnel near the ramps to avoid accidents."</p>
<p><strong>Alternative spot</strong><br />Transport experts have slammed MMRDA's poor planning. Expert Jitendra Gupta said the MMRDA is notorious for ill thought projects. "Take the Monorail and the cycling track projects, for example. Public funds have been wasted on them. The freeway ramp near Wadala is a dangerous spot. Had the MMRDA coordinated with the traffic police and discussed the locations with them, the ramps could have been thrown open a long time ago."</p>
<p>Joint CP (traffic) Pratap Digaonkar said, "No one has approached us for clearance of the ramps."</p><br/>Accidents on Eastern Freeway<br/><p><strong>Sept 2013:</strong> A biker who had illegally entered the Eastern Freeway died in an accident.&nbsp;The pillion rider was<br />grievously injured.<br /><strong>July 2015:</strong> A motorist died and another person was injured when their vehicle rammed into the divider.<br /><strong>June 2015:</strong> Two persons were killed and three others were injured after the speeding car of lawyer Janhavi Gadkar (35) crashed into another car, having entered the wrong lane.</p>
<p><strong>Clueless</strong><br />The opening of the freeway ramps isn't the MMRDA's top priority at the moment. How do we know that? Sanjay Khandare, additional metropolitan commissioner, MMRDA, is not aware of the reasons why they haven't been opened. "I will have to check before commenting on it."</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Petrol price hiked by 1.06 a litre, diesel 2.094 paise]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/petrol-price-hiked-by-106-a-litre-diesel-2094-paise/17185175]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 18:12:14 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185175]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/feb/18petrol-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Petrol price hiked by 1.06 a litre, diesel 2.094 paise]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Petrol price was on Saturday hiked by Rs 1.06 per litre and diesel by Rs 2.94 a litre. Petrol in Delhi will cost Rs 62.19 per litre from midnight tonight as against Rs 61.13 currently, said Indian Oil Corporation (IOC), the nation's largest fuel retailer</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> Petrol price was on Saturday hiked by Rs 1.06 per litre and diesel by Rs 2.94 a litre. Petrol in Delhi will cost Rs 62.19 per litre from midnight tonight as against Rs 61.13 currently, said Indian Oil Corporation (IOC), the nation's largest fuel retailer.</p>
<p><img title="Representational picture" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/feb/18petrol.jpg" alt="Representational picture" width="550" height="379" /></p>
<p>Similarly, a litre of diesel will cost Rs 50.95 compared to Rs 48.01 at present.</p>
<p>The hike comes on back of Rs 0.74 per litre cut in petrol price and diesel by Rs 1.30 a litre on April 16. "The current level of international product prices of petrol and diesel and the rupee-US Dollar exchange rate warrant increase in price of petrol and diesel, the impact of which is being passed on to the consumers with this price revision," the IOC said.</p>
<p>State-owned fuel retailers IOC, Bharat Petroleum Corporation Ltd (BPCL) and Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Ltd (HPCL) revise rates of the fuel on 1st and 16th of every month based on the average oil price and the foreign exchange rate in the preceding fortnight.</p>
<p>"The movement of prices in the international oil market and the rupee-USD exchange rate shall continue to be monitored closely and developing trends of the market will be reflected in future price changes," the company added.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Forest fires rage across Uttarakhand, 6 dead; NDRF deployed]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/forest-fires-rage-across-uttarakhand-6-dead-ndrf-deployed/17185166]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 16:10:25 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185166]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Forest fires rage across Uttarakhand, 6 dead; NDRF deployed]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Major forest fires raged on Saturday across Uttarakhand even as three teams of NDRF were deployed in Almora, Gauchar and Pauri and one team of SDRF in Nainital to extinguish the flames</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dehradun:</strong> Major forest fires raged on Saturday across Uttarakhand even as three teams of NDRF were deployed in Almora, Gauchar and Pauri and one team of SDRF in Nainital to extinguish the flames.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of forest fire incidents in the state in early February this year, 922 incidents have occurred so far killing six people including three women and a child, in separate incidents, injuring seven and blighting 1890.79 hectares of green cover, Principal Conservator of Forest (Research) B P Gupta told PTI.</p>
<p>Rudraprayag forest division is taking the army's help for fire-fighting operations especially along the highways, Gupta said. Chamoli, Pauri, Rudraprayag, Tehri, Uttarkashi, Pithoragarh, Almora and Nainital are the worst-affected districts, he said.</p>
<p>The casualties due to forest fires which have spread to sparsely-populated remote hill areas, rose to six with another life lost in Nainital district on Friday evening. 1890.79 hectares of green cover have been destroyed by the fires which had an early start on February 2 this year due to a dry winter.</p>
<p>Governor K K Paul reviewed the rescue efforts underway via videoconferencing with officials in the field and asked them to speed up their efforts. NDRF companies, assisted by expert teams and locals, are conducting fire-fighting and rescue operations in Garhwal and Kumaon regions. IG Sanjay Gunjyal is cordinating with NDRF, District Magistrates concerned and the Principal Conservator of Forest to supervise the rescue operations.</p>
<p>Locals are being encouraged to report a fire incident to the District Magistrate concerned as soon as they see it so that it can be controlled in time. The Governor has doubled the number of personnel deployed to control the fires from 3000 to 6000 and asked all agencies including SDRF, district administration and the rural population to contribute their bits in the exercise saying the forest department alone cannot accomplish the onerous task, Gupta said.</p>
<p>Forest fires are a natural phenomena in summer but this time they have occurred on a bigger scale as the fire season which normally begins by February 15 and ends by June 15 began on February 2 itself.</p>
<p>Former chief minister Harish Rawat has asked the Governor to declare Uttarakhand as a fire disaster struck state and involve locals as much as possible in fire-extinguishing efforts. Pradesh Congress president Kishore Upadhyay has also written to party workers asking them to work unitedly to pull the state out of the 'crisis.'</p>
<p>The PCF said the scale of forest fires in Uttarakhand this time has been bigger due to little or no rain during winter at most places. Pre-fire alerts listing possible fire points over the next seven days in forest areas is being made available on forest department's website www.forest.uk. govt, an official release here said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13-year-old girl killed in families' quarrel over songs at wedding]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/13yearold-girl-killed-in-families-quarrel-over-songs-at-wedding/17185172]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 15:56:40 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185172]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[13-year-old girl killed in families' quarrel over songs at wedding]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A 13-year-old girl was killed in Haryana's Mewat district in firing that took place after her family objected to some songs being played at a neighbouring house during a wedding ceremony, police said on Saturday</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gurgaon:</strong> A 13-year-old girl was killed in Haryana's Mewat district in firing that took place after her family objected to some songs being played at a neighbouring house during a wedding ceremony, police said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Police were yet to arrest anyone.</p>
<p>Police said the incident occurred late Friday night during the marriage of Dinu's son Yahbudi, a resident of Biwan village in Haryana's Mewat district.</p>
<p>The police complaint stated that Dinu's neighbour Israel and a few villagers were objecting to the loud and double meaning songs being played during the wedding.</p>
<p>In his complaint, Israel stated that when he along with other villagers objected to playing such songs around 2 a.m, some people opened fire.</p>
<p>In the firing, Israel's 13-year-old daughter Swahalia was killed on the spot when a bullet hit her forehead.</p>
<p>Police have booked a group of people including Shokeen, Naseen, Sakeen, Haku and others under various sections of the Indian Penal Code, including murder.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Narrow escape for Hema Malini again as vehicles in her cavalcade collide]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/narrow-escape-for-hema-malini-again-as-vehicles-in-her-cavalcade-collide/17185170]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 14:45:59 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185170]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/jan/17hema-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Narrow escape for Hema Malini again as vehicles in her cavalcade collide]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Actor-turned-politician Hema Malini on Saturday had a narrow escape as two vehicles in her cavalcade collided with each other under Highway police station area in Mathura, police said</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mathura:</strong> Actor-turned-politician Hema Malini on Saturday had a narrow escape as two vehicles in her cavalcade collided with each other under Highway police station area in Mathura, police said.</p>
<p><img title="Hema Malini" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/jan/17hema.jpg" alt="Hema Malini" width="670" height="447" /><em style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Hema Malini</strong></em></p>
<p>"MP Hema Malini is safe," SP City, Mukul Dwivedi said.</p>
<p>The accident took place when the BJP MP was going to Deen Dayal Upadhyay Veterinary University and Gau Anusandhan Kendra to inaugurate a function."One of the vehicles in the MP's cavalcade suddenly applied the brakes, halting the movement of the other vehicles. Meanwhile, a speeding car entered into the fleet and brushed past the vehicle carrying the MP," Sanjai Govil, BJP leader, said.</p>
<p>The stray vehicle fled the spot thereafter, he added.</p>
<p>The Bollywood actor had met with an accident in Rajasthan last year, in which a four-year-old girl was killed and five others were injured, including Hema Malini. <a title="Hema Malini is 'fine' say doctors, driver arrested for child's death " href="http://www.mid-day.com/articles/hema-malini-is-fine-say-doctors-driver-arrested-for-childs-death/16339159" target="_blank"><span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>(Read more)</strong></span></a></p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Minor sustains bullet injury while taking selfie with revolver]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/minor-sustains-bullet-injury-while-taking-selfie-with-revolver/17185165]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 13:28:03 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185165]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Minor sustains bullet injury while taking selfie with revolver]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A 15-year-old boy sustained bullet injury in his head while taking selfie with a revolver at his home at Shiv Nagar here, police said on Saturday</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pathankot</strong>: A 15-year-old boy sustained bullet injury in his head while taking selfie with a revolver at his home at Shiv Nagar here, police said on Saturday.</p>
<p>With bullet stuck in his head, critically injured Ramandeep Singh was shifted to a hospital in Ludhiana, they further said.</p>
<p>The incident occurred last night when Ramandeep was trying to take a selfie on his mobile phone with the licensed .32 bore revolver while pointing the weapon to his head, Pathankot Deputy Superintendent of Police (City) Manoj Kumar said.</p>
<p>The revolver belonged to Ramandeep's father Gurkirpal Singh who is a property dealer.</p>
<p>"As per statement given by his father, Ramandeep sustained bullet injury while taking selife with a revolver and the shot got accidentally fired," DSP said.</p>
<p>At the time of the incident, Ramandeep's mother and other family members were present at home, he said.</p>
<p>"We shall try to record Ramandeep's statement as and when he is fit, to find out what actually happened last night. We shall also ask family's neighbours about incident," the DSP said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[4-year old boy slips into 200-ft borewell; rescue operation on]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/4year-old-boy-slips-into-200ft-borewell-rescue-operation-on/17185164]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 12:56:16 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185164]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[4-year old boy slips into 200-ft borewell; rescue operation on]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A four-year-old boy accidentally fell into a 200-feet deep open borewell on Saturday at a village in Shirur taluka of the district even as rescue operation was on to pull him out, police said</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pune:</strong> A four-year-old boy accidentally fell into a 200-feet deep open borewell on Saturday at a village in Shirur taluka of the district even as rescue operation was on to pull him out, police said.</p>
<p>The incident took place on Saturday afternoon at Mandwan village in Shirur, nearly 63 km from here, when Sunil More, son of a labourer who was working at a farm nearby, slipped into the borewell while playing, station duty officer at Shirur Police Station A J Jagdale said.</p>
<p>The boy got struck at 20-feet depth from the ground level, he added.</p>
<p>"Local administration along with fire brigade, medical team and police have reached the spot and an operation has been launched to rescue the boy," Jagdale said.</p>
<p>The rescue teams are digging a parallel hole near the borewell in an attempt to pull out the child, the officer said, adding that oxygen is being pumped into the borewell and the boy is responding.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Soldier killed in accidental firing in Kashmir]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/soldier-killed-in-accidental-firing-in-kashmir/17185163]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 12:14:47 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185163]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Soldier killed in accidental firing in Kashmir]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A soldier of the counter-insurgency Rashtriya Rifles (RR) died in Jammu and Kashmir's Kupwara district on Saturday after shooting himself accidentally with his service weapon, defence sources said</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Srinagar:</strong> A soldier of the counter-insurgency Rashtriya Rifles (RR) died in Jammu and Kashmir's Kupwara district on Saturday after shooting himself accidentally with his service weapon, defence sources said.</p>
<p>He was identified as junior commissioned officer Jai Prakash Singh of 30 RR, posted in Langate area of Kupwara.</p>
<p>"After hearing shots, troops of 30 RR in Langate found the JCO lying in a pool of blood. His service rifle had misfired accidentally, as per initial reports from the camp.</p>
<p>"He was airlifted for treatment to the army's 92 Base hospital in Srinagar, but could not be revived," a source said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Auction fails as no bidder turns up for Kingfisher brands in Mumbai]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/auction-fails-as-no-bidder-turns-up-for-kingfisher-brands-in-mumbai/17185159]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 11:17:01 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185159]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/Kingfisher-House-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Auction fails as no bidder turns up for Kingfisher brands in Mumbai]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Auction of brands and trademarks of Kingfisher Airlines turned out to be a damp squib as lenders failed to attract a single bidder for sale of these pledged assets at a reserve price of Rs 366.70 crore in their efforts to recover unpaid loans from beleaguered Vijay Mallya</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Auction of brands and trademarks of Kingfisher Airlines turned out to be a damp squib on Saturday as lenders failed to attract a single bidder for sale of these pledged assets at a reserve price of Rs 366.70 crore in their efforts to recover unpaid loans from beleaguered Vijay Mallya.</p>
<p><img title="Kingfisher house" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/Kingfisher-House.jpg" alt="Kingfisher house" width="670" height="457" /><em style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Kingfisher House was put under the hammer by SBI, which had lent Rs 1,600 crore to Kingfisher Airlines. Pic/Nimesh Dave&nbsp;</strong></em></p>
<p>This is the second failed attempt by the 17-bank consortium led by state-run behemoth SBI to recover some money from Mallya, after an earlier auction of Kingfisher House -- the erstwhile headquarters of the long-defunct airline -- met with a similar fate, with no bidder coming forward.</p>
<p>The items on sale during today's e-auction included the the Kingfisher logo as also the once-famous tagline 'Fly the Good Times'. The other trademarks on sale included Flying Models, Funliner, Fly Kingfisher and Flying Bird Device. The reserve price for the trademarks was kept at Rs 366.70 crore, which is not even one-tenth of the price at which it was pledged as a collateral for the loan. Sources, however, said the reserve price was 'too high' for any bidder to come in.</p>
<p>"There were no bids, possibly because the reserve price was considered very high. Though the reserve price was set much lower than its original valuation at the time of taking the brand as collateral, people still found it to be high," a banking source said.</p>
<p>The online auction began at 11:30 am and lasted for an hour without any success. It was conducted by SBICAP Trustee Company on behalf of lenders under the Sarfaesi Act.</p>
<p>The Kingfisher brand itself was valued at over Rs 4,000 crore by Grant Thornton when the airline was at its peak. In its annual report for 2012-13, KFA said that at its peak, it was the largest airline in India, with a five-star rating from Skytrax. The airline's brand had been registered separately from the Kingfisher beer trademarks.</p>
<p>A senior banker said, "The interest for this auction could have been from existing airline operators, but no one will come. It is better to start a new airline company than to buy this brand and revive it."</p>
<p>In a previous attempt at recovery of dues, which have ballooned to over Rs 9,000 crore after taking into account the interest component, the banks had conducted an auction of Kingfisher House last month, but did not find any takers at a reserve price of Rs 150 crore.</p>
<p>Sources said the lenders might now try to lower the reserve price in both the cases in their future efforts to sell these pledged assets. The Kingfisher House property has a built-up area of over 17,000 square feet in posh Vile Parle near domestic airport in Mumbai. Mallya, who left India on March 2 and is currently in London, has a non-bailable warrant against him in a money-laundering investigation. His passport has also been revoked. Earlier this week, the government said it has written to the British government seeking Mallya's deportation.</p>
<p>In an interview to the Financial Times, the liquor baron, however, said he is in a 'forced exile' and has no plans at the moment to return to India where things are flying at him 'fast and furious'.</p>
<p>"I definitely would like to return to India. Right now, things are flying at me fast and furious. My passport has been revoked. I don't know what the government is going to do next," he said.</p>
<p>Mallya said he wanted a 'reasonable' settlement with creditor banks for his defunct airline, but they 'are not getting any money' by taking his passport or arresting him.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bride walks out of ceremony after finding groom drunk]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/bride-walks-out-of-ceremony-after-finding-groom-drunk/17185158]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 10:31:27 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185158]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Bride walks out of ceremony after finding groom drunk]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>A bride walked out of her wedding ceremony after finding out that the groom was quite older to her and was drunk in Deep Pur village in Kanpur, police said on Saturday</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kanpur:</strong> A bride walked out of her wedding ceremony after finding out that the groom was quite older to her and was drunk in Deep Pur village in Kanpur, police said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The bride's decision at the venue led to ugly scenes with both sides entering into a confrontation, SP(Rural) Surender Tiwari said.</p>
<p>The incident took place yesterday, when the bride (26), during the wedding ceremony, noticed that the groom looked much older than her and was reeking of alcohol, he said.</p>
<p>She refused to exchange garlands with him and walked out. Police was asked to intervene in the matter following which the wedding was called off and the groom and his family eturned to their village, he added.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Death toll rises in 90-year-old building collapse]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-death-toll-rises-in-90yearold-building-collapse/17185155]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 10:12:30 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185155]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/building-collapse-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Death toll rises in 90-year-old building collapse]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Five people, including a woman, were killed and three others were injured after a three-storey building in Kamathipura area in south Mumbai collapsed on Saturday</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Five people, including a woman, were killed and three others were injured after a three-storey building in Kamathipura area in south Mumbai collapsed on Saturday, civic officials said.</p>
<p><img title="Kamathipura collapse" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/1-kamathipura-collapse.jpg" alt="Kamathipura collapse" /><em style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Rescue operations at the site where the building collapsed. Pic/Ajinkya Sawant</strong></em></p>
<p>The building, which was over 90 years old, was under repair when it caved in at around 2 pm, the official said. "Four persons died on the spot, while one succumbed to his injuries during treatment," Chief Fire Officer Prabhat Rahangdale said.</p>
<p>The <span>under-construction </span>building is located in&nbsp;Kamathipura's Gully 14 <span>near Grant Road railway station in Mumbai. </span></p>
<p><span><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/building-collapse.jpg" alt="" /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>The fire brigade officials trying to rescue people trapped under the debris at the accident site. Pic/Suresh Karkera&nbsp;</strong></em></span><br /></span></p>
<p><span>Four people have been rescued and some are feared trapped under the debris. Two of the rescued have been taken to JJ Hospital and other two to Grant Medical Hospital.</span>&nbsp;The condition of the other injured is said to be critical.</p>
<p>Many people are still feared trapped under the rubble, the Fire Brigade official said, adding the structure housed a beer bar and a factory, among others.</p>
<p>A fire official said, "We stopped the rescue operation after we confirmed that no one was trapped inside the debris. However, keeping in mind the dilapidated condition of the adjoining wall and the neighbouring building, we have kept two fire engines ready."</p>
<p>Eight fire engines and three ambulances were pressed into rescue operation, the official said.</p>
<p>Local MLA Amin Patel, who visited the spot, said an inquiry should be conducted into the incident. "Keeping the safety of people in mind, a nearby building has been evacuated and the residents are being shifted to a transit camp," Patel said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, state BJP spokesperson Atul Shah alleged that there are over 500 illegal structures that have come up in the area. "We need to have an inquiry on such illegal structures. There has to be a proper development plan for Kamathipura, for which a micro survey needs to be done," he said.</p>
<p>When contacted, police said an inquiry into the matter was on, but no FIR has been registered against anyone in this connection so far.</p>
<p><span><br /></span></p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[TMC minister Firhad Hakim rakes up controversy by calling part of Kolkata port 'mini Pakistan']]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/tmc-minister-firhad-hakim-rakes-up-controversy-by-calling-part-of-kolkata-port-mini-pakistan/17185153]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 09:26:31 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17185153]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[TMC minister Firhad Hakim rakes up controversy by calling part of Kolkata port 'mini Pakistan']]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>BJP has alleged that a state&nbsp;minister and Trinamool Congress leader Firhad Hakim has&nbsp;described a part of Kolkata port area as "mini Pakistan" in an&nbsp;interview to Pakistan daily 'Dawn' and demanded an&nbsp;explanation, even as Hakim denied having made such comment</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kolkata:&nbsp;</strong>BJP has alleged that a state&nbsp;minister and Trinamool Congress leader Firhad Hakim has&nbsp;described a part of Kolkata port area as "mini Pakistan" in an&nbsp;interview to Pakistan daily 'Dawn' and demanded an&nbsp;explanation, even as Hakim denied having made such comment.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"How can a minister say such things? We demand an&nbsp;explanation from both Mr Firhad Hakim and also Chief Minister&nbsp;Mamata Banerjee," BJP national secretary Siddharth Nath Singh&nbsp;said.</p>
<p>When contacted Hakim told PTI he never made such&nbsp;comment.</p>
<p>"The Pakistani journalist came along with a journalist of&nbsp;a local Bengali daily. She only asked me that this place looks&nbsp;like Karachi of Pakistan. I did not make any comment. She&nbsp;spoke to me about my election campaign. I answered those&nbsp;questions. That's all," he said.</p>
<p>According to an article in Dawn, a journalist of the&nbsp;newspaper who was in Kolkata few days back, spoke to Hakim&nbsp;during his campaign trail in Muslim-dominated Kolkata port&nbsp;area and it was during this interview that he termed the part&nbsp;of Kolkata port area as "Mini Pakistan".</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jaidev, Vijay, Peter: Three famous men and their controversies]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/jaidev-vijay-peter-three-famous-men-and-their-controversies/17182184]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 07:40:41 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17182184]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/three-controversy-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Jaidev, Vijay, Peter: Three famous men and their controversies]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Fame and controversies often go hand in hand. Businessmen Vijay Mallya and Jaidev Shroff as well as former media baron Peter Mukerjea have found this out the hard way in recent times</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Fame and controversies often go hand in hand. Businessmen Vijay Mallya and Jaidev Shroff as well as former media baron Peter Mukerjea have found this out the hard way in recent times. A detailed account of their troubles.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/23-Jaidev-Shroff.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="644" /></p>
<p><strong>Jaidev Shroff:</strong>&nbsp;Top industrialist and head of United Phosphorus Limited, is fighting an ugly divorce battle with his wife Poonam Bhagat, Accusations have been flying thick and high, with Jaidev accusing Poonam of spiking his drink with a mysterious powdery concoction on the advice of a &lsquo;Bengali baba&rsquo;. In response, Poonam has claimed that inhuman treatment was meted out to her while they were married and that she suffered physical and mental violence and even a miscarriage.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/poonam-bhagt-m.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>Poonam</strong>&nbsp;has also said that she was ready for a quick divorce after she recently learnt about Shroff&rsquo;s long drawn extra-marital affair that she alleges started in 2013. Police have arrested the &lsquo;Bengali baba&rsquo;, Gulam Moin Shattir Hakim Sufi, after he confessed to his crime in connection with the case. Further, a family court on Friday passed an order restraining Poonam from entering husband Jaidev&rsquo;s Bandra home until the disposal of their divorce case. A taped conversation, allegedly between Poonam and a &lsquo;Bengali baba&rsquo; she had roped in, went against her. Poonam has maintained that the allegation against her is a &lsquo;quick divorce&rsquo; stunt.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/Mallya-old.jpg" alt="" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>File pic/AFP</em></strong></span></p>
<p><strong>Vijay Mallya:</strong> He is no longer the &lsquo;King Of Good Times&rsquo;. The beleaguered businessman is in a soup, and is facing legal proceedings for allegedly defaulting on loans of over Rs 9,000 crore from several banks, which he had taken for the now-defunct Kingfisher Airlines. Non-bailable warrants (NBWs) have been issued against him.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/Kingfisher-ladies.jpg" alt="" /><br /><strong><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>This file photograph taken on December 21, 2013, shows then Indian United Breweries Group chairman Vijay Mallya (C, in white) as he poses with models during the launch of the Kingfisher 2014 calendar in Mumbai. Pic/AFP</em></span></strong></p>
<p>Lenders made a failed attempt to sell Kingfisher House, and the latest is that they will auction the trademarks of the airline, including the &lsquo;Kingfisher&rsquo; logo and once-famous &lsquo;Fly the Good Times&rsquo; tagline on April 30.&nbsp;He is also likely to be expelled from Parliament. We haven&rsquo;t heard the last of this yet.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/Indrani-Peter-1.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="591" /></p>
<p><strong>Peter Mukerjea:</strong> The former Star India CEO has been arrested in connection with the Sheena Bora murder case. In what has been one of the most gruesome murder cases in recent years, Peter&rsquo;s arrest followed that of his wife Indrani, who was nabbed for the murder of Sheena, her daughter from a previous marriage.</p>
<p>Peter has been charged with murder and criminal conspiracy. He has also been accused of destroying evidence and lying to protect his wife Indrani. <br />As per the CBI charge sheet, Peter&rsquo;s motive for committing the crime was that he was against the relationship between Sheena and his son Rahul Mukerjea.</p>
<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/mar/Indrani-Peter-2.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="663" /></p>
<p>Indrani, her former husband Sanjeev Khanna and her driver Shyamvar Rai allegedly strangled Sheena (24) inside a car in April 2012. The crime came to light last August. The police learnt of Sheena&rsquo;s murder from Indrani&rsquo;s driver, Shyam Manohar Rai (43), who spilled the beans when he was arrested on August 21 last year in connection with an illegal arms case.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal: Draft bill for Delhi's statehood ready]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/arvind-kejriwal-draft-bill-for-delhis-statehood-ready/17184199]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 07:33:53 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184199]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2015/dec/22kejriwal-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal: Draft bill for Delhi's statehood ready]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal on Saturday said that a draft bill for statehood of the national capital was ready</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal on Saturday said that a draft bill for statehood of the national capital was ready.</p>
<p><img title="Arvind Kejriwal" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2015/dec/22kejriwal.jpg" alt="Arvind Kejriwal" width="592" height="393" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>Arvind Kejriwal</strong></em></span></p>
<p>"Draft bill for statehood of Delhi ready. Will be soon placed in public domain for comments and suggestions from the public," the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader said in a tweet.</p>
<p>Kejriwal has been batting for full statehood for Delhi, claiming the move will help him implement his plans better in the city.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supreme Court refuses to re-look into NEET order]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/supreme-court-refuses-to-relook-into-neet-order/17184198]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 07:30:43 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184198]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Supreme Court refuses to re-look into NEET order]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The Supreme Court on Saturday refused to re-look at its order directing the holding of two National Eligibility Entrance Tests (NEET) for admission to under graduate medical courses for 2016-17</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> The Supreme Court on Saturday refused to re-look at its order directing the holding of two National Eligibility Entrance Tests (NEET) for admission to undergraduate medical courses for 2016-17.</p>
<p>While declining to entertain a plea for re-look at the order, the apex court bench comprising Chief Justice T.S. Thakur, Justice A.K. Sikri and Justice R. Banumati said: "The matter has been argued before another bench. The matter is over."</p>
<p>The court said this when a lawyer pointed out to the difficulties that students would face if they are asked to appear for NEET if they are not prepared for it.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court on Friday said that Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) will conduct the NEET on May 1 and July 24, for admission to under-graduate medical courses as it had earlier directed.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[mid-day impact: BEST orders water cut for washing buses]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/midday-impact-best-orders-water-cut-for-washing-buses/17183191]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 06:53:20 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183191]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30bus-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[mid-day impact: BEST orders water cut for washing buses]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>BEST Undertaking decides to lessen amount of water used to wash buses by 50%, till the monsoon arrives; buses will now be washed only when necessary</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>The next time you travel in a BEST bus, don't mind if there's a sliver of dirt on your seat. Four days after mid-day reported about BEST using potable water for washing its fleet every&nbsp;day, the undertaking has decided to curtail its water usage drastically by washing buses with less water and only when necessary.</p>
<p><img title="The officials are hoping for early rains as now they fear that the number of buses will further come down. File pic" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30bus-1.jpg" alt="The officials are hoping for early rains as now they fear that the number of buses will further come down. File pic" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>The officials are hoping for early rains as now they fear that the number of buses will further come down. File pic</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Sources said that on an average, at least 50 litres less water from the usual quantum would be used for washing buses, whenever they are cleaned. Over the last few weeks, the authorities have lessened the use of water by 50 per cent.</p>
<p>mid-day had reported on April 26 how out of 27 BEST depots, 23 have been using potable water. The report stated that the undertaking uses over 70,000 litres of water for the cleaning everyday, and almost the entire amount comes from the BMC's potable water supply. Now, the officials have sent a letter to all depots, asking them to ensure that they use minimum amount of water for washing buses. "We will wash only those buses that are in dire need of cleanliness, until the monsoon arrives," said a BEST official.</p>
<p>The officials are hoping for early rains as now, they fear that the number of buses &mdash; around 400 &mdash; that currently go for daily washing will further come down. The existing amount of water for manually washing a bus, around 200 litres, has been brought down.</p>
<p>"Currently, there is no segregation or system for supplying potable and non-potable water throughout the city. Unless that happens, total separation and dependence on non-potable water is not possible," said another official.</p>
<p><a title="Mumbai: 23 out of 27 BEST depots use drinking water to wash buses" href="http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-23-out-of-27-best-depots-use-drinking-water-to-wash-buses/17170185" target="_blank"><img title="mid-day's April 26 report" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30midday-1.jpg" alt="mid-day's April 26 report" /></a><br /><a title="http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-23-out-of-27-best-depots-use-drinking-water-to-wash-buses/17170185" href="http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-23-out-of-27-best-depots-use-drinking-water-to-wash-buses/17170185" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>mid-day's April 26 report</em></strong></span></a></p>
<p>"The BEST administration needs to make a provision for more borewells at its depots," said Ravi Raja, BEST committee member.</p>
<p>At present, four depots have borewells. BEST was instructed to use borewell water, but officials had earlier said they had not done so because of lack of funds to dig borewells. They also use mechanised cleaning machines, which consume 40 per cent less water.</p><br/>Uproar over slashing of fares<br/><p>Meanwhile, BEST also faced an uproar from its committee members for declaring stoppage of 52 routes from May 1. mid-day had reported about the same yesterday. They also slashed the fares of air-conditioned buses by half, which they claimed is a tactic for diverting the issue of these cancellations.</p>
<p>"The public is knocking on our door, asking us why is an important bus route, which ferried them from home to the station and back has been cancelled," said committee member Yakub Memon. Deputy general manager R R Deshpande said, "We will have to approach the union and they will have go give their nod and only then will we be able to change it. If not, we will try to make some changes in the schedule and keep a few of the 52 routes still running."</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Flyover connecting Goregaon East and West to open today]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-flyover-connecting-goregaon-east-and-west-to-open-today/17184186]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 04:45:24 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184186]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Goregaon-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai: Flyover connecting Goregaon East and West to open today]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The 2.3-km-long flyover connecting SV Road and the Western Express Highway (WEH) in Goregaon will finally open on Saturday, six years after its construction began. Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis and Shiv Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray will inaugurate it</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Goregaon-1.jpg" alt="" /><br />The 2.3-km-long flyover connecting SV Road and the Western Express Highway (WEH) in Goregaon will finally open on Saturday, six years after its construction began. Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis and Shiv Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray will inaugurate it. The flyover, built at a cost of over Rs 250 crore, will be named after late socialist leader Mrinal Gore. Over 358 structures and huts had to be removed for the project. <em><strong>Pic/Nimesh Dave</strong></em></p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Commuters forced to run 65-m to catch 12-car train on Harbour Line]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/commuters-forced-to-run-65m-to-catch-12car-train-on-harbour-line/17183197]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:44:23 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183197]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Wadala-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Commuters forced to run 65-m to catch 12-car train on Harbour Line]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>On Day 1, all locals on Harbour line were stopped three coach-lengths ahead as the motormen tried to get used to operating the newly introduced 12-car rakes</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>On a day when Central Railway (CR) authorities celebrated the rollout of the first 12-car train service on Harbour line's CST-Panvel route, commuters at railway stations were left breathless. All trains on the Harbour line, regardless of the number of cars, were halted three coaches ahead on Friday, forcing passengers to break into a 65-m dash to catch them.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;"><strong>Watch Video: <a title=" Watch Video: 12-car train rolls into Vashi station on Harbour line" href="http://www.mid-day.com/articles/watch-video-12-car-train-rolls-into-vashi-station-on-harbour-line/17182171" target="_blank"><span style="color: #ff0000;">12-car train rolls into Vashi station on Harbour line</span></a></strong></span></p>
<p><img title="Need for speed: Commuters rush to catch the local at the Wadala station. Pic/Suresh Karkera" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Wadala-1.jpg" alt="Need for speed: Commuters rush to catch the local at the Wadala station. Pic/Suresh Karkera" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Need for speed: Commuters rush to catch the local at the Wadala station. Pic/Suresh Karkera</em></strong></span></p>
<p>All motormen have been asked to pull up at the prescribed halt for 12-car locals, close to the signal on platforms, irrespective of whether they are driving 9-car or 12-car trains. The change, said CR officials, is to get them habituated to operating 12-car trains.</p>
<p>"We want to check how well the new 12-car services will work when they are merged with the 9-car services," said a CR official.</p>
<p><strong>Blanking out</strong><br />Although railway officials publicised the change &mdash; through constant announcements on the public address system, notice boards and posters on the windows of ticket counters &mdash;commuters weren't clued in to the change.</p>
<p>They stuck to their usual spots and broke into a sprint when the trains stopped ahead. "We are starting the trains slowly so that even if people try catching a running train, they don't fall off," said a CR motorman.</p>
<p><strong>Stumbling blocks</strong><br />CR officials, complained commuters, havn't thought the plan for 12-car trains through. There are no sunshades at the ends of platforms where the trains now halt, forcing many commuters to stick to their usual spots, instead of risking standing in the scorching heat.</p>
<p>Dockyard Road, Reay Road and Wadala Road stations also threaten to play spoilsport to the new plan. The total length of a 12-car rake (buffer-to-buffer) is 258 m. To accommodate such trains, the ideal length of a platform should be at least 265 m. But, the length of the platforms at these stations is 262 m &mdash; leaving a buffer of just 4 m &mdash; thus increasing the chances of trains overshooting them.</p>
<p>Besides, the signals are barely 400-450 m apart, which makes speeding for 12-car trains an issue. Also, work on providing parking spaces near Wadala, Panvel and Sanpada stations are still pending.</p>
<p>Sources said railway officials are speeding up the work at Wadala to make space for a second 12-car train.</p>
<p><strong>Mega block tomorrow</strong><br />While senior CR officials hope to introduce the second 12-car train before May 5, it will take another three months for the authorities to convert the entire fleet of 36 locals from 9-car rakes to 12-car trains.</p>
<p>The CR operates over 570 services on the Harbour line, of which only 14 are 12-car locals. The conversion will up the carrying capacity of the trains by 33%. Currently, 10 lakh people travel on the Harbour line daily.</p>
<p>The Mumbai Rail Vikas Corporation, which is extending platforms for 12-car trains, will undertake an eight-hour block again this Sunday, between Mahim and Andheri on the Harbour line to complete the pending works.</p><br/>Are we ready for 12-car trains?<br/><p>Three stations play a crucial role in the success of operations of 12-car trains. mid-day takes a look at their preparedness.<br /><strong>Wadala Road:</strong> A large chunk of the work on provision of stabling for trains is still pending. Tracks, too, are only half done. Sources said the curvature here is steep. So, motormen will face a minor visibility problem. This could worsen during a heavy rainfall.<br /><strong>Dockyard Road:</strong> The sides&nbsp;of the bridge have been&nbsp;cut to allow extension&nbsp;of the platform. The buffer space is too small.<br /><strong>Reay Road:</strong> The branches of a few trees block the signal; they need to be trimmed.</p>
<p><strong>First service a success</strong><br />The first 12-car train on the Harbour line left the Vashi station at 6 am on Friday and reached the Wadala Road station at the scheduled time, said CR's Chief PRO Narendra Patil. There was no technical glitch, he added. &ldquo;Our team will monitor and study the running of the train, and try to ascertain its impact on punctuality, passengers and train movement,&rdquo; said DRM Amitabh Ojha of CR's Mumbai division.</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[BMC failed to act against 27 corrupt officials: RTI]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/bmc-failed-to-act-against-27-corrupt-officials-rti/17183195]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:41:36 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183195]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[BMC failed to act against 27 corrupt officials: RTI]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The Brihanmumbai Municipal Corporation (BMC) has not initiated any action against as many as 27 officials who were found to be involved in corruption cases from 2005 to February this year but rather reinstated some of them, an RTI query has revealed</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>The Brihanmumbai Municipal Corporation (BMC) has not initiated any action against as many as 27 officials who were found to be involved in corruption cases from 2005 to February this year but rather reinstated some of them, an RTI query has revealed.</p>
<p>The disclosure has given fresh ammunition to opposition parties to target the Shiv Sena-BJP alliance, which controls the richest civic body, ahead of 2017 municipal polls. The RTI application was filed by activist Jeetendra Ghadge.</p>
<p>The officials were either caught by ACB for accepting bribes or have cases of disproportionate assets registered against them. However, no action like suspension was taken against them by the civic body, with some of them being reinstated, he said.</p>
<p>"It's shocking they are reinstated despite cases pending against them. If this is what is happening people will not file complaints in ACB fearing revenge from such officials who will be back on duty within a year," Ghadge said.</p>
<p>The development has given a handle to the Congress and NCP to hit the saffron combine with. "The RTI response is proof that governance of BMC is in shambles. The citizens of Mumbai will surely teach a lesson to the corrupt politicians backing these corrupt officers," said Congress spokesperson Al-Nasser Zakaria.</p>
<p>NCP leader Sachin Ahir said the ruling corporators are keeping mum as they know they have failed and are a part of the "corrupt" system. BMC Chief Enquiry Officer Ramesh Danane said, "whatever decisions have been taken were as per the instructions of BMC Commissioner".</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hours after giving birth, hospital heater leaves mother with burnt leg]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/hours-after-giving-birth-hospital-heater-leaves-mother-with-burnt-leg/17183198]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:20:11 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183198]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Shilpa-Parihar-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Hours after giving birth, hospital heater leaves mother with burnt leg]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The 28-year-old software engineer suffered burn injuries when the nurse at a Pune hospital ignored her calls for help to turn down the temperature of the heater</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pune:</strong> This young couple trusted a renowned hospital for the delivery of their first baby, but their happiness was marred by pain and agony. On April 1, Shilpa Parihar-Gill (28) was admitted to Aditya Birla Memorial Hospital (ABMH) and the next day, she underwent a caesarean section and gave birth to a girl around 9 pm.</p>
<p><img title="Shilpa Parihar-Gill with her baby. The burn injuries on her right leg can clearly be seen" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Shilpa-Parihar-1.jpg" alt="Shilpa Parihar-Gill with her baby. The burn injuries on her right leg can clearly be seen" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Shilpa Parihar-Gill with her baby. The burn injuries on her right leg can clearly be seen</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Shilpa, who works as a software engineer with an MNC, was feeling cold in the recovery room, where she was transferred after the surgery. She asked the nurse to turn on the heater. "She directed it to the lower part of my body, which had no sensation due to anaesthesia. When the upper part of my body heated up excessively, I was alarmed. When I called a nurse, it was then that I found out that my right leg had sustained severe burn injuries," recalled Shilpa, who is finding it difficult to take care of her newborn.</p>
<p>Shilpa, who stays with her husband in Pimple Saudagar, feels lucky that she was awake at the time of the incident. "I was given medication to help induce sleep. Had I slept, I would have suffered 100% burns on the right leg. Due to sheer negligence and carelessness of that nurse, I am not able to take proper care of my child," said a visibly angry Shilpa.</p>
<p>Shilpa's husband Jitendra Singh-Gill, also a techie, has submitted a written complaint to Rekha Dubey, CEO of ABMH, Pune, and attached photographs of the burnt leg with it. "We visited ABMH and met Dubey on April 11, after consulting a doctor for the burns. We asked her for compensation for the suffering we have had to endure due to the hospital's negligence. She promised to look into it," he said.</p>
<p>On April 16, they again visited the hospital and planned to meet Dubey. "She said she would meet us in some time, and told us to wait. We kept waiting for more than three hours with our newborn. We called her three times, but she didn't answer our calls. Finally, when we went to her cabin, we were told that she has left the hospital some time ago. We have not got any response from the hospital since then. We have now approached a lawyer and have also filed a petition in the consumer grievance redressal forum against the defaulters," said Jitendra.<br />Hospitalspeak</p>
<p>The hospital staff refused to comment, saying they are not authorised to speak on any issue. "I would not like to comment on this issue. You can go ahead, mentioning the one-sided story. I do not wish to clear my view on this," said Dubey.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[With Adarsh demolition order, HC trains guns on tainted officials]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/with-adarsh-demolition-order-hc-trains-guns-on-tainted-officials/17183187]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:16:27 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183187]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Ashok-Chavan-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[With Adarsh demolition order, HC trains guns on tainted officials]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Bombay HC ordered demolish of scam-tainted Adarsh building in upscale Colaba and also directed the government to initiate proceedings against politicians for negligence and misuse of power</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Taking a strong stand against corruption, the Bombay High Court on Friday ordered the ministry of environment and forests (MoEF) to demolish the 31-storey scam-tainted Adarsh Cooperative Housing Society in upscale Colaba, holding that the tower was illegally constructed. It also directed the central and state governments to initiate proceedings against bureaucrats, ministers and politicians for negligence and misuse of power.</p>
<p><img title="Then CM Ashok Chavan resigned in 2010, after it was found that his relatives were given three flats during his term as the revenue minister " src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Ashok-Chavan-1.jpg" alt="Then CM Ashok Chavan resigned in 2010, after it was found that his relatives were given three flats during his term as the revenue minister " /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Then CM Ashok Chavan resigned in 2010, after it was found that his relatives were given three flats during his term as the revenue minister </em></strong></span></p>
<p>Besides, the bench comprising justices Rajesh Ketkar and Ranjit More told the society to pay for the demolition and shell out a compensation of Rs 1 lakh each for the expenses incurred by the six officials &mdash; Dr Nalini Bhat, Bharat Bhushan, A Senthilvel and E Thirunavukkarasu from the MoEF, former BMC commissioner Sitaram Kunte and former municipal officer TC Benjamin &mdash; who had deposed during the trial.</p>
<p><object id="ventuno_player" width="405" height="325" data="http://player.ventunotech.com/vtn_player_2.swf?vID=NzcxODE0fHwxMjY0fHw0MTd8fDEsMiwx" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://player.ventunotech.com/vtn_player_2.swf?vID=NzcxODE0fHwxMjY0fHw0MTd8fDEsMiwx" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allownetworking" value="all" /><param name="flashvars" value="muted=false&amp;autoPlay=false" /></object></p>
<p>The HC, however, agreed to stay its order for 12 weeks, following a plea from the society's counsel, Nawroz Seervai, to allow it to challenge the verdict in the Supreme Court. Justice Ketkar also asked the BEST Undertaking to "take into custody its plot adjacent to the society".</p>
<p><strong>The petitions</strong><br />The court had in September 2015 started the final hearing of petitions, including the one filed by the Adarsh society (challenging the demolition order of the MoEF, dated January 16, 2011, to demolish the structure built on defence land on the grounds that it had violated CRZ guidelines), and the plea of the defence ministry seeking implementation of the demolition order and a title suit of the plot's ownership.</p>
<p><img title="Testament to corruption: The Adarsh Housing Society in Colaba was supposed to house war heroes and widows who lost their husbands in the Kargil War. File pic" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Colaba-1.jpg" alt="Testament to corruption: The Adarsh Housing Society in Colaba was supposed to house war heroes and widows who lost their husbands in the Kargil War. File pic" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Testament to corruption: The Adarsh Housing Society in Colaba was supposed to house war heroes and widows who lost their husbands in the Kargil War. File pic</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The society had sought a stay on the MoEF's order, claiming that it had not been given a fair chance to represent itself. The defence ministry, through counsel Dhiren Shah, had sought the implementation of the MoEF, staking claim to the land on which the building was constructed. It had also argued in court that the building posed a threat to national security since it overlooked key defence installations. The Maharashtra Coastal Zone Management, represented by senior counsel Darius Khambatta, told the court that the action initiated against the society was justified and legal. The bench had reserved its order on December 2 after hearing all parties.</p>
<p><strong>Baying for Ashok Chavan's scalp</strong><br />The Adarsh Cooperative Housing Society was sanctioned for widows of Kargil War heroes and its height was to be restricted to six floors. But it grew to 100 m. The issue had been brewing since 2003, but a scrutiny of the high-profile list of owners began only in 2010, prompting the Army and the CBI to launch separate investigations. The CAG, too, submitted a report on the scam.</p>
<p>Then Chief Minister Ashok Chavan was the first casualty of the scam, who resigned on November 9, 2010, after it was found that his relatives, including his mother-in-law, were given three flats during his term as the revenue minister.</p>
<p>In January 2011, the CBI registered an FIR, stating that the society promoters had colluded with bureaucrats and politicians to take over a defence land and that documents for this acquisition had been forged. In its chargesheet, it named Chavan, then sub-divisional officer of defence estate office RC Thakur, Brigadier (retd) MM Wanchu, former Congress MLC and Adarsh promoter KL Gidwani, Major General (retd) AR Kumar, Maj Gen (retd) TK Kaul, Brigadier (retd) TK Sinha; retired IAS officers PV Deshmukh, Ramanand Tiwari and Subhash Lalla; serving IAS officers Pradeep Vyas and Jairaj Phathak; and Col (retd) RK Bakshi.</p>
<p>In 2011, the state government set up a two-member judicial commission, headed by Justice JA Patil, to probe the scam. In its report submitted two years later, the commission said there had been 25 illegal allotments, including 22 purchases made by proxy.</p>
<p>In 2013, then governor, K Sankaranarayanan, denied permission to the CBI to prosecute Chavan in the case. The CBI then approached the HC to drop Chavan's name from its chargesheet, but the court refused to allow this, saying there was evidence that Chavan had made financial gains while holding a public office.</p>
<p>In February this year, the CBI got nod from Governor CH Vidyasagar Rao to prosecute Chavan under Section 197 (to try a public servant) of the CrPC. To this, Chavan said he was being targeted by the BJP.</p><br/>Arrests<br/><p>The CBI has so far arrested retired major generals TK Kaul and AR Kumar, retired brigadier MM Wanchu, Adarsh promoter KL Gidwani, his son, Kailash, IAS officers Pradeep Vyas and Jairaj Phatak and former IAS officer Ramanand Tiwari.</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hardik Patel's PAAS dismisses Gujarat government's 10% quota as 'lollipop']]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/hardik-patels-paas-dismisses-gujarat-governments-10-quota-as-lollipop/17184159]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:06:33 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184159]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Vijay-Rupani-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Hardik Patel's PAAS dismisses Gujarat government's 10% quota as 'lollipop']]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Facing the heat over Patel quota agitation, the BJP government in Gujarat yesterday announced 10 per cent reservation for the economically backward among upper castes up to an annual family income of R6 lakh, but the Hardik Patel-led outfit rejected it</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gandhinagar:</strong> Facing the heat over Patel quota agitation, the BJP government in Gujarat yesterday announced 10 per cent reservation for the economically backward among upper castes up to an annual family income of R6 lakh, but the Hardik Patel-led outfit rejected it.</p>
<p><img title="State BJP president Vijay Rupani (left) made the announcement with CM Anandiben Patel and senior minister Nitin Patel. Pic/PTI" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Vijay-Rupani-1.jpg" alt="State BJP president Vijay Rupani (left) made the announcement with CM Anandiben Patel and senior minister Nitin Patel. Pic/PTI" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>State BJP president Vijay Rupani (left) made the announcement with CM Anandiben Patel and senior minister Nitin Patel. Pic/PTI</em></strong></span></p>
<p>In its initial reaction, quota agitation leader Hardik Patel's Patidar Anamat Andolan Samiti (PAAS) rejected the move as another "lollipop" extended by the BJP and the state government to "mislead" their community.</p>
<p>"This is just another 'lollipop' given by the state government to mislead the Patel community. "We do not accept this reservation for EBCs. Our main demand is to release Hardik Patel from jail and then we will decide the future course of action," PAAS spokesperson Dharmik Malaviya said.</p>
<p>However, another quota agitation body Sardar Patel Group (SPG) welcomed the government's move, but said they will assess how much will it help the community.</p>
<p>State BJP president Vijay Rupani, flanked by Chief Minister Anandiben Patel and senior minister Nitin Patel, said, "Families having an annual income of R6 lakh or below will be eligible to avail the reservation. That means a family having an income up to R50,000 per month can take the benefit of the scheme," he said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mumbai Diary: Saturday Sossier]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/mumbai-diary-saturday-sossier/17184175]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 03:03:59 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184175]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Shivaji-Park-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Mumbai Diary: Saturday Sossier]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The city &mdash; sliced, diced and served with a dash of sauce</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>The changing park-scape</strong></span><img title="Shivaji Park" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Shivaji-Park-1.jpg" alt="Shivaji Park" /><br />Shivaji Park &mdash; that nursery of Mumbai cricket, that green space, that political battleground, call it what you will, is changing. Not always for the better, though. Another bungalow that rings the periphery of this park has fallen to the builders' bulldozer. These structures that give the area its character, are making way for high-rises. A recent casualty is the space near a popular caf&eacute;. Earlier, we were able to spot high rises behind the immediate ring of bungalows around the park. But now, we notice that the first ring within the periphery is changing. This diarist, a regular at the park for decades, wonders if it's time to capture the iconic frame of the park in what's left of its glory days.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Bombay booked</strong></span><img title="The author of Humans of Bombay, Karishma Mehta, flanked by publishers Karan (to her right) and Arjun at Cymroza Art Gallery, Breach Candy on Friday. Pic/Atul Kamble" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Karishma-Mehta-1.jpg" alt="The author of Humans of Bombay, Karishma Mehta, flanked by publishers Karan (to her right) and Arjun at Cymroza Art Gallery, Breach Candy on Friday. Pic/Atul Kamble" /><br />Bombay was compressed into the second floor of the Cymroza Art Gallery. Props like a dabbawallah's cycle and red post boxes, as well as the city's iconic snacks were on display. This was, after all, the launch of the city's favourite Facebook page in the form of a book &mdash; a full cycle for Humans of Bombay that chronicles ordinary lives in the city in pursuit of extraordinary stories. A swish crowd had gathered to cheer its young writer, Karishma Mehta and publishers Karan and Arjun. Clich&eacute;s on the city like speed, energy, life were overheard which were used almost like codes to begin and end chatter. After some deliberation and a self-effacing declaration of being terrible at it, Mehta took the mic to recall that when she started the page two years ago, she would only write, as the camera was still not something she was good with. Eventually, she did both. Now, the page has over 600,000 followers. A few copies of the book, otherwise available on their website, were sold at the venue. There was also a declaration that R100 from each sale would go towards helping Marathwada's farmers though the organizers hadn't yet zeroed in on which NGO or government body would be the beneficiary.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>A different kind of lesson<br /><img title="A still from Best Friends Forever" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Best-Friends-Forever-1.jpg" alt="A still from Best Friends Forever" /></strong></span><br />Recently, this diarist came across city-based director Sandeep Modi's film Best Friends Forever. Much to our delight, this engaging work, produced by School Cinema, has won a national film award. The heartwarming film, which presents the evolving relationship between a mother and a teenage daughter, won the award in the category of Best Film on Family Values. EduMedia, under the aegis of School Cinema, now has won four national film awards and has been showcased in over fifty international film festivals across the world. The film showcases a mother's friendship with her teenage daughter, who as she grows up, begins keeping secrets from her. The film embraces the theme of independence &mdash;will the mother be able to cope with her daughter's need for freedom? Given that she has invested her time in caring for her daughter for so long, will she finally be able to embrace her independence? We hope it's films like these that are screened in India's schools.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>Rusty is back in the city</strong></span><br /><img title="Ruskin Bond" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Ruskin-Bond-1.jpg" alt="Ruskin Bond" /><br />This diarist's fangirl-like moments of having met Ruskin Bond a while ago will always be cherished. So, when we learnt that the iconic Indian writer's work and experience will be staged at NCPA, in the form of A Special Bond Part Three, come May 27, we did a virtual jig. All those tales of Rusty's adventures, his trysts with the known and the mysterious, will come to life on stage. From what we hear, the play will begin as the story on Bond, the little boy growing up in India during World War II, his journeys across India and the world, and the tales around it. Being semi-autobiographical, we're hoping this one will leave a mark on not just the little ones but adults too who've been regaled by his storytelling gems.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><strong>The science of art, the art of science<br /><img title="Shivaprasad Khened (left) and Pheroza Godrej at the NGMA. Pic/Sayyed Sameer Abedi" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Shivaprasad-Khened-1.jpg" alt="Shivaprasad Khened (left) and Pheroza Godrej at the NGMA. Pic/Sayyed Sameer Abedi" /></strong></span><br />Science is Science and culture is culture and never the twain doth meet&hellip; for those who think that they are mutually exclusive, here is a bit of an eyebrow raise for you. Dr Shivaprasad M Khened is director of both, National Science Centre at Mahalaxmi (opposite Famous Studios) and The National Gallery of Modern Art (NGMA) at Kala Ghoda. It is interesting that Science with its exactitude, hard-nosed rep, logic and of course the stereotype of the absent-minded professor, goes along with Art, with its creative, open to interpretation vibe, where there are no correct answers and its creators are as far removed from scientists with their bohemian stereotype. When we met him recently at the NGMA, he was wrapping up a meeting at the Museum, before heading back to the leafy green campus of Science Centre at Mahalaxmi. We asked him how he manages to straddle both worlds to which he smiled and simply said, "by burning the midnight oil."</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[No record of molestation acquittals in Maharashtra: RTI]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/no-record-of-molestation-acquittals-in-maharashtra-rti/17183193]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:55:44 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17183193]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[No record of molestation acquittals in Maharashtra: RTI]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Maharashtra government has no record available on the number of people acquitted in cases of outraging the modesty of women, an RTI query has revealed</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Maharashtra government has no record available on the number of people acquitted in cases of outraging the modesty of women, an RTI query has revealed.</p>
<p>The application, seeking to know the total number of people charged under Section 354 of IPC (assault or criminal force to woman with intent to outrage her modesty) but were later acquitted of the charge, was filed by city-based activist Mansoor Darvesh with Law and Judiciary department.</p>
<p>The department sent Darvesh's query to Home Ministry which forwarded it to the office of the Director General of Police, which said, "the information is not available with this office". The applicant was also provided a list of all police stations in Mumbai and was asked to approach them for case details.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Congress demands CBI probe in Vasundhara Raje's '05 chopper deal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/congress-demands-cbi-probe-in-vasundhara-rajes-05-chopper-deal/17184162]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:55:39 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184162]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Vasundhara-Raje-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Congress demands CBI probe in Vasundhara Raje's '05 chopper deal]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Former Union minister Sachin Pilot yesterday sought a CBI probe into the alleged irregularities in the purchase of an Agusta Westland helicopter by the Rajasthan government in 2005</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jaipur:</strong> Former Union minister Sachin Pilot yesterday sought a CBI probe into the alleged irregularities in the purchase of an Agusta Westland helicopter by the Rajasthan government in 2005.</p>
<p><img title="Vasundhara Raje" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Vasundhara-Raje-1.jpg" alt="Vasundhara Raje" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Vasundhara Raje</em></strong></span></p>
<p>He said the Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG) in its report had alleged that misappropriation of public funds to the tune of R1.14 crore had taken place in the helicopter deal by the then Vasundhara Raje-led BJP government in the state.</p>
<p>"It is not an allegation by Congress, but a report of CAG. We have just demanded an inquiry and clarification from the government but there is no reaction from them and the BJP state president is defending the government," he said.</p>
<p>Pilot alleged that the Raje government in 2008 had initiated a process to procure another helicopter at an inflated price of R59 crore. He said it should also be investigated that why the government agreed to pay the additional premium.</p>
<p>Reacting to the allegations, BJP state president Ashok Parnami claimed R1.14 crore was spent on chartered flights due to non-availability of pilots for the Agusta Westland helicopter from September 2005 to January 2006. He said the expenses were "unavoidable."</p><br/><br/><p><strong>ED summons Tyagi</strong><br />Enforcement Directorate summoned former IAF chief SP Tyagi in connection with its probe in the Agusta Westland chopper deal case. Official sources said the summons have been issued under the provisions of the Prevention of Money Laundering Act.</p>
<p><strong>Tweet talk</strong><br />Amit Shahji is asking Soniaji with folded hands &ndash; 'please tell who took bribes'. Is this how probe is conducted? Dissolve CBI and ACB then<br />@arvindkejriwal</p>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cheers! Bandra's Purerose Baptista turns a 100 years]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/cheers-bandras-purerose-baptista-turns-a-100-years/17184150]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:55:17 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184150]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Marcellus-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Cheers! Bandra's Purerose Baptista turns a 100 years]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Bandra's Purerose Baptista marks a landmark century with a toast of her favourite tipple a whisky-soda and a warm family bash &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p>Purerose Baptista, notched up a landmark 100 on the scoreboard of her life, yesterday. There was a Mass in the morning and a swinging party with friends and family in the evening at her home. Piety and gaiety came together, as the Bandra resident celebrated her hundredth birthday.</p>
<p><img title="Purerose with son, Marcellus at their Bandra home. Pic/Pradeep Dhivar" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Marcellus-1.jpg" alt="Purerose with son, Marcellus at their Bandra home. Pic/Pradeep Dhivar" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Purerose with son, Marcellus at their Bandra home. Pic/Pradeep Dhivar</em></strong></span></p>
<p>Her children, daughter Scarlett Nikitovic (settled down in Belgrade, Serbia, former Yugoslavia, since past over 40 years), had flown down for the very special occasion. Her sons, Darryl, Brian and Marcellus, were all there playing hosts at their mom's bash. Darryl and Brian live in Andheri with their families but Marcellus, who is a journalist who reports on parties, fashion events and hi-society dos, lives with his mother.</p>
<p>Her daughter, Scarlett said, amidst the whirlwind meets yesterday, "I just had to be here for this special occasion, it is rare that a mother is a century old!" Scarlett comes to Mumbai once in two or three years, usually. She has been coming down to Mumbai for her mom's birthday for the last few years annually though, since she doesn't want to miss celebrating her birthday with her.</p>
<p>Purerose, a former junior school teacher, who taught at St Aloysius School and St Andrew's School in Bandra. Post her marriage, she took a break for 25 years, and after that, she went back to teaching at Apostolic Carmel Convent, Bandra. The western suburb has been home to the 100-year-old all her life. Every nook and cranny of Bandra is comforting and familiar. Purerose first lived on the beautiful Chapel Road and today, she lives on Veronica Road, one of those leafy, charming Bandra bylanes full of character and homes that make you think they just don't make them like that anymore.</p>
<p>Purerose has outlived her husband Faustin Baptista, by 30 years. He passed away on September 1, 1986. She found love and support from her family but also her female friends, who in fact, she said, "are her most important memories." Purerose added, "Develop a passion or a hobby, that keeps you going outside of work. It does not have to be grandiose, like travelling to exotic lands. For me," she said while smiling, "it is as simple as collecting boxes, I have a lot of them, small and big."</p>
<p>Purerose, is still very active, she walks aided with a walking stick but can get around without it. As she bustled around, yesterday, post morning Mass, awaiting guests for the party, she was especially happy about Mass. It was held at her home, and conducted by Fr. Joe Abreo (84), who, incidentally, Purerose had taught as a boy, in St Andrews School. Fr. Abreo has written a book called, 'Gossip by Candlelight' dedicated to his teacher. Purerose.</p>
<p>Marcellus said, "She is still a teacher. Today, the 'boys' that she taught, many of them, old men now still refer to her as their foundation." Her daughter Scarlett says, "Mom's a girlie girl. Her favourite colour is pink. She loves to bake and can bake a cake herself!" Her favourite dish is minced meat with hot-and-sweet tomato sauce. Yet, it is her drink of choice, "a small whisky-soda that I have with Marcellus which is the secret of my longevity," Purerose said with a cheeky chuckle.</p>
<p>Marcellus said they talk about him reporting on parties and his mom laughs when he shares the air-kissing ways and dahlings that the party sets stock greeting. Since Marcy, as he is known is the ultimate party guy, he has a collection of bright, zany shirts, which are his corporate or work wear. "She always asks me whether people liked my shirt," he said.</p>
<p>For Purerose, there have been no regrets, if she feels a twinge, it is because she wanted to move from being a tenant of her ground plus one storey dilapidated building, Philomena Terrace, to a redeveloped building. Purerose is holding the fort with the other three tenants no longer in the building. One tenant passed away and the other two have moved to Andheri and Malad.&nbsp;"So many builders have come in and seen the place, but the redevelopment has not taken place&hellip;" she says, wistfully.</p>
<p>Marcellus adds, "She wishes at least one day before she passes away, she would have a nice, new house&hellip;" Yesterday, though was time for wishes of another kind for this spunky Bandra native. The one that said, Happy birthday, Purerose. We know you have 100 that's the score, but here's hoping you have many more.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Contaminated water kills seven special needs children in Rajasthan ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/contaminated-water-kills-seven-special-needs-children-in-rajasthan/17184160]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:52:22 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184160]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Contaminated water kills seven special needs children in Rajasthan ]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Seven children with special needs, who were staying at a government-run home in Jamdoli near here, have died over the last eight days in a hospital where they were admitted with septic shock after allegedly drinking contaminated water</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jaipur:</strong> Seven children with special needs, who were staying at a government-run home in Jamdoli near here, have died over the last eight days in a hospital where they were admitted with septic shock after allegedly drinking contaminated water.</p>
<p>The condition of three others is stated to be critical. "Children were admitted to the hospital between April 21 and 28. Seven of them have died, while four are undergoing treatment. Of them, three are critical," Dr Ashok Gupta, superintendent of JK Lone Hospital, said.</p>
<p>He said the children belonging to different age groups were suffering from septic shock &mdash; complication of infection where toxins can initiate a full body inflammatory response &mdash; and high blood pressure. All of them were admitted after they complained of vomiting and other problems, he said.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Traditions take long time to change, says Pravin Togadia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/traditions-take-long-time-to-change-says-pravin-togadia/17184163]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:46:08 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184163]]></storyid><media:content url="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Pravin-Togadia-s.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Traditions take long time to change, says Pravin Togadia]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>VHP leader Pravin Togadia said traditions take a long time to change and getting angry over them is no solution, comments coming in the backdrop of ongoing campaigns in Maharashtra seeking entry of women into certain places of worship in the state</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nashik:</strong> VHP leader Pravin Togadia today said traditions take a long time to change and getting angry over them is no solution, comments coming in the backdrop of ongoing campaigns in Maharashtra seeking entry of women into certain places of worship in the state.</p>
<p><img title="VHP leader Pravin Togadia" src="http://images.mid-day.com/images/2016/apr/30Pravin-Togadia.jpg" alt="VHP leader Pravin Togadia" /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><em>Pravin Togadia</em></strong></span><br /><br />"It is a matter of tradition whether to allow (women) inside a temple or a dargah. It is wrong to get angry over the issue as it takes hundreds of years to change traditions," he told reporters here.<br /><br />The VHP International Working President was responding to questions regarding campaigns launched by Bhumata Brigde, an outfit led by activist Trupti Desai, and others, for entry of women into inner sanctum of Ahmednagar Shani Temple, Trimbakeshwar Temple in Nashik, and Mumbai's Haji Ali Dargah. <br /><br />"Instead of getting angry over the issue of women's entry into temples or dargah, what is needed is involvement of local civilians and trusts to sort out the matter," said Togadia,&nbsp; who was here to take part in a VHP programme.<br /><br />"It will take time to change traditions. There was a time when 'ghunghat' (veil) system was widespread in the country. <br /><br />This is not the case now," he said. The VHP leader expressed hopes that the Modi government, which has a comfortable majority in the Lok Sabha, will enact a law to facilitate construction of a Ram Temple at Ayodhya.<br />He later spoke at a training programme organised for 'health ambassadors' of 'India Health Line' - a network of doctors for providing free medical care to the needy. <br /><br />The initiative was launched by Togadia in 2014 in several cities for facilitating a connect between the poor patients and medical fraternity. <br /><br />Togadia, himself a cancer surgeon by qualification, said increasing prevalence of lifestyle diseases is a matter of concern.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adarsh case complainant hails HC order]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/adarsh-case-complainant-hails-hc-order/17184164]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:34:45 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184164]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Adarsh case complainant hails HC order]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>Welcoming the Bombay High Court's direction to the MoEF to demolish the 31-storey scam-tainted Adarsh building in south Mumbai, activist Simpreet Singh, who had filed a complaint in this case, today said it had been a long journey for him and he now feels vindicated.</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mumbai:</strong> Welcoming the Bombay High Court's direction to the MoEF to demolish the 31-storey scam-tainted Adarsh building in south Mumbai, activist Simpreet Singh, who had filed a complaint in this case, today said it had been a long journey for him and he now feels vindicated. <br /><br />"It has been a long journey. We started in 2006 by filing an RTI (on Adarsh building). Thereafter, in 2010, we filed a complaint with the Union Ministry of Environment and Forests (MoEF). Today's high court order is a welcome step and we stand vindicated," Singh told PTI.<br /><br />Holding that the building was illegally constructed, the high court today directed the MoEF to demolish the tower in Colaba area of South Mumbai and sought criminal proceedings against politicians and bureaucrats for "misuse" of powers. <br /><br />While ordering the demolition, the HC also placed on record its appreciation for Singh. <br /><br />Singh said he is ready to go to the Supreme Court in case Adarsh Society appeals against the HC order. "We will go to the SC and we are hopeful that the apex court will uphold the HC order," Singh said.<br /><br />He also said the MoEF had ordered demolition of the building in 2011. "We were clear from day one that there were violation in construction of the building and it should be demolished."<br /><br />Singh recalled that people used to ridicule him when he said that his prayer to the authorities was demolition of the building.<br /><br />"They used to say that investigation may happen regarding the irregularities, but nobody will direct demolition", Singh said and added that justice has been done by the high court.</p><br/>]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Police issue summons to FC Goa official over Qnet sponsorship]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.mid-day.com/articles/police-issue-summons-to-fc-goa-official-over-qnet-sponsorship/17184158]]></link><pubDate><![CDATA[30 Apr 2016 02:20:27 GMT]]></pubDate><storyid><![CDATA[17184158]]></storyid><media:content type="image/jpeg"/><media:title><![CDATA[Police issue summons to FC Goa official over Qnet sponsorship]]></media:title><summary><![CDATA[<p>The Economic Offences Wing (EOW) of Mumbai police has issued summons to a top official of Football Club Goa, an Indian Super League team, to inquire about his role into taking sponsorship from the scam-tainted Qnet company, a senior official said here today</p>]]></summary><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mumbai:</strong> The Economic Offences Wing (EOW) of Mumbai police has issued summons to a top official of Football Club Goa, an Indian Super League team, to inquire about his role into taking sponsorship from the scam-tainted Qnet company, a senior official said here today. <br /><br />The EOW issued summons to the Manager of FC Goa, owned by Goan Football Club Pvt Ltd, yesterday. The club official has been asked to record his statement at the earliest, the official said.<br /><br />"The official will be questioned as to how the proceeds of a company under serious investigation, went into sponsoring the club team," he added.<br /><br />Qnet case whistle-blower Gurupreet Anand said it is disheartening to see how money looted from people is making its way back into some Bollywood films and sports events. <br /><br />The EOW had arrested ten people for allegedly duping investors by offering to sell products, including magnetic disks, herbal products and holiday schemes of the QNet through fraudulent practises.<br /><br />The police had also invoked the stringent Maharashtra Protection of Interest of Depositors (MPID) against the company.<br /><br />Qnet, previously known as Goldquest and Questnet, is a Malayasia-based network marketing company. It has been accused of running an illegal Pyramid Scheme. The total amount involved in the scam is now estimated to be at more than Rs 7,000 crore. <br /><br />An FIR in the case was registered in 2013.</p><br/>]]></description></item></channel></rss>