<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--RSS generated by RSSviaXmlTextWriter at Sun, 01 May 2016 19:36:03 GMT-->
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tribune</title>
    <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/</link>
    <description>Tribune News Service</description>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230466.html</link>
      <title>Green corridors in Delhi help transportation of organs in minutes</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: A live heart was transported from IGI Airport here to Medanta Hospital in Gurgaon in 16 minutes and a liver was rushed to the Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences in 15 minutes with the help of green corridors put in place by Delhi and Gurgaon police.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 18:06:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230466.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230459.html</link>
      <title>India, New Zealand friendship will continue to strengthen: Mukherjee</title>
      <description>AUCKLAND: Friendship between India and New Zealand will continue to strengthen, President Pranab Mukherjee said on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:36:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230459.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230458.html</link>
      <title>Modi launches scheme to provide free LPG connections to poor</title>
      <description>BALLIA (UP):  Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday launched a Rs 8,000 crore scheme to provide 5 crore free LPG connections to poor families as he attacked previous governments for just paying lip service to reducing poverty.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:31:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230458.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230455.html</link>
      <title>Indian worker dies at Qatar World Cup site; labour rights under scrutiny</title>
      <description>DOHA: The organisers of Qatar's 2022 World Cup said on Sunday they were investigating the death of an Indian labourer at one of its sites but denied it was caused by working conditions which the wealthy Gulf country is under pressure to improve.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:59:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230455.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230454.html</link>
      <title>Kanhaiya Kumar shown black flags in Patna</title>
      <description>PATNA: Jawaharlal Nehru University student leader Kanhaiya Kumar, who faced sedition charges, was shown black flags at a function on Sunday by two unidentified people who were roughed up by his supporters before being detained by the police for questioning.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:56:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230454.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230452.html</link>
      <title>Netaji memorial to come up at IGNCA complex</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: The Culture Ministry is likely to allot up to six acres of land in the campus of Indira Gandhi National Centre for Arts (IGNCA) in the heart of national capital for construction of Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose memorial.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230452.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230450.html</link>
      <title>New uniform for Air India cabin crew in the offing</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: Air India's cabin crew may soon undergo a makeover: an internal committee, mostly comprising the in-flight staff, has suggested various sartorial options for draping themselves.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 15:20:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230450.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230448.html</link>
      <title>Narendra Modi secured first class in MA from Guj University: V-C</title>
      <description>AHMEDABAD: Amid the raging row over Prime Minister Narendra Modi's educational qualification, the Gujarat University on Sunday said the leader had scored 62.3 per cent as an external student of the varsity.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 14:25:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230448.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230447.html</link>
      <title>Diesel, petrol cabs go off roads, owners warn of suicides</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: The Supreme Court's ban on plying of diesel and petrol driven taxis in Delhi took effect on Sunday, with three taxi owners warning this might lead to suicides in frustration.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 14:13:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230447.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230441.html</link>
      <title>Will provide better life to poor: Modi</title>
      <description>BALLIA, UTTAR PRADESH: Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday pledged to ensure a better life for the poor, saying his government was "for the poor".</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:36:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230441.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230439.html</link>
      <title>All help being given to Uttarakhand: Environment Minister Prakash Javadekar</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: Stating that the Centre had taken the Uttrakhand forest fires very seriously, Environment Minister Prakash Javadekar said on Sunday that its first priority was to douse the flames by augmenting manpower and monetary help to the distressed hill state.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:16:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230439.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230438.html</link>
      <title>States' rising debt, unplanned spending worries central bank</title>
      <description>KOLKATA: Non-productive expenditure of state governments remains a cause of worry and their growing liabilities need redressal, even though there has been some improvement in this regard, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has said in a report.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230438.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230437.html</link>
      <title>Non-subsidised LPG, kerosene, ATF prices hiked</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: After petrol and diesel, rates of non-subsidised cooking gas, non-PDS kerosene and aviation turbine fuel (ATF) were today raised in line with global trends.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230437.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230431.html</link>
      <title>Will table Agusta papers in Parliament on May 4, says Parrikar</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI: I will place a detailed chronology of events on the AgustaWestland chopper deal with supporting documents before Parliament on May 4, Defence Minister Manohar Parrikar said on Sunday. "Those who received kickbacks will not leave behind the proof for us to prosecute them, but we will have to prove it (that kickbacks were received)," he said.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230431.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230428.html</link>
      <title>Forest fire: Mi-17 helicopters to put off blaze in Uttarakhand</title>
      <description>NAINITAL: The central government has deployed two Mi-17 helicopters to douse forest fires raging in Uttarakhand. More than 1,900 hectares of forestland have been affected by the fire in the Kumaun and Garwal region. Two Air Force helicopters have been dispatched to battle the blaze in Pauri and Nanital districts.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 10:20:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230428.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230290.html</link>
      <title>Realty Act is reality finally</title>
      <description>New Delhi:  The Real Estate (Regulation and Development) Act, 2016 comes into force from Sunday, setting in motion rules and institutional infrastructure for protecting consumers and promoting the sector’s growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 01:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230290.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230288.html</link>
      <title>Nosey welcome for the President</title>
      <description>Auckland: President Pranab Mukherjee rubbed his nose with the Maori chief and his wife as part of the traditional welcome on a three-day visit to New Zealand.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 01:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230288.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230287.html</link>
      <title>27, 000 diesel taxis off road</title>
      <description>New Delhi: Nearly 27,000 diesel-run taxis will not be allowed to ply on the national capital’s roads from Sunday after the Supreme Court on Saturday refused to extend the April 30 deadline fixed for their conversion to the CNG mode.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 01:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230287.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230286.html</link>
      <title>Forest fires rage  across U’khand</title>
      <description>Dehradun: Major forest fires raged across Uttarakhand on Saturday even as three National Disaster Response Force teams were deployed in Almora, Gauchar and Pauri and a state team in Nainital to extinguish the flames. Since February, 922 fires have been reported, killing seven people and blighting 1,890 hectares.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 01:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230286.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <category>Nation</category>
      <link>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230285.html</link>
      <title>6.67 lakh to take  NEET-1 today</title>
      <description>NEW DELHI:The Central Board of Secondary Education is all set for the first phase of the historic National Eligibility cum Entrance Test (NEET) to be conducted tomorrow and has asked aspirants to adhere to a strict dress code to help ensure a fair exam.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 01:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/story/230285.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>